<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gillian Wearing on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/gillian-wearing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gillian Wearing on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/gillian-wearing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Richard Patterson: Only Fans | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Richard Patterson was a YBA, part of the scandalous 1990s ‘Sensation’ generation. But, like his peers Gillian Wearing and Gavin Turk, he’s matured into a painter of sensitivity and skill. Proof of this view comes in ‘Only Fans’, a show of small-format works using what the press release describes as a “carnal palette”, which closed this week at Timothy Taylor.
All 13 paintings in the exhibition are dreamy swirls of flesh-toned roses and ochres, on luxurious-looking linen canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychomachia | The Old Bank Vault</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/laurent-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/laurent-vault/</guid>
      <description>After four months of long lockdown, London’s commercial galleries reopened this week. The city’s bathed in spring sunshine, the streets are (comparatively) bustling, and it’s time to blow the dust and cobwebs off this website and get going again!
I guess you could call it a staged reopening: not being able to face a busy tube and Mayfair, I chose my first show back to be at a gallery within cycling distance of my flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2020</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is my third year of the Artangled project, and my third end-of-year roundup. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the 2018 and 2019 format, listing the five art exhibitions I enjoyed most this year. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;ve also called out a couple of shows I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy. But for 2020, there’s only one candidate for my festive lump of coal: the global pandemic itself, one of whose side effects was to shutter London&amp;rsquo;s art galleries for months on end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Wearing - Lockdown | Maureen Paley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wearing-paley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wearing-paley/</guid>
      <description>This year, many of us have been given the opportunity to spend a lot more time in peaceful self-contemplation at home. Which has absolutely sucked. The artist Gillian Wearing has produced many self portraits in lockdown. Some oil on canvas, some watercolour, and all with a striking atmosphere of quiet, watchful despair.
In each of the fourteen self portraits on show at Maureen Paley, plus one I saw at the the Royal Academy, Wearing’s painted image seems to be waiting for something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Order - Art, Product, Image 1976-1995 | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wearing-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wearing-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>The place is quite familiar, rendered strange over the decades. We’re in a shopping centre in Peckham in 1994. Everyone’s dressed in baggy 90s style. If anyone’s carrying a shopping bag, it’s plastic. This being several decades before that multi-story car park down the road got its pink coat of paint and craft beer outlets, the crowd is solidly ungentrified. And nobody has a mobile phone, so nobody’s filming the very unusual scene - except one camera.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
