<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bridget Riley on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/bridget-riley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bridget Riley on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/bridget-riley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Noland: Stripes/Plaids/Shapes | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Noland put himself under a lot of pressure to achieve such chilled-out art. He’s been called a “minimalist” or “colour field” painter, with his large canvases banded with simple patterns - or just stripes. In fact, Stripes/ Plaids/ Shapes, the title of this show, Noland’s first monograph exhibition in the UK for over 20 years, pretty much sums up what’s on display.
So, where’s the pressure from? In the technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piero Dorazio, Chromatic Fantasies (1948-82) | Tornabuoni Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</guid>
      <description>Showing in the depths of an interminable winter, this blast of colour, at Tornabuoni until springtime, comes as a welcome relief &amp;ndash; even a joy.
Dorazio isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a heavy hitter in the pantheon of post war Italian painting. In fact, this is billed as his &amp;ldquo;first London show in a generation&amp;rdquo; (though he was a big part of a group show up the road at Mazzoleni last year). He gave the Futurist tropes of bustle and movement a new spin in the 50s, after a formative meeting with the then-elderly Giacomo Balla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Riley: Recent Paintings 2014 - 2017 | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>New year, new blockbuster at Zwirner. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s Op Art queen Bridget Riley, in a mini-retrospective of (mainly) work from the past four years.
It&amp;rsquo;s based around two themes: her return to the black and white patterns that made her name in the 60s, and her more recent disc paintings. What the two styles have in common is formal rigour, the impression of movement and disorientation. You could say her work, taken as a whole, form an inquiry into the constituent elements of painting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
