<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annely Juda Fine Art on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/annely-juda-fine-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Annely Juda Fine Art on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/annely-juda-fine-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leon Kossoff | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</guid>
      <description>Along with bigger names like Lucian Freud and Francis Bacon, Leon Kossoff was part of the School of London, painters who passed a pitiless eye on the down-at-heel postwar capital city, pre Olympics, pre Millennium Dome, pre Big Bang boom. A fine retrospective selection of Kossoff’s work - the artist died in 2019 - is on show right now at Annely Juda Fine Art.
Kossoff&amp;rsquo;s subject matter is firmly rooted in the city he rarely left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prunella Clough and Alan Reynolds | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</guid>
      <description>Prunella Clough liked to explore the train yards at Willesden Junction: quite a messy and down-at-heel place these days, but surely an absolute decrepit dump in the post-war years in which she started working. From a wealthy background, she spent much of her career teaching at the Chelsea School of Art. But her own artistic output focused on semi-abstract paintings and prints of grimy, industrial and forgotten corners of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony Caro - Seven Decades | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>Despite the epic title, this one is a small, lovingly-curated show over two floors in a quiet upstairs gallery off Oxford Street. I particularly loved the bigger machine-like works on the upper floor.
They’re collectively a study in contrasts: the forms balanced between the rectilinear and the curvy; the material combining both reused parts and the purpose-built; the surfaces vary between the smooth and the pitted.
What about Sky Passage (T0179), a very recent, three metre high work from 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmgreen &amp; Dragset - This Is How We Bite Our Tongue | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>Whitechapel Gallery has been transformed into a derelict swimming pool with an imaginary backstory. Built by a Victorian philanthropist (the story goes), the Whitechapel Pool played host to Tesco founder Jack Cohen and David Hockney over its decades as a public utility. Then it got shut down in the privatisation-happy Thatcher era, before being renovated as part of a “design hotel” opening in 2019. Unfortunately for future Cohens and Hockneys, it’ll be accessible only through membership.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
