<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orlanda Broom on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/orlanda-broom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orlanda Broom on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/orlanda-broom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Cohen: Two Point Eight Million | FOLD</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</guid>
      <description>This show is dominated by a mini mountain range of day-glo green “eco chips” - the kind of polystyrene-like packaging that pads out Amazon boxes - in the far corner of the gallery. The artist Benjamin Cohen called it all mouth and no trousers, and studded the green chip mountains with an amp and two transparent speakers emitting droning sounds.
It’s a riff on Félix González-Torres’s Portrait of Ross in LA, which was a pile of sweets stacked up in the corner of the gallery, weighing the same as the artist’s lover - before he was stricken with AIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orlanda Broom: Shapeshifters | Grove Square Galleries</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</guid>
      <description>Producing this collection of abstract works, made with colourful resin on canvas, must have taken a toll on the artist. Orlanda Broom can only work on works using resin for a couple of months each year - otherwise the ambient temperature isn’t right. The perfectionist artist also doesn’t allow any resin works with trapped hairs and dust out of the studio.
“I’m interested in the interpretation of abstract works,” she says.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
