<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blain Southern on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/blain-southern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blain Southern on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/blain-southern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bosco Sodi - Heavens and the Earth | Blain Southern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sodi-blain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sodi-blain/</guid>
      <description>There are two parts of this exhibition. First the heavens: big black and white paintings, made of ultra-thick paint, cracked in interesting ways, depicting mysterious swirls and bubbles. It’s as if you’re staring at a mountain range from the sky.
Then the earth, brick towers in Jenga-style patterns. They look about as stable as Jenga towers, too: the bricks wonky and uneven.
The bricks and the paint were both formed by chance as well as craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Leonard. Aerials | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Zoe Leonard is an American conceptual artist who took aerial photos of New York City over several years in the late 80s. Gelatin silver prints of these are on show as Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth right now, and when I went to see them, I basically wanted to buy them all, in an alternative fantasy universe where I actually have the funds to do that.
The artist’s eye gets caught on urban infrastructure; the densely gridded street pattern of the city; worn summer baseball fields, packed back to back and encroached on by houses from all sides; and, most lovingly shot of all, a gleaming rail interchange, the iron and wood of the parallel tracks caught by low light, rendered mysterious by the silver print’s blur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
