<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hauser &amp; Wirth on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/hauser-wirth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hauser &amp; Wirth on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/hauser-wirth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phyllida Barlow | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Why am I looking at and writing about concrete so much this summer? First there was Prunella Clough’s desolate little paintings of midcentury urban corners, that caught my eye at Annely Juda Fine Art. Then there was Yu Ji’s dripping, detritus-filled installation at Chisenhale Gallery.
Now, rather grander than both, is Phyllida Barlow’s ring of a hundred or so three-metre-high cement sentinels, that squeeze to the edges of Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth’s main gallery at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Leonard. Aerials | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Zoe Leonard is an American conceptual artist who took aerial photos of New York City over several years in the late 80s. Gelatin silver prints of these are on show as Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth right now, and when I went to see them, I basically wanted to buy them all, in an alternative fantasy universe where I actually have the funds to do that.
The artist’s eye gets caught on urban infrastructure; the densely gridded street pattern of the city; worn summer baseball fields, packed back to back and encroached on by houses from all sides; and, most lovingly shot of all, a gleaming rail interchange, the iron and wood of the parallel tracks caught by low light, rendered mysterious by the silver print’s blur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Sander - Men Without Masks | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sander-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sander-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Nazi Germany wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly an ideal environment for any artist, and that&amp;rsquo;s particularly true for an artist with a vision as profoundly kind, non-judgmental and humanistic as August Sander. His life&amp;rsquo;s work was a photographic project called &amp;ldquo;People of the 20th Century&amp;rdquo;, in which he chose as diverse a range of subjects as possible, and took their portraits.
This impressive show at Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth showcases examples from between 1910 and 1931, a year before Hitler&amp;rsquo;s (elected) rise to power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
