<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alison Jacques on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/alison-jacques/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alison Jacques on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/alison-jacques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sheila Hicks: Music to my Eyes | Alison Jacques</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hicks-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hicks-jacques/</guid>
      <description>Wandering into a side room at Alison Jacques felt like stumbling into an odd interplanetary church service. Arranged on plinths were small fabric discs, bound into shape by lengths of thread, looking like cosmic spheres, but also somehow like heads on straining necks. On the wall, a larger disc, like a godhead, radiantly pink.
I’d entered into the world of Sheila Hicks, a prolific artist who works in a bunch of media but who is primarily known for textile works like these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dorothea Tanning - Worlds in Collision | Alison Jacques</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</guid>
      <description>This American artist, who lived past 100, has a hefty reputation as a Surrealist icon of the 20th century. Over her long career, Dorothea Tanning was famous for her crafty paintings and stuffed-toy-like sculptures. Accompanied by her husband Max Ernst, she lived in an Arizona desert town and then in Paris. That’s certainly the life on show in her Tate Modern retrospective, which I enjoyed and returned to repeatedly during its run early last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilse d’Hollander | Victoria Miro</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dhollander-victoriamiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dhollander-victoriamiro/</guid>
      <description>Ilse d’Hollander worked in Flanders, and had just one gallery show, in a local café, before her death in 1997. She painted alone, in a studio in the countryside. And now, she has a UK solo show, on at Victoria Miro right now.
You could call all of the paintings on show “landscapes” of one kind or another. Houses, trees, grass and sky are mainly legible, though sometimes unusually cropped and zoomed in - and therefore abstracted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
