<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Léon Spilliaert on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/l%C3%A9on-spilliaert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Léon Spilliaert on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/l%C3%A9on-spilliaert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Grassie: Looking for something that doesn’t exist | Maureen Paley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/grassie-paley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/grassie-paley/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition is seasonally appropriate. I viewed Andrew Grassie’s monochrome paintings on the kind of dark January day where which the sun seems barely to lift from the horizon. The gallery, in an old school building, was viciously strongly lit, as if to compensate for the gloominess outside. The hard electric light made these small, grey, wintry paintings even harder to make out.
This all suits the show&amp;rsquo;s mysterious subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Bacon: Man and Beast | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>I caught COVID a few days ago. Worse than the sharp, uncanny fever has been the confinement - the daily stare at the fading T line on my LFT test, the lack of human contact, exercise… and gallery trips. This means I have nothing new to write about this week.
It’s possible I caught it at the last show I saw, this major Francis Bacon retrospective at the Royal Academy. I breezed around the large exhibition in around half an hour, not paying very close attention but taking in the atmosphere and getting my bearings: it’s on for a few months, so plenty of other chances to go back, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2020</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is my third year of the Artangled project, and my third end-of-year roundup. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the 2018 and 2019 format, listing the five art exhibitions I enjoyed most this year. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;ve also called out a couple of shows I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy. But for 2020, there’s only one candidate for my festive lump of coal: the global pandemic itself, one of whose side effects was to shutter London&amp;rsquo;s art galleries for months on end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Léon Spilliaert | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>What a shame this show, like all the others in London, is now closed. If there ever was an artist who exemplified social distancing, it’s Léon Spilliaert. And, having not spoken in person to anybody for coming up to two weeks now, I can’t tell anyone about how much I loved his paintings. I already regret just taking a quick spin around the three rooms in the upper galleries of the Royal Academy when I visited the exhibition, blithely assuming that I’d be back soon enough for a proper look.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
