<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theaster Gates on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/theaster-gates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theaster Gates on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/theaster-gates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving Bodies, Moving Images | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/farid-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/farid-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>This show of video art seems like an appropriate one to feature for the last post of the year. Firstly, because it&amp;rsquo;s the festive season, and the artwork I’m going to write about features a festival. Secondly, because it means that posts on the Whitechapel Gallery, my local public art collection, will bookend this year.
Alia Farid’s 15 minute movie At the Time of the Ebb could hardly be more different to the Theaster Gates ceramics I featured back in January, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theaster Gates: A Clay Sermon | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gates-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gates-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>I caught Theaster Gates’ show at Whitechapel Gallery on its last weekend. I’d cycled there without checking the (rainy) weather forecast. Along with blurry glasses and a wet bum, I’d brought along a raft of preconceptions about Gates’ work. The main one being that his activist ceramic works were compelling due to their artistic influences and political meaning, rather than being beautiful objects in themselves.
I was disabused of this dumb opinion in the final room of the show, pictured below, a spectacular collection of large pots, earthenware and stoneware, shining with different glazes, shaped with different forms, some amphora-shaped, some more organic and mysterious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
