<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timothy Taylor on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/timothy-taylor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timothy Taylor on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/timothy-taylor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Richard Patterson: Only Fans | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Richard Patterson was a YBA, part of the scandalous 1990s ‘Sensation’ generation. But, like his peers Gillian Wearing and Gavin Turk, he’s matured into a painter of sensitivity and skill. Proof of this view comes in ‘Only Fans’, a show of small-format works using what the press release describes as a “carnal palette”, which closed this week at Timothy Taylor.
All 13 paintings in the exhibition are dreamy swirls of flesh-toned roses and ochres, on luxurious-looking linen canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victor Willing | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/willing-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/willing-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Knight Errant (1978), pictured below and currently on show at Timothy Taylor, is a very intense painting, painted at an intensely trying time for its artist. Victor Willing had moved back to London from Portugal with his wife, Paula Rego; by all accounts, theirs was a deeply dysfunctional relationship. He’d been diagnosed with MS, a condition that would take his life a decade later. He&amp;rsquo;d been painting in a rented studio in Stepney that had no windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Exhibition - Simon Hantaï, Pierre Soulages and Antoni Tàpies | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</guid>
      <description>International gallery Timothy Taylor has a new home on the other side of Berkeley Square as its old one, and has put on an interesting exhibition to mark the occasion. The show brings together three artists who found fame at a similar time - the years following the last world war - but via quite different methods.
Pierre Soulages applied thick black paint - layers and layers of it - to his large canvases, while Antoni Tàpies went even heavier, with his bulky sculptures in bronze and fired clay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Masters  | Hamilton&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</guid>
      <description>So often when looking at large-scale work, it&amp;rsquo;s a single detail that catches your eye. With Modern Masters, a group photographic show currently on at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s a young woman commuter in a light raincoat, glaring out from a train. She&amp;rsquo;s the emotional centre of Shinjuku Station, Tokyo, Japan, taken by photographer Hiro in 1962.
Across the breadth of this seven metre wide work, made up of seven gelatin silver prints, faces and hands of Tokyo commuters are pressed against the steamy glass of the subway car&amp;rsquo;s window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
