<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National Gallery on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/national-gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National Gallery on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/national-gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lucian Freud: New Perspectives | National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</guid>
      <description>Kindness isn’t a word that’s really associated with Lucian Freud, whose centenary retrospective is just coming to an end at the National Gallery. As befits such a big artistic beast - Freud has only become more mega-famous since his death in 2011 - the show is epic in scale. It’s loaded with the rather cruel portraits of his lovers and children he’s famous for: the early subjects bug-eyed and on the verge of tears, the later ones nude, uncomfortably contorted and rendered in thick oil paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Thomas Jones at the National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/jones-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/jones-national/</guid>
      <description>This fascinating and tiny painting, 16cm across and 10cm high, was usually one of my stops when I dropped in to the National Gallery. I must have visited the gallery hundreds of times over the years, and therefore must have seen this painting dozens of times, back when I had the option of doing so.
The title is admirably descriptive: Jones paints, in oils on paper, a worn out wall, lit by strong sunshine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bartolomé Bermejo - Master of the Spanish Renaissance | National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>Walking around this impressive one-room exhibition , I was reminded of another artist on show in the National Gallery’s permanent collection, down the corridor. Because Bartolomé Bermejo, like the better-known Antonello da Messina, was a painter of the south that was as influenced by the Northern Renaissance as what was going on in Italy at the time.
There’s an echo of van Eyck and van der Weyden in these artists: their jewel-like clarity; the comparative disinterest in anatomical correctness and the new rules of perspective; the love lavished on different surfaces and materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edward Burne-Jones | Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</guid>
      <description>I went into this large exhibition ready to write off Edward Burne-Jones as total kitsch. But he resists being dismissed. The show is full of annoying reminders of the artist&amp;rsquo;s great popularity - from the start - and the fact that he was an epic do-gooder. Rising to world fame from humble origins, unlike some of his fellow pre-Raphaelites, Burne-Jones went into business with Socialist paragon of virtue William Morris to produce mass-market wall-hangings, to go along with his paintings for rich patrons and collectors; he saw no distinction between fine and decorative art.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
