<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wayne Thiebaud on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/wayne-thiebaud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wayne Thiebaud on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/wayne-thiebaud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2021</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</guid>
      <description>I’ve surprised myself with sticking to the Artangled project for another year. Ever since lockdown eased in April, and many London galleries reopened, I’ve posted weekly. Just as I have each week since the beginning of 2018. This site, and its thousands of words, remain a personal project: I doubt I could ‘grow the brand’ even if I tried! But I should admit, it’s remained a personal pleasure to sit down each week and put together a post, and I’ll continue doing it as long as the pleasure remains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Cartier Lucy: Cake on the Floor | Soft Opening</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, from Nashville-based painter Shannon Cartier Lucy, are really excellent, and illuminated what I saw in the gallery. (Given that show notes are so often trite and obfuscatory, it’s worth shouting out.)
“Any singular narrative is made obtuse,” by this artist, Philomena Epps writes, “the certainty of reality melted away through her embrace of fantasy and the uncanny.
“The setting of a party can be inferred by the particular debris and signs of festivities: there is cake and strings of undulating, crimped satin ribbons, but the situation reads as ominous, toxic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
