<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Margo Arden on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/alex-margo-arden/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alex Margo Arden on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/alex-margo-arden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jenkin van Zyl: Surrender | Edel Assanti</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/van-zyl-assanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/van-zyl-assanti/</guid>
      <description>I love this video of Jenkin van Zyl, which I stumbled across while writing this post. In it, the young artist and filmmaker cheerfully discusses his horrifyingly time-consuming “extreme beauty regime” in his impeccably plummy Home Counties accent. The video’s intercut with footage of van Zyl striding around east London and then eating a takeaway in full kabuki makeup, facial prosthetics and blow-up latex body suit. He&amp;rsquo;s like a lither Leigh Bowery for the Instagram generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2022</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another 50 or so new posts about some art show I&amp;rsquo;d seen that week. Following the pandemic, which put a major dampener on the Artangled project, things are pretty much back to normal on here.
That’s reflected by the numbers. I saw 220 exhibitions in total this past year, practically the same as 2019 (221) and well up from last year’s 141 - a drop almost entirely attributable to lockdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Margo Arden: All Clear | Ginny on Frederick</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arden-frederick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arden-frederick/</guid>
      <description>Inside a small, tiled room opposite Smithfield meat market, surrounded by an unplacable odour, lies a charismatic pile of wooden furniture. It’s the work of Alex Margo Arden, a performance artist with her roots in the theatre. It’s on show in a gallery that used to be an old fashioned sandwich shop, the kind made practically extinct by the rise of Pret and its bougier competitors, especially in the city centre.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
