<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Avedon on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/richard-avedon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Richard Avedon on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/richard-avedon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alice Neel: Hot Off The Griddle | Barbican</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</guid>
      <description>Alice Neel blazed her own trail for decades, painting from her home studio in New York City from the 1930s right up to her death in 1984. She lived unfashionably far uptown, ignoring the comings and goings of Precisionism, Abstract Expressionism, Pop and the rest. Even more unfashionably, she dedicated her artistic life to figuration, sticking doggedly to being an “anarchic humanist”, painting people who interested her.
This impressive retrospective, featuring works from every stage of the long career, also proves that Neel’s artistic motifs got locked in early and never varied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Masters  | Hamilton&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</guid>
      <description>So often when looking at large-scale work, it&amp;rsquo;s a single detail that catches your eye. With Modern Masters, a group photographic show currently on at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s a young woman commuter in a light raincoat, glaring out from a train. She&amp;rsquo;s the emotional centre of Shinjuku Station, Tokyo, Japan, taken by photographer Hiro in 1962.
Across the breadth of this seven metre wide work, made up of seven gelatin silver prints, faces and hands of Tokyo commuters are pressed against the steamy glass of the subway car&amp;rsquo;s window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
