<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luigi Ghirri on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/luigi-ghirri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Luigi Ghirri on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/luigi-ghirri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Demand | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>I loved Canopy, the photograph below, on show in the main gallery room at Sprüth Magers at the moment. It’s a sunny scene of some powdery blue apartment block, with a single, lemon sorbet-coloured canopy over-extended over one of the blocky white balconies. Given the work’s from 2020, the artist must have been thinking of our lockdown when he made it. The silent shadowy interiors signal the confinement of unseen occupants; I remember that for some city-dwellers, in the early days of the crisis, balconies were the only &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; outside space available to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2019</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</guid>
      <description>Across 2019, I saw 221 art exhibitions and collections, not counting repeats, and posted reviews of 48 of them on this website. That’s slightly down on the 256 I saw in 2018. But, on the plus side, I did a lot of travelling within the UK this year and managed to make the site a bit less London-centric,	posting reviews across 10 cities, up from nine last year.
As will hopefully become an annual tradition here at Artangled, I’m going to round up my five favourite shows of the year, and name and shame a couple of public gallery exhibitions I didn’t like so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francesco Arena - Cubic Metre of Seawater as a Diagonal | Sprovieri</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</guid>
      <description>Two shows from Italian artists caught my eye this week. First, this exhibition from Franceso Arena at one of the west end’s least accessible galleries, up a flight of stairs behind Regent Street. Arena makes vaguely arte povera-aligned works, using natural and found materials.
The centrepiece of this show is rather grandiose: exactly as the title suggests, seawater is contained in a metal trough, 13 metres long, oriented diagonally across the largest gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luigi Ghirri - Cartes et Territoires | Jeu de Paume</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/ghirri-paume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/ghirri-paume/</guid>
      <description>This intoxicating exhibition gives us a panoramic view of a photographer who specialised in narrow, close-cropped scenes.
Luigi Ghirri’s photographs showcase his background as a surveyor, his daily dealings with charts and maps. The exhibition concentrates on his work during the 70s, a time of comparative peace and stability in Italy, his native land, following lean postwar years. Gardens and houses are neat, the roads are smooth, the skies are (usually) blue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
