<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tate Modern on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/tate-modern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tate Modern on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/tate-modern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Martha Rosler | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rosler-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rosler-tate/</guid>
      <description>Quite suitably, this mini-exhibition of works is in a place of transit: a busy connecting room within the maze of permanent collection displays at Tate Modern. Crowds of wandering friend groups, mostly tourists, march past, without much of a glance at the display. One of the few who stopped to look while I was there, a pair of young English men, were loudly derisive.
I get the derision: at first glance, the collection&amp;rsquo;s impressively banal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubaina Himid | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’ve talked about Lubaina Himid here before. During lockdown, my mind wandered towards Ankledeep, a pair portrait that’s part of a series the British-born painter completed in the 1990s. Each work in the series depicts pairs of “watchful and calm” black women, discussing important matters.
That painting, from the Tate’s permanent collection, forms part of an illuminating retrospective of Himid’s work, currently on show at Tate Modern. Himid’s an artist who returns again and again to repeating, overlapping themes, mainly in paint, but also in ceramics, set designs and sound works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Warhol | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been waiting to see this show for ages, given Tate&amp;rsquo;s pandemic-induced shutdown just after its opening. This vast, career-spanning retrospective has been extended now until November. Following all that anticipation, it was a sad experience to visit Tate Modern post-lockdown. I could deal with the need to pre-book, the long queues and the mask wearing - all good by me. But the long queues and implied one-way system made me feel like I needed to keep moving forwards, and not linger on this or that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takis | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/takis-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/takis-tate/</guid>
      <description>Despite the multi-decade career - he died just after this Tate Modern show opened - the “kinetic” artist Takis is bound into the 1960s, specifically the decade’s go-ahead technological positivity. His art, kindled by the possibilities of electromagnetism and machinery, shows an excitement and wonder similar to that of the IBM pavilion at the 1965 World’s Fair, or Vasarely’s strobing patterns.
That’s not to suggest this exhibition is any fun though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2018</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a pretty big first year of art watching for this little side project.
In all, I saw 256 shows and collections in 2018 - not counting repeated visits to some old favourite permanent collections in London. Over that time, I featured a fifth of that total on the site, posting each week.
While I give my eyes a rest over the festive period, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up post, listing my top five of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso 1932 – Love, Fame, Tragedy | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</guid>
      <description>Even though I went in a churlish mood, on a relentlessly rainy Saturday, surrounded by wheelie-suitcase wielding crowds, I can&amp;rsquo;t pretend that this show is anything else than a megawatt, full-bore, ocean-going triumph. Picasso in 1932 was 50, world-famous, trapped in a love triangle and, according to the evidence currently on the walls at Tate Modern, at the apex of his inventive powers.
This blitz of beauty and innovation, from one of the 20th century&amp;rsquo;s foundational geniuses, overwhelmed my critical faculties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
