<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Massimo de Carlo on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/massimo-de-carlo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Massimo de Carlo on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/massimo-de-carlo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2022</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another 50 or so new posts about some art show I&amp;rsquo;d seen that week. Following the pandemic, which put a major dampener on the Artangled project, things are pretty much back to normal on here.
That’s reflected by the numbers. I saw 220 exhibitions in total this past year, practically the same as 2019 (221) and well up from last year’s 141 - a drop almost entirely attributable to lockdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Holding: Jenna Gribbon | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</guid>
      <description>I was so impressed with Jenna Gribbon’s vigorous handling of oil paint in this tight, tense exhibition. Her virile brush strokes mercilessly expose her main subject - her partner, and according to Twitter, soon-to-be wife - in full-face portraits.
Heightening the tension, in many of these works, like M in Blinding Light, below, the subject has a bright clamp light directly shone in her face. That&amp;rsquo;s the light that&amp;rsquo;s being held.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junque | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</guid>
      <description>The first time I saw US-based Jamian Juliano-Villani’s work was at Massimo de Carlo last year. I wrote about this show’s prime attraction: a cuddly tiger getting rigorously orally penetrated with a plastic-clad dildo. The fun continues in the same gallery this summer, in a group show organised around “junk”.
That’s junk in both the literal and slang senses of the word: either worthless clutter, or, like… a penis. It doesn’t really matter which way you take it (hmmm), Juliano Villani’s slapdash, don’t-care aesthetic isn’t proscriptive in the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamian Juliano-Villani - Let’s Kill Nicole | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</guid>
      <description>Slapdash, funny and deeply, deeply Instagrammable, New York-based Jamian Juliano-Villani has produced a sweet summer treat. Like a soft scoop ice cream special with hundreds and thousands, a flavoured cone AND a Flake, this show is an all out assault. And the generally lurid work is nicely offset by its host: one of London’s poshest and soberest private gallery spaces.
My favourite - introduced via Russell Tovey’s Instagram of all places - features a cuddly tiger getting savagely orally pumped by a mechanised dildo in a plastic bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermann Nitsch - Das Orgien Mysterien Theater | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/itsch-de-carlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/itsch-de-carlo/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t realise how Catholic a country Austria is until I arrived in the centre of Vienna on All Saint’s Day last year and couldn’t find a single supermarket open. Wandering past wedding-cake Baroque churches, with their over-ornate interiors, I finally found a tiny Turkish corner shop – packed, of course. Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s a memory triggered by wandering around a very different type of Austrian Catholic dysfunction, currently on show at Massimo de Carlo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
