<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenna Gribbon on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/jenna-gribbon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jenna Gribbon on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/jenna-gribbon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Danielle Roberts: Evening All Day | Fredericks &amp; Freiser</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</guid>
      <description>The portraitist Danielle Roberts, who has a show right now at the Fredericks &amp;amp; Freiser gallery, has a lot in common with Jenna Gribbon and Shannon Cartier Lucy, who I’ve featured on here before. All three painters are young women who paint young women: dramatically lit, listless, filled with ennui.
Roberts’ scenes are generally suburban, and take place at night. One woman is perched with one leg up on the back of a car in a convenience store car park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2022</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another 50 or so new posts about some art show I&amp;rsquo;d seen that week. Following the pandemic, which put a major dampener on the Artangled project, things are pretty much back to normal on here.
That’s reflected by the numbers. I saw 220 exhibitions in total this past year, practically the same as 2019 (221) and well up from last year’s 141 - a drop almost entirely attributable to lockdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Holding: Jenna Gribbon | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</guid>
      <description>I was so impressed with Jenna Gribbon’s vigorous handling of oil paint in this tight, tense exhibition. Her virile brush strokes mercilessly expose her main subject - her partner, and according to Twitter, soon-to-be wife - in full-face portraits.
Heightening the tension, in many of these works, like M in Blinding Light, below, the subject has a bright clamp light directly shone in her face. That&amp;rsquo;s the light that&amp;rsquo;s being held.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
