<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Théo Mercier on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/th%C3%A9o-mercier/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Théo Mercier on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/th%C3%A9o-mercier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Théo Mercier: The Sleeping Chapter | Conciergerie</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mercier-conciergerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mercier-conciergerie/</guid>
      <description>On a rainy November’s morning in the dead centre of Paris, I experienced a show that can only be described as dreamy.
Théo Mercier is an artist I admire a lot - and have featured on here before. He works in a monumental register, in a humble way. He reflects on the ephemerality of things, the fragility of the present as we lose ourselves, inevitably, to the future.
In the last show of his I saw - in this city in 2017 - Mércier cast Classical-looking amphoras, busts and pillars in thin plaster, and set them at dangerously teetering angles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Théo Mercier at Bugada &amp; Cargnel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mercier-bugada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mercier-bugada/</guid>
      <description>Back in lockdown, nowhere to go. Which is a problem for a website that&amp;rsquo;s updated weekly, with updates based on an exhibition I saw that week. During the spring 2020 lockdown here in London, I wrote a bunch of posts about works in permanent collections that I was thinking of at time of writing. This time, during this hopefully short winter interlude of closed galleries, I’m going to dig into my notes, and write each week about a standout show I saw sometime in the past, that didn’t make the website for whatever reason.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
