<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leon Kossoff on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/leon-kossoff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leon Kossoff on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/leon-kossoff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keith Cunningham: The Cloud of Witness | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</guid>
      <description>This is a deeply gloomy exhibition of densely-worked oil paintings with a repeating roster of macabre subjects. Dogs, fighting each other; animal carcasses and slabs of meat and fish; portraits surrounded by foul, foggy miasmas, in semi-silhouette. The grandeur of the paintings’ surroundings - every time I come to this Damien Hirst-owned gallery, I’m struck by its lofty luxuriousness - sets them off wonderfully.
The story behind the exhibition is unusual: the works were created over half a century ago, but have been barely seen since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2021</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</guid>
      <description>I’ve surprised myself with sticking to the Artangled project for another year. Ever since lockdown eased in April, and many London galleries reopened, I’ve posted weekly. Just as I have each week since the beginning of 2018. This site, and its thousands of words, remain a personal project: I doubt I could ‘grow the brand’ even if I tried! But I should admit, it’s remained a personal pleasure to sit down each week and put together a post, and I’ll continue doing it as long as the pleasure remains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leon Kossoff | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</guid>
      <description>Along with bigger names like Lucian Freud and Francis Bacon, Leon Kossoff was part of the School of London, painters who passed a pitiless eye on the down-at-heel postwar capital city, pre Olympics, pre Millennium Dome, pre Big Bang boom. A fine retrospective selection of Kossoff’s work - the artist died in 2019 - is on show right now at Annely Juda Fine Art.
Kossoff&amp;rsquo;s subject matter is firmly rooted in the city he rarely left.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
