<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>London on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/london/</link>
    <description>Recent content in London on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Richard Tuttle: 18 x 24 | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tuttle-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tuttle-modern/</guid>
      <description>Richard Tuttle’s art has consistently been defined - and derided - by the modesty of its means. Over an artistic career of almost 50 years, his wood reliefs, his single wires, his pencil marks on the wall have remained provocatively small-scale. But, taken together, I think there’s a hypnotic pull to his works. You can see for yourself with his latest collection, on show right now at Modern Art.
These new works are arrayed at eye level around the walls of the gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Patterson: Only Fans | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Richard Patterson was a YBA, part of the scandalous 1990s ‘Sensation’ generation. But, like his peers Gillian Wearing and Gavin Turk, he’s matured into a painter of sensitivity and skill. Proof of this view comes in ‘Only Fans’, a show of small-format works using what the press release describes as a “carnal palette”, which closed this week at Timothy Taylor.
All 13 paintings in the exhibition are dreamy swirls of flesh-toned roses and ochres, on luxurious-looking linen canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Neel: Hot Off The Griddle | Barbican</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</guid>
      <description>Alice Neel blazed her own trail for decades, painting from her home studio in New York City from the 1930s right up to her death in 1984. She lived unfashionably far uptown, ignoring the comings and goings of Precisionism, Abstract Expressionism, Pop and the rest. Even more unfashionably, she dedicated her artistic life to figuration, sticking doggedly to being an “anarchic humanist”, painting people who interested her.
This impressive retrospective, featuring works from every stage of the long career, also proves that Neel’s artistic motifs got locked in early and never varied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balthus: Under the Surface | Luxembourg &#43; Co</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, apparently the first Balthus exhibition in the UK since 1968, contain the following Oscar Wilde quote: “All art is at once surface and symbol. Those who go beneath the surface do so at their peril. Those who read the symbol do so at their peril.”
This plea not to look too closely is appropriate for this artist, considering the fact he was a snob, a vile anti-semite despite his Jewish heritage, and is most famous these days for his unabashedly erotic pictures of little girls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giorgio Morandi: Masterpieces from the Magnani-Rocca Foundation | Estorick Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/morandi-estorick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/morandi-estorick/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition claims to show the only work Giorgio Morandi ever painted from a commission. Still Life (Musical Instruments), from 1941 and pictured below, is definitely a break from the norm for the artist, who was and remains famous for his oddly intense small paintings of collections of bottles and cups.
It isn&amp;rsquo;t surprising that this artist wasn&amp;rsquo;t receptive to commissions. Beyond his fame, Morandi stands out for the dogged narrowness of his focus, and his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protean: Art &amp; Architecture in Post-War France | Hanina Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pichette-hanina/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pichette-hanina/</guid>
      <description>Everything sounds better in French. Their version of massive, heavy, dour post-war Abstract Expressionism is the lither, prettier Abstraction lyrique. While Pollock and Rothko painted with the weight of the world on their shoulders, their counterparts across the pond seemed to share a brighter, lighter outlook.
Perhaps their happiness came from the large amount of government support on offer. This exhibition focuses on paintings from artists who benefitted from the “1% policy” - promoted by the novelist André Malraux, who became France’s first cultural affairs minister in the post-war years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grayson Perry: Posh Cloths | Victoria Miro</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/perry-miro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/perry-miro/</guid>
      <description>Grayson Perry’s been making a multi-media attack on the idea of Englishness over recent years. In 2019, Perry had an exhibition of pots on this theme at Victoria Miro’s Mayfair space in 2019. Most recently, there&amp;rsquo;s this exhibition of textile works, and a TV show called Grayson Perry’s Full English. In both, Perry pokes at, and sometimes celebrates, English people&amp;rsquo;s sense of themselves.
I said the exhibition had &amp;ldquo;textile works&amp;rdquo;, but these particular posh cloths are actually tapestries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Noland: Stripes/Plaids/Shapes | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Noland put himself under a lot of pressure to achieve such chilled-out art. He’s been called a “minimalist” or “colour field” painter, with his large canvases banded with simple patterns - or just stripes. In fact, Stripes/ Plaids/ Shapes, the title of this show, Noland’s first monograph exhibition in the UK for over 20 years, pretty much sums up what’s on display.
So, where’s the pressure from? In the technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Flavin: colored fluorescent light | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>The handsome townhouse&amp;rsquo;s windows were glowing with warm pink light. A warm and welcome sight as I approached the David Zwirner gallery up Hay Hill on a gloomy afternoon in early February, the dark already setting in.
Warmth isn’t a feeling commonly associated with Dan Flavin, who wore his various intellectual inspirations heavily even by the standards of his fellow macho midcentury Minimals. But you can’t knock the fact that his central artistic innovation - using light as his material - was both radical and influential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>José Lerma: Guerras Tibias | Almine Rech</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/lerma-rech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/lerma-rech/</guid>
      <description>José Lerma’s striking recent paintings, several of which are on show downstairs at Almine Rech at the moment, are both austere and abundant. Austere in their extreme economy of huge brushstrokes, but abundant in the sheer quantity of paint used to make them. The artist achieves this effect by using a commercial broom to apply acrylic paint directly to a rough burlap canvas.
The head of each subject, most of which are captured in profile, fills each frame almost exactly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkin van Zyl: Surrender | Edel Assanti</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/van-zyl-assanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/van-zyl-assanti/</guid>
      <description>I love this video of Jenkin van Zyl, which I stumbled across while writing this post. In it, the young artist and filmmaker cheerfully discusses his horrifyingly time-consuming “extreme beauty regime” in his impeccably plummy Home Counties accent. The video’s intercut with footage of van Zyl striding around east London and then eating a takeaway in full kabuki makeup, facial prosthetics and blow-up latex body suit. He&amp;rsquo;s like a lither Leigh Bowery for the Instagram generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Plain Sight | Wellcome Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rafman-wellcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rafman-wellcome/</guid>
      <description>I love the Wellcome Collection! Not only does it host the best museum shop in London hands down, its exhibitions are so entertaining - imaginative grab bags of interesting things, based loosely around a single theme. I also feel a bit defensive of it as an institution, given the silly &amp;ldquo;anti-woke&amp;rdquo; media fracas it faced recently when it announced plans to update its permanent collection display.
Anyway, following recent shows on themes like electricity, games and (my favourite) teeth, it’s the turn of sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucian Freud: New Perspectives | National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</guid>
      <description>Kindness isn’t a word that’s really associated with Lucian Freud, whose centenary retrospective is just coming to an end at the National Gallery. As befits such a big artistic beast - Freud has only become more mega-famous since his death in 2011 - the show is epic in scale. It’s loaded with the rather cruel portraits of his lovers and children he’s famous for: the early subjects bug-eyed and on the verge of tears, the later ones nude, uncomfortably contorted and rendered in thick oil paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Grassie: Looking for something that doesn’t exist | Maureen Paley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/grassie-paley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/grassie-paley/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition is seasonally appropriate. I viewed Andrew Grassie’s monochrome paintings on the kind of dark January day where which the sun seems barely to lift from the horizon. The gallery, in an old school building, was viciously strongly lit, as if to compensate for the gloominess outside. The hard electric light made these small, grey, wintry paintings even harder to make out.
This all suits the show&amp;rsquo;s mysterious subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2022</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2022/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another 50 or so new posts about some art show I&amp;rsquo;d seen that week. Following the pandemic, which put a major dampener on the Artangled project, things are pretty much back to normal on here.
That’s reflected by the numbers. I saw 220 exhibitions in total this past year, practically the same as 2019 (221) and well up from last year’s 141 - a drop almost entirely attributable to lockdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Bodies, Moving Images | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/farid-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/farid-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>This show of video art seems like an appropriate one to feature for the last post of the year. Firstly, because it&amp;rsquo;s the festive season, and the artwork I’m going to write about features a festival. Secondly, because it means that posts on the Whitechapel Gallery, my local public art collection, will bookend this year.
Alia Farid’s 15 minute movie At the Time of the Ebb could hardly be more different to the Theaster Gates ceramics I featured back in January, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Dordoy: Answering Machine | GRIMM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dordoy-grimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dordoy-grimm/</guid>
      <description>The ambiance cast by the works in this exhibition somehow matched the weather on the day I went: cold, clear and uncannily still. Alex Dordoy uses shallow collages of acrylic paint on canvas to render apparently comforting and familiar scenes. The interior of a church (Answering Machine); a seascape (A Few Careless Words); a couple camping in a forest (Kindling the March Wind).
Look closer, though, and things get uncomfortable. The church’s statues are cut off at the ankles; a big wave in the middle of the sea is breaking on… apparently nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harland Miller: Imminent End, Rescheduled Eternally | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/miller-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/miller-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>Harland Miller is a novelist as well as a painter, and his best-known works bring the two media together. I’ve seen (and loved) his large painted versions of imaginary Penguin book covers: the artist faithfully matched the typeface and colours of the classic series in his paintings, but added mordant titles of his own, with his own name always in the author&amp;rsquo;s slot.
He’s now taken over the large, coldly-lit White Cube space in Bermondsey, with 45 paintings and works on paper, all produced this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romauld Hazoumè: Carnaval | October Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hazoume-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hazoume-october/</guid>
      <description>Like Antoni Tàpies, featured on here last week, Romauld Hazoumè uses found objects in his work. But the two artists could hardly be more different. As this show highlights, Hazoumè is droll, down to earth and humanist where Tàpies is sober, grand and ethereal.
This artist, who lives and works in Benin, uses discarded oilcans, bottles, feathers and other throwaway objects to produce what he calls masques bidons (repurposed masks). The title of the exhibition’s a clue to the kind of atmosphere Hazoumè wants to create: just like at a carnival parade, the masks shouldn’t just look good, they also provide a kind of subversive social commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>antoni tàpies: alchemy | Nahmad Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tapies-nahmad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tapies-nahmad/</guid>
      <description>Nahmad Projects is one of Mayfair’s shiniest white cubes, a deceptively large gallery with a nave, side chapel and benches. This allows the dozen or so large, abstract works that make up most of this exhibition to be presented like relics in a church.
Antoni Tàpies, the artist on show, made a decisive turn towards abstraction early in his career, and built up a distinctive visual lexicon of signs and symbols, using everyday materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Denny - Dotcom Séance | Outernet</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/denny-outernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/denny-outernet/</guid>
      <description>The bombastically-named, black-and-gold clad Now Building is the West End&amp;rsquo;s newest (and brightest) art gallery. Opened a couple of weeks ago opposite Tottenham Court Road tube station, the open-plan space glows from within, thanks to the massive LED screens that blaze across its interior walls and ceiling. It’s part of a newly-opened complex called the Outernet, which also includes a new theatre and the restoration of a very useful pathway to Soho Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secundino Hernández: time TIME | Victoria Miro</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hernandez-victoriamiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hernandez-victoriamiro/</guid>
      <description>This week, I got a lesson in the imaginative handling of paint. The classroom was the beautiful, high-ceilinged main gallery at Victoria Miro in Islington. The teacher was Madrid-based Secundino Hernández. The subject, pictured below, is Minimar (2022): an enormous canvas which, despite its title, captures something cosmically vast. There are several paintings of his on show in this exhibition, but Minimar stood out.
I loved Hernández’s unmannered handling of his acrylic paints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victor Willing | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/willing-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/willing-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Knight Errant (1978), pictured below and currently on show at Timothy Taylor, is a very intense painting, painted at an intensely trying time for its artist. Victor Willing had moved back to London from Portugal with his wife, Paula Rego; by all accounts, theirs was a deeply dysfunctional relationship. He’d been diagnosed with MS, a condition that would take his life a decade later. He&amp;rsquo;d been painting in a rented studio in Stepney that had no windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marwan Bassiouni: New British Views | Workplace</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bassiouni-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bassiouni-workplace/</guid>
      <description>There’s something about the low light of my homeland, depicted in a painting or a photograph, that pushes me to write about it: see previous examples from George Shaw, Mike Silva and Jock McFadyen. This time, it’s an exhibition from Marwan Bassiouni, whose impressively cosmopolitan background (Italian-Swiss-Egyptian-American) hasn’t stopped him depicting the most humdrum, low-lit British landscapes with notable sensitivity and skill.
Bassiouni’s conceit is simple: he shoots landscapes, seen through the windows of mosques and Islamic prayer rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cudelice Brazelton IV: Tensors | Cell Project Space</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/brazelton-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/brazelton-cell/</guid>
      <description>The multimedia artist Cudelice Brazelton IV was born in Dallas and studied in Germany, where he now lives. The notes for this show, Brazelton’s first in London, state he spent some time in between “working in Ohio’s industrial foundries”. That sounds like, but doesn’t quite explicitly state, that he had a job in a factory. Or maybe it was a fancy art residency.
Either way, the sounds and sights of the factory floor are clearly a major inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Craig-Martin: Past Present | Cristea Roberts Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/craig-martin-cristea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/craig-martin-cristea/</guid>
      <description>Pieter Saenredam’s paintings of bracingly plain church interiors helped to define the Dutch Golden Age, artistically at least. Saenredam was a master of minimalism, taking infinite care with slightly varied shades of white on his walls, rendering the play of sunlight and shadow.
Michael Craig-Martin’s also known for his use of colour, though his palette is hard, flat and bold. In this exhibition of new works, Craig-Martin committed the (self-described) “sacrilege” of recreating Saenredam’s Interior of the Sint-Odulphskerk in Assendelft as a line drawing, then printing it in several different colourways, including this ultimate inversion - one in black.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Felipe Rezende: Long is the Road | Jack Bell Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rezende-bell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rezende-bell/</guid>
      <description>Taking a midweek day off always makes me feel a bit delinquent. At leisure to do fun stuff - in my case, that usually means going to galleries - while most of the people around me are at work. As it happens, the world of work is the guiding subject of this impressive exhibition, though the world of its paintings is far distant from the Mayfair gallery that hosts them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lea Cetera: Chassis | Phyilida Reid</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cetera-reid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cetera-reid/</guid>
      <description>The titular work in this exhibition is fascinatingly described in the show notes. It’s a “motor-powered gyroscopic structure based on a rotocasting machine”, in which a small transparent figurine is pinned between steel frames, and periodically spun around.
It’s a hypnotic work, most powerful when the growly motor stops. Contained in this (female) plastic body are red and blue liquids, that combine to form a purple goo, that mostly settles wherever the figurine is angled during the rest periods, but leaves the odd spatter in the areas above the watermark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carolee Schneemann: Body Politics | Barbican</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/schneemann-barbican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/schneemann-barbican/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about the Queen’s death just after seeing this exhibition, a full career retrospective of the US painter and performance artist Carolee Schneemann. On getting the notification on my phone, sat in a comfy chair on the ground floor of the Barbican Centre, I took off my headphones - maybe expecting that the large, crowded, concrete-clad room would fall into reverent monarchist silence, and that I should experience that momentous hush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernat Klein: His Garden | Rodeo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/klein-rodeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/klein-rodeo/</guid>
      <description>The dog days for London’s commercial galleries come slightly after the dog days of actual summer. This weekend, I walked around Mayfair as usual, knowing not much would be open - and, sure enough, most of the galleries were in darkness, or with white paper or blinds on the windows, the early autumn exhibition in the process of being installed. Only during Christmastime is there less on offer to the dedicated gallery-goer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Cohen: Two Point Eight Million | FOLD</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</guid>
      <description>This show is dominated by a mini mountain range of day-glo green “eco chips” - the kind of polystyrene-like packaging that pads out Amazon boxes - in the far corner of the gallery. The artist Benjamin Cohen called it all mouth and no trousers, and studded the green chip mountains with an amp and two transparent speakers emitting droning sounds.
It’s a riff on Félix González-Torres’s Portrait of Ross in LA, which was a pile of sweets stacked up in the corner of the gallery, weighing the same as the artist’s lover - before he was stricken with AIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martha Rosler | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rosler-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rosler-tate/</guid>
      <description>Quite suitably, this mini-exhibition of works is in a place of transit: a busy connecting room within the maze of permanent collection displays at Tate Modern. Crowds of wandering friend groups, mostly tourists, march past, without much of a glance at the display. One of the few who stopped to look while I was there, a pair of young English men, were loudly derisive.
I get the derision: at first glance, the collection&amp;rsquo;s impressively banal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonio Calderara: From Lake Orta | Lisson Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/calderara-lisson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/calderara-lisson/</guid>
      <description>Antonio Calderara, also known as Antonio da Vaciago, lived quietly next to Lake Orta in northern Italy. Born in 1903, he was active from the 1920s, right up to his death in 1978. According to this collection of works, at Lisson Gallery, he specialised in small, jewel-like figurative works on wooden panels early on, eventually moving to almost-abstraction by the end. All his work is linked by a sense of quietude and withholding: quite appropriate for an artist who’s dropped into semi-obscurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orlanda Broom: Shapeshifters | Grove Square Galleries</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</guid>
      <description>Producing this collection of abstract works, made with colourful resin on canvas, must have taken a toll on the artist. Orlanda Broom can only work on works using resin for a couple of months each year - otherwise the ambient temperature isn’t right. The perfectionist artist also doesn’t allow any resin works with trapped hairs and dust out of the studio.
“I’m interested in the interpretation of abstract works,” she says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Opie: To What We Think We Remember | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</guid>
      <description>Catherine Opie is a globally-famous photographer who’s broadened her artistic topics of interest over recent years. She hit the big time in the 90s through her confrontational self-portraits, carving words and pictures into her flesh. They’re still her best-known photos. But a set of her work from the last decade, currently on show at Thomas Dane Gallery, reveals an artist in a lyrical mood.
These are photos of calm lakes, sunlit windows and dappled light, revealed in lush pigment prints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathleen Ryan: Red Rose | Josh Lilley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/ryan-lilley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/ryan-lilley/</guid>
      <description>I chucked out a rotten half lemon the same morning I saw this show. There was nothing pretty about it, the yellow skin turned wobbly, the innards blue black: fruit spoils so quickly in the summer heat. Kathleen Ryan, on the other hand, sees beauty in this kind of organic ruin; she assembles semi precious gemstones, studded with metal, into sculptures of mouldy fruits, and produces something unique and strange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magdalena Skupinska: Blending Elements | Maximillian William</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/skupinska-maximillian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/skupinska-maximillian/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition, similar to the Alex Margo Arden show I covered last week, smells great. This time though, the odour wafting through the gallery isn’t synthetic, but all natural, emanating from the dried pine needles that carpets one of the works. There’s a little glass pot of pine next to the visitor’s book, too. Raw nature is an important governing concept for the Warsaw-born, London-based artist, who mixes her own paints from natural products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Margo Arden: All Clear | Ginny on Frederick</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arden-frederick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arden-frederick/</guid>
      <description>Inside a small, tiled room opposite Smithfield meat market, surrounded by an unplacable odour, lies a charismatic pile of wooden furniture. It’s the work of Alex Margo Arden, a performance artist with her roots in the theatre. It’s on show in a gallery that used to be an old fashioned sandwich shop, the kind made practically extinct by the rise of Pret and its bougier competitors, especially in the city centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haunted Realism | Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/haunted-gagosian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/haunted-gagosian/</guid>
      <description>This is a typically epically show-offy group exhibition, in which various contemporary and 20th century A-listers face each other down in large galleries police by black-clad security men. A confluence of art celebrity, crammed together: here, a wall full of Richard Prince photos loomed over a Rachel Whiteread bed; there, a Jenny Saville bum rubbed against what looked to be a string shopping bag with a chunk of polystyrene inside (in fact it was a bronze and marble sculpture from Tatiana Trouvé).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emil Nolde: Anatomy of Light and Water | Bastian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nolde-bastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nolde-bastian/</guid>
      <description>Emil Nolde was a supremely talented painter who made gorgeous use of colours suggesting light. He also had well-documented Nazi sympathies. That’s surely a big reason why he isn’t much seen: this small show of watercolours was the first Nolde exhibition I can recall in London in my years of gallery-going.
As an older man, Nolde spent his summers in Seebüll in Northern Germany, a beach-side town. Thomas Mann country - Caspar David Friedrich country - at least in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henni Alftan: Contour | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/alftan-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/alftan-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>The painting below is called Tinted. It really stood out to me when I visited the artist’s show at Sprüth Magers, which opened this week. The painter, Henni Alftan, is Finland-born and Paris-based. She takes her inspiration from everyday mundane human scenes, except the human beings are absent. A prevailing theme in exhibitions featured here recently, including one from Thomas Demand (at the same gallery) and another from Hwang Seontae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Wall | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wall-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wall-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Wall’s best known for large, lush, elaborately staged photographs set in light boxes. This absorbing exhibition puts on show several of his unstaged and landscape works - all of which are blown up to a grand scale. The show’s at the large White Cube gallery in Mayfair was eerily deserted when I visited, with most other commercial galleries closed due to the Jubilee weekend.
Quite appropriately, the standout exhibit depicts a party - though not one you’d want to be at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chantal Joffe: A Sunday Afternoon in Whitechapel | Whitechapel Station</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/joffe-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/joffe-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>I’m a major train geek, but even I wasn’t ready for the opening of the Elizabeth Line, London’s biggest public transport event in decades, to be so joyous. The huge, cool, beautiful stations were filled with joyriders the first day it opened on Tuesday. By later in the week, the stations were still packed, but by now almost everybody seemed to be using the line for what it’s intended to be: a much quicker way of getting across town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Salgado: A Never-Setting Sun | BEERS London</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/salgado-beers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/salgado-beers/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Salgado draws inspiration from heavy folk traditions and literary sources, but his light touch renders his paintings pretty, lyrical. The collection of oil-and-pastel portraits on show at BEERS London also benefitted greatly from being viewed on a sunny day.
His subjects - mainly male - are surrounded by flowers and greenery, occasionally printed words. The palette is vibrant and zingy. Some of the artistic signifiers are a bit on the nose - did his portrait of Virginia Woolf really need to be titled River Ouse?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Vostell: Destruction is Life | Cardi Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/vostell-cardi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/vostell-cardi/</guid>
      <description>There are two impressive mini-retrospectives for members of the post-war Fluxus group - some of the original performance artists - on in London at the moment. Per Kirkeby’s dark landscape paintings are at Michael Werner, while Wolf Vostell, one of the movement’s leading lights, has taken over all three floors of the large Cardi Gallery.
Vostell specialised in what he called décollages - mixed media collages, built through creating new things and destroying existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victoria Crowe: Resonance of Time | Flowers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/crowe-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/crowe-flowers/</guid>
      <description>A pair of unseasonal exhibitions this week, in galleries on opposite sides of Cork Street. Unseasonal in that both of the featured artists use bare, skeletal tree branches as consistent visual motifs; look around you though, and trees are bursting into leaf everywhere, as summer begins to stir.
Victoria Crowe, on show at Flowers, studied under Prunella Clough, who’s shown up more than once on this site before; unlike her teacher though, Crowe’s work escapes from the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohammed Sami | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</guid>
      <description>The Execution Room, painted by Mohammed Sami, is one of the most impressively ugly artworks I’ve seen in a while. It’s currently on show at Modern Art, along with a collection of other new, thematically-linked work from this Iraq-born, Sweden-based artist.
It shows a dining table and chair set in a style that might kindly be termed “dictator chic”. I suspect, but can’t confirm by googling, that it was a room in Saddam Hussein’s palace, captured by allied forces during the disastrous war of 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keith Cunningham: The Cloud of Witness | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</guid>
      <description>This is a deeply gloomy exhibition of densely-worked oil paintings with a repeating roster of macabre subjects. Dogs, fighting each other; animal carcasses and slabs of meat and fish; portraits surrounded by foul, foggy miasmas, in semi-silhouette. The grandeur of the paintings’ surroundings - every time I come to this Damien Hirst-owned gallery, I’m struck by its lofty luxuriousness - sets them off wonderfully.
The story behind the exhibition is unusual: the works were created over half a century ago, but have been barely seen since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steph Huang: Everything and Nothing | mother’s tankstation limited</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/huang-tankstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/huang-tankstation/</guid>
      <description>Steph Huang, who was born in Taiwan but now lives and works in London, makes sardonic, surprising, and sometimes funny use of everyday objects. A collection of works are on show at mother’s tankstation: several quite modest individual pieces pack a bigger collective punch when imaginatively displayed, together.
The artist clearly misses home, but finds quirky pleasures in her new surroundings. The ironically named Forest features bamboo leaves, neatly trapped in a gridded metal mesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AR Penck: Paintings 1974-1990 | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/penck-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/penck-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>AR Penck has been on show pretty frequently in London over recent years: I enjoyed an intimate collection of his paintings and sculpture at Michael Werner last November, and now some large canvases are at the large White Cube gallery in Mayfair. His popularity isn’t surprising. Penck, who died in 2017, was a loveable artist, with his large canvases of hieroglyph-like figures and symbols.
The large scale of the White Cube gallery gives his works some room to breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yves Marchand &amp; Romain Meffre: Movie Theaters | Tristan Hoare Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/marchand-meffre-hoare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/marchand-meffre-hoare/</guid>
      <description>‘Ruin porn’ is a loaded term. Viewers living in intact and tidy homes, getting a vicarious thrill from images of spectacularly derelict places. Places we don’t have to deal with in our day to day lives.
Anyway, if ruin porn is a thing, Yves Marchand and Romain Meffre are some of the top pornographers in the game. They’re behind The Ruins of Detroit, a coffee table book of sumptuously shot photos of the motor city, once so prosperous and now run so completely to seed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubaina Himid | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’ve talked about Lubaina Himid here before. During lockdown, my mind wandered towards Ankledeep, a pair portrait that’s part of a series the British-born painter completed in the 1990s. Each work in the series depicts pairs of “watchful and calm” black women, discussing important matters.
That painting, from the Tate’s permanent collection, forms part of an illuminating retrospective of Himid’s work, currently on show at Tate Modern. Himid’s an artist who returns again and again to repeating, overlapping themes, mainly in paint, but also in ceramics, set designs and sound works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternalising Art History: From Da Vinci to Modigliani | Unit London</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nft-unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nft-unit/</guid>
      <description>Despite their sudden and enormous impact on the art world over recent months, the ins and outs of NFTs have passed me by. This show is the first of its type I’ve been to - in which the artworks are digital files, authenticated on the blockchain. I can’t face attempting to explain what the blockchain is, because I’ve read several Wikipedia pages and I’m still not sure I understand it myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brothers in Art: Walter &amp; Harold Steggles and the East London Group | Beecroft Art Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been really interested in The East London Group’s paintings for a while - ever since I moved to Bow, slap bang in the middle of the neighbourhood depicted by these painters. This large exhibition puts over 100 paintings on show: that&amp;rsquo;s a hefty proportion of the total known surviving works from the Group. With the big majority of these in private collections, this exhibition represents a rare opportunity for an interested viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bona to Vada Your Dolly Bold Eek: Assume Vivid Astro Focus | LAMB</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/avaf-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/avaf-lamb/</guid>
      <description>As an aficionado of Round the Horne, I was tempted into this show by its title. It’s in polari, a secret language used by gay men in the years after the Second World War, and translates into something like “nice to see you”! Polari was actually on the way out by the time (closeted) comedians Kenneth Williams and Hugh Paddick (aka Julian and Sandy) spoke the language on BBC radio, in the mid-1960s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Bacon: Man and Beast | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>I caught COVID a few days ago. Worse than the sharp, uncanny fever has been the confinement - the daily stare at the fading T line on my LFT test, the lack of human contact, exercise… and gallery trips. This means I have nothing new to write about this week.
It’s possible I caught it at the last show I saw, this major Francis Bacon retrospective at the Royal Academy. I breezed around the large exhibition in around half an hour, not paying very close attention but taking in the atmosphere and getting my bearings: it’s on for a few months, so plenty of other chances to go back, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Holding: Jenna Gribbon | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</guid>
      <description>I was so impressed with Jenna Gribbon’s vigorous handling of oil paint in this tight, tense exhibition. Her virile brush strokes mercilessly expose her main subject - her partner, and according to Twitter, soon-to-be wife - in full-face portraits.
Heightening the tension, in many of these works, like M in Blinding Light, below, the subject has a bright clamp light directly shone in her face. That&amp;rsquo;s the light that&amp;rsquo;s being held.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Aagaard Hansen: Autumn skullcap | Union Pacific</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/aagaard-pacific/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/aagaard-pacific/</guid>
      <description>The weather in London this week has been grey, cold and still. Though the first daffodils are out in the parks, and there’s that extra few minutes of light in the afternoon to let us know that better times are on their way. This wintry feeling meant that Martin Aagaard Hansen’s paintings, scratchy and cold, struck a chord with me this week.
Copenhagen-based Hansen clearly enjoys escaping to the countryside: the paintings on show at Union Pacific are closely thematically linked, all some variation on a forest scene with solitary wanderers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hughie O’Donoghue: Deep Water and the Architecture of Memory | Marlborough Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/odonoghue-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/odonoghue-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Hughie O’Donoghue is a Manchester-born painter who now lives in Ireland. I say painter, but the works on show in this exhibition are complex, layered collages that include painting, but are also built up through photographs and resin. Especially unusual are the bases: O’Donoghue paints and prints on shiny tarpaulins, sackcloths, sandbags, which must make his craft very technically difficult to pull off.
Taken as a whole, the images are haunting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theaster Gates: A Clay Sermon | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gates-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gates-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>I caught Theaster Gates’ show at Whitechapel Gallery on its last weekend. I’d cycled there without checking the (rainy) weather forecast. Along with blurry glasses and a wet bum, I’d brought along a raft of preconceptions about Gates’ work. The main one being that his activist ceramic works were compelling due to their artistic influences and political meaning, rather than being beautiful objects in themselves.
I was disabused of this dumb opinion in the final room of the show, pictured below, a spectacular collection of large pots, earthenware and stoneware, shining with different glazes, shaped with different forms, some amphora-shaped, some more organic and mysterious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s a Magda Archer Christmas | Karsten Schubert</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/archer-schubert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/archer-schubert/</guid>
      <description>Merry Christmas one and all! Unless you want a festive spin around London’s commercial galleries - in which case you’ll find they’ve all shut due to the COVID wave that’s engulfed the city recently. Some people didn&amp;rsquo;t get the message though, and like me speculatively walked the streets of Mayfair yesterday, armed with a negative LFT test, getting repeatedly confronted by locked doors.
So, this last single-show post of the year - next week as usual it’s a roundup of my five top shows of the year - is about something I saw a couple of weeks back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Shrigley: MAYFAIR TENNIS BALL EXCHANGE | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/shrigley-stephen-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/shrigley-stephen-friedman/</guid>
      <description>“I will make 100 works on paper with the intention that no more than half are any good,” the extremely popular and successful artist David Shrigley told the Guardian recently. “And there are probably four where you’re like: ‘This is basically fantastic! This is me demonstrating my area of expertise and all the other 96 are just attempts to do this.’ And do they sell? Do they fuck. You look through the inventory going: ‘Nobody bought that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Constable | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/constable-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/constable-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>A few years back, I bought a print of one of my favourite works in the National Gallery, which as a native Londoner I’ve passed countless times over the years. Cenotaph to the Memory of Sir Joshua Reynolds was completed by John Constable in 1836, a year before the painter’s death. The romantic, autumnal scene, the deep browns of the mostly-bare trees melding into the vanilla-yellow, darkening sky, a ghostly stag gazing straight back at the viewer, is still on my wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hwang Seontae: The Power of Light | Pontone Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hwang-pontone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hwang-pontone/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition shows scenes of well-appointed, but empty modernist interiors from Korean artist Hwang Seontae. They’re light boxes, with sandblasted glass fronts and cold LED lights, the cable powering each scene discreetly boxed in.
In these imaginary rooms, the light comes from the windows: all of the works on show have the same title, The Space with Sunshine. It’s sunny outside, meaning that strong shadows are cast on the wooden floorboards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frieze Sculpture | The Regent’s Park</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/frieze-regents-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/frieze-regents-park/</guid>
      <description>My last trip to the Frieze tent, in 2019, ended up as a bit of a disaster, not that I admitted it on here at the time. After three hours of walking, looking intently, elbowing aside crowds and becoming increasingly unbalanced by loading more and more free merchandise into my straining tote, I ended up having a quiet panic attack in Benugo, vowing never again. If you’re not important enough to buy any of the work on show, then you’re effectively paying quite a lot to be overstimulated to the point of exhaustion - not really the best frame of mind to look at art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Fischl: The Krefeld Project | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</guid>
      <description>Sorry Lucian Freud, but when I think of a painter who captures the vulnerability and variety of the skin we live in, it’s Eric Fischl. The American artist, still active and showing at Skarstedt this autumn, works with loose, sparse but unerringly suggestive brushstrokes. He’s an unsentimental, relentless chronicler of skin, our skin, as it stretches, puffs and sags.
This show zooms in on a particular series Fischl undertook in 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Howard: You Have a New Memory | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</guid>
      <description>I first featured the British painter Rachel Howard on this site in 2018, when I saw a stately and sombre show of hers in Damien Hirst’s cavernous Newport Street Gallery. Back then, she showed works based around the stations of the cross. This new exhibition, Howard’s first at Simon Lee, is a more intimate affair, both spatially, in that the Mayfair gallery’s a bit pokier, and in the subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leon Kossoff | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</guid>
      <description>Along with bigger names like Lucian Freud and Francis Bacon, Leon Kossoff was part of the School of London, painters who passed a pitiless eye on the down-at-heel postwar capital city, pre Olympics, pre Millennium Dome, pre Big Bang boom. A fine retrospective selection of Kossoff’s work - the artist died in 2019 - is on show right now at Annely Juda Fine Art.
Kossoff&amp;rsquo;s subject matter is firmly rooted in the city he rarely left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jorge Otero-Pailos: American Fence | Holtermann Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/otero-pailos-holtermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/otero-pailos-holtermann/</guid>
      <description>Like many other Londoners, I first heard of Jorge Otero-Pailos with his knockout The Ethics of Dust show in 2016, in which he applied, pulled off and displayed an absorbent latex panel across an entire wall of Westminster Hall. Under that spectacular medieval hammerbeam roof, the Spanish-born, US-based artist confronted us with the layered debris of centuries of our history. An unforgettable sight!
Five years later, Otero-Pailos is showing in London again, digging into some more recent history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hockney: The Arrival of Spring, Normandy, 2020 | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hockney-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hockney-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>While the world went into lockdown last Spring, David Hockney, ensconced in his comfortable country house in northern France, took out his iPad and captured the passing of the seasons.
Through circumstance, this Royal Academy show, containing 116 of these iPad pictures, comes at a time when lockdowns are over, and the Burlington House courtyard and the city beyond is ever more crowded. We’re having a springtime, then, even with the days getting shorter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Riding Gravestones: George Shaw &amp; Thomas Bewick | Laure Genillard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bewick-shaw-genillard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bewick-shaw-genillard/</guid>
      <description>I love a show that brings together two apparently totally different artists, and finds unexpected and inspiring connections! In fact, that kind of thing is what this blog is all about, as I tried to explain in my first post way back when. And I’ve showcased a couple such exhibitions since.
So, on one hand, George Shaw, famous for painting scenes from the not-so-nice Coventry suburb he grew up in, using the kind of enamel paints more commonly used for model aeroplanes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllida Barlow | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Why am I looking at and writing about concrete so much this summer? First there was Prunella Clough’s desolate little paintings of midcentury urban corners, that caught my eye at Annely Juda Fine Art. Then there was Yu Ji’s dripping, detritus-filled installation at Chisenhale Gallery.
Now, rather grander than both, is Phyllida Barlow’s ring of a hundred or so three-metre-high cement sentinels, that squeeze to the edges of Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth’s main gallery at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Burley: The Intricate Live Habits and Rituals of the Goblin | GAO Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/burley-gao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/burley-gao/</guid>
      <description>I wonder whether Daniel Burley, the young British multimedia artist, pored over the memorably disgusting Fungus the Bogeyman when he grew up. He’d definitely have seen Shrek. And he’s clearly come of age in the noughties, the decade that fashion forgot, with its gross bootcuts and belly shorts.
All that’s gone in the aesthetic mixer for this show in the small GAO Gallery, just off the Mile End Road. Three “goblins”, green figures made of epoxy and steel, finished off with oil paint, galavant across the floor: tumbling over a log, gathering flowers, and clawing at the sky with sharp talons - painted with nail polish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Damien Hirst: Relics and Fly Paintings | Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hirst-gagosian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hirst-gagosian/</guid>
      <description>Again and again, on this site I’ve returned to exhibitions from the YBAs of the 90s. Damien Hirst, the most famous of them all probably, relies more on spectacle these days than the mature style of his contemporaries Gillian Wearing, Tracey Emin and Gary Hume, for example.
Gagosian, with its black clad security guards and show-off cavernous spaces, is a perfect venue for Hirst, who’s come up with a variety of spectacular installations to be on display there for the next few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosie Gibbens: Soft Girls | Zabludowicz Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gibbens-zabludowicz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gibbens-zabludowicz/</guid>
      <description>Rosie Gibbens’ sculptures are soft, cute and semi-interactive. The artist, clad in a constraining sheath dress and high heels, has activated this room of ‘soft girls’ in performances. Visitors to her show at the Zabludowicz Collection can also unroll a giant plushy tongue, attached to the wall by a mangel-like device, and use a foot pump to inflate one of the girls’ hands (a plastic glove).
The artist’s made inventive used of a combination of sex toys, clothing, office chairs and exercise equipment, plus a bunch of other found objects, to pull together her cute collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forest | Parafin</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/forest-parafin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/forest-parafin/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always liked a good thematic group show, and this one at Parafin didn’t disappoint. The theme is &amp;rsquo;the forest&amp;rsquo;, which are part of our shared consciousness, even for those of us who live in the middle of large cities. Across different cultures and times, the forest represents a quiet place to retreat to and hide. But it&amp;rsquo;s also a lonely place, where monsters may lurk.
The exhibition begins with an engraving from the mystical French artist Gustave Doré to set the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackney in the 1980s: Photographs from the Tape/Slide project | Hackney Museum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tape-hackney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tape-hackney/</guid>
      <description>This show isn’t a likely subject for me. It’s a photography exhibition, sure, but the photos in it aren’t fine art. Rather, they’re the legacy of the Rio Tape/Slide Newsreel Group, a local voluntary project that ran at the Rio (a cinema in Dalston, East London) from 1982 until 1988. These photos are some of the thousands of slides that were found mouldering in the cinema’s basement recently, and provide a totally fascinating slice of life in a place that’s really familiar to me, at a time that’s just in living memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Cartier Lucy: Cake on the Floor | Soft Opening</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, from Nashville-based painter Shannon Cartier Lucy, are really excellent, and illuminated what I saw in the gallery. (Given that show notes are so often trite and obfuscatory, it’s worth shouting out.)
“Any singular narrative is made obtuse,” by this artist, Philomena Epps writes, “the certainty of reality melted away through her embrace of fantasy and the uncanny.
“The setting of a party can be inferred by the particular debris and signs of festivities: there is cake and strings of undulating, crimped satin ribbons, but the situation reads as ominous, toxic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheila Hicks: Music to my Eyes | Alison Jacques</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hicks-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hicks-jacques/</guid>
      <description>Wandering into a side room at Alison Jacques felt like stumbling into an odd interplanetary church service. Arranged on plinths were small fabric discs, bound into shape by lengths of thread, looking like cosmic spheres, but also somehow like heads on straining necks. On the wall, a larger disc, like a godhead, radiantly pink.
I’d entered into the world of Sheila Hicks, a prolific artist who works in a bunch of media but who is primarily known for textile works like these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roe Ethridge: Pictures for Sale | Greengrassi</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/ethridge-greengrassi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/ethridge-greengrassi/</guid>
      <description>Roe Ethridge, an American photographer, spent the early part of 2021 in Paris, as the city started to shrug off the hideous toll of COVID, and started to reopen. The French capital had a tough time of it by European standards, both in its case rate and the strictness of the restrictions faced by citizens, including a nighttime curfew.
There’s something of that mood in the pose of an old lady who caught the photographer’s eye one day, and is featured in this show, on currently at Greengrassi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swinging London | Hazlitt Holland-Hibbert</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/swinging-hazlitt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/swinging-hazlitt/</guid>
      <description>Three linked exhibitions this week, each carrying with them a whiff of patchouli oil and pot. It’s not quite (yet) a Summer of Love in London, but these shows all reach back to the 1960s, a time of Pop and Op&amp;hellip; and some very big floppy collars.
One of the biggest and floppiest is sported by legendary fashion designer Ossie Clark, sketched at home by the still more legendary (and decade-defining) David Hockney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yu Ji: Wasted Mud | Chisenhale Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/yu-chisenhale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/yu-chisenhale/</guid>
      <description>My response to this installation in the reopened one-room Chisenhale Gallery was quite visceral. The first thing that hit me was the smell of standing water, which stood in puddles on the concrete floor, after dripping down from steel pipes. The source of those pipes is also the source of the second sensory reaction: stainless steel jugs churn loudly, a threatening hum. This is an electric water pump, the source of the drips, the puddles, the smell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracey Emin / Edvard Munch: The Loneliness of the Soul | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>There’s a bench in Berkeley Square in Mayfair with a funny plaque: On this bench in 2007, it states, the notorious artist Tracey Emin surrendered all her art rebel credibility when she decided to become a member of the Royal Academy of Arts. Times have changed: she’s not just a member these days. Instead, this self-described “notorious rebel” has aged into full blown grande dame status, and is getting a new RA exhibition, a few streets away from the square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Opie | Lisson Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/opie-lisson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/opie-lisson/</guid>
      <description>This artist is the subject of much critical sniffiness, thanks to his works generally being so open and people pleasing. His vinyl cuts and sculptures adorn many a public square (and the odd album cover), to general acclaim. His current show at Lisson Gallery’s Mayfair outpost is typically cute and arresting.
There are two main subjects, generally in painted metal: group scenes of crowds walking down the street, and brightly-coloured tower blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prunella Clough and Alan Reynolds | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</guid>
      <description>Prunella Clough liked to explore the train yards at Willesden Junction: quite a messy and down-at-heel place these days, but surely an absolute decrepit dump in the post-war years in which she started working. From a wealthy background, she spent much of her career teaching at the Chelsea School of Art. But her own artistic output focused on semi-abstract paintings and prints of grimy, industrial and forgotten corners of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ed Fornieles: Associations | Carlos/Ishikawa</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fornieles-carlos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fornieles-carlos/</guid>
      <description>Ed Fornieles brings together a couple of prevailing themes I’ve been covering on Artangled these last few months. First, the technique of using found photographs in a clever way: see here for similar on Wade Guyton and Jan Hendrickse. Second, responding artistically to the weird phase of lockdown the world’s been in this past year or so: as have Gillian Wearing, Alban Laurent, Thomas Demand and likely many more to be featured in future weeks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queer as Folklore | Gallery 46</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/queer-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/queer-46/</guid>
      <description>As the trendy Carhartt-clad east London dad put it to his iPhone-toting child: “This is all old folky art, sort of British traditionalist.” We were all walking round the new show at Gallery 46, a deliberately ramshackle space, carved out of a couple of Georgian terraced houses, under the shadow of the big blue modern Royal London hospital in Whitechapel.
The exhibition enveloped us in a deliberately fey world of mummers and satyrs, woodlands and flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam McKinniss: Country Western | Almine Rech</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mckinniss-rech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mckinniss-rech/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to think of a more universally loved celebrity than Dolly Parton. Not an original observation - there was a whole podcast about it a year or so back. Adulation for the country superstar has hit new heights, as if it were possible, over recent months when it emerged she’d helped fund the Moderna vaccine.
The job of the artist is to mess with the narrative. So when the very talented and original painter Sam McKinniss picked up on this latest wave of adulation, he felt… fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Demand | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>I loved Canopy, the photograph below, on show in the main gallery room at Sprüth Magers at the moment. It’s a sunny scene of some powdery blue apartment block, with a single, lemon sorbet-coloured canopy over-extended over one of the blocky white balconies. Given the work’s from 2020, the artist must have been thinking of our lockdown when he made it. The silent shadowy interiors signal the confinement of unseen occupants; I remember that for some city-dwellers, in the early days of the crisis, balconies were the only &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; outside space available to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanya Kantarovsky &amp; Camille Blatrix: Will-o’-the-wisp | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-blatrix-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-blatrix-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’ve loved Sanya Kantarovsky’s snarky, morbid and scatological paintings since I first encountered them, in his 2018 solo show at Kunsthalle Basel. So I was really excited to see this London show of his woodblock prints, set in frames from French painter/sculptor Camille Blatrix.
The thing that struck me about Kantarovsky’s work, then and now, is the balance between the serious and the silly. These prints have hideous subject matter - in one, a robed, bloodied figure kneels by the surf; in another, a child and his mother are molested by a bony hand - but are cartoonishly-drawn, in zanily bright colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychomachia | The Old Bank Vault</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/laurent-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/laurent-vault/</guid>
      <description>After four months of long lockdown, London’s commercial galleries reopened this week. The city’s bathed in spring sunshine, the streets are (comparatively) bustling, and it’s time to blow the dust and cobwebs off this website and get going again!
I guess you could call it a staged reopening: not being able to face a busy tube and Mayfair, I chose my first show back to be at a gallery within cycling distance of my flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Tallentire - As Happens | Hollybush Gardens</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tallentire-hollybush/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tallentire-hollybush/</guid>
      <description>The works in this small exhibition are grouped around the idea of scale - measurements. In the main room, Anne Tallentire shows us Area, wall-mounted, flat-coloured MDF panels corresponding to the dimensions, rather than the appearance, of objects in the communal area of a public housing complex in Graz: the work was first shown in that city in 2018.
Originally shown, in other words, before the pandemic which has made us measure things in new ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meleko Mokgosi - Democratic Intuition | Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mokgosi-gagosian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mokgosi-gagosian/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the amount of security guards at Gagosian galleries a bit over the top. And even more so this visit, with London fresh out of lockdown and the city’s residents more likely to catch up on their Christmas shopping than catch up on new exhibitions on a Saturday afternoon. That, coupled with the fact the gallery’s gone appointment-only, meant that I had this show all to myself. Well, more accurately, I shared each room of Gagosian’s massive space on Britannia Street with a black mask-and-suit clad guard - and nobody else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Michel Verjux at Laure Genillard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/verjux-genillard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/verjux-genillard/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to do. I had some leave from work to use, and used it this week, while galleries (and so many other places) remain locked down here in London. So the days have seemed blank, featureless.
I think of a plain circle of electric light, cast by a ceiling-mounted electric lamp. It’s a work by Michel Verjux, downstairs at Laure Genillard, which I viewed at an exhibition of his early last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Wearing - Lockdown | Maureen Paley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wearing-paley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wearing-paley/</guid>
      <description>This year, many of us have been given the opportunity to spend a lot more time in peaceful self-contemplation at home. Which has absolutely sucked. The artist Gillian Wearing has produced many self portraits in lockdown. Some oil on canvas, some watercolour, and all with a striking atmosphere of quiet, watchful despair.
In each of the fourteen self portraits on show at Maureen Paley, plus one I saw at the the Royal Academy, Wearing’s painted image seems to be waiting for something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gary Hume: Archipelago | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hume-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hume-magers/</guid>
      <description>When I think of Gary Hume’s work, it’s a particular texture that comes to mind first. Glossy paint on ultra-flat aluminium, standing up in ridges. Frameless, the only sign of the human touch is the occasionally streaked paint running down the sides of the metal block. Then comes the feeling I get when I look at these paintings: serenity.
Archipelago, Hume’s latest exhibition at Sprüth Magers, brings that serene approach to some troubling source material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mimmo Rotella Beyond Décollage | Cardi Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rotella-cardi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rotella-cardi/</guid>
      <description>While Andy Warhol’s mega-show plays across the river at Tate, a much less-heralded friend from Italy has taken up residence in a quiet street in Mayfair. Just like Warhol, Mimmo Rotella was obsessed by the mechanistic over the manual. But instead of making glitzy silk screen prints of pop icons, Rotella responded to the post-War boom with a grungy alternative: the décollage.
In the 1950s, Rotella launched his artistic career by roaming the streets of Rome and tearing advertising posters from the walls, which he then distressed further at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coco Capitán: Naïvy | Maximillian William</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/capitan-william/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/capitan-william/</guid>
      <description>This young artist, who also pays the bills as a fashion photographer, is very obviously going places. Still a couple of years shy of 30, she has a rock-solid aesthetic across photos, paintings, (hand) writing and found objects, which are all on show at Maximillian William right now.
The exhibition is based around a garment that could be militaristic, cute or camp: a sailor suit. The actual suit is draped over a schoolroom-style wooden chair, its hood carefully appliquéd with white-stitched daisies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Cézanne - Drawings - Tess Jaray - Roundels | Karsten Schubert</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cezanne-jaray-schubert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cezanne-jaray-schubert/</guid>
      <description>I spent a magical half hour here, in the weakening early autumn sunlight. The viewing room at Karsten Schubert, looking out onto Lexington Street in Soho from an upper floor of an 18th century former townhouse, hosts two utterly different sets of works: Jaray’s mathematical, precise, abstracted pairs of painted roundels, and intimate preparatory sketches and doodles from Cézanne.
It’s more interesting to me how each work relates to the space, rather than how the artists relate to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gisela McDaniel - Making WAY/FARING Well | Pilar Corrias</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mcdaniel-corrias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mcdaniel-corrias/</guid>
      <description>Gisela McDaniel’s women tend to wear proud smiles, adopt open and relaxed postures, and stare directly out at the viewer. They’re generally in company, too, sitting and relaxing in pairs and threes. They sit in lush landscapes, surrounded by tropical foliage.
Six of this artist’s paintings are currently on show at Pilar Corrias. The oil paint is embroidered by found objects - beads and fabrics, generally - strategically stuck onto the canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junque | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</guid>
      <description>The first time I saw US-based Jamian Juliano-Villani’s work was at Massimo de Carlo last year. I wrote about this show’s prime attraction: a cuddly tiger getting rigorously orally penetrated with a plastic-clad dildo. The fun continues in the same gallery this summer, in a group show organised around “junk”.
That’s junk in both the literal and slang senses of the word: either worthless clutter, or, like… a penis. It doesn’t really matter which way you take it (hmmm), Juliano Villani’s slapdash, don’t-care aesthetic isn’t proscriptive in the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atelier Picasso | Bastian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/picasso-bastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/picasso-bastian/</guid>
      <description>Pablo Picasso moved to the south of France after the second world war, and pitched up in Cannes in 1955, living in splendour at La Californie, a sumptuous mansion in the hills above town. He remained in the area until his death in 1973. This period is the focus of a new show at Bastian - one of the few open in London at this time of year.
As productive as ever, Picasso painted, sculpted, drew and cast thousands of ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sophie Cundale: The Near Room | South London Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cundale-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cundale-south/</guid>
      <description>Sophie Cundale’s third major film is both visually striking and deeply ropey. South London Gallery, where this is showing again after a COVID-induced cutoff during the spring, kindly terms it a “melodrama”. It’s a story of a boxer, knocked out in one of his fights, hallucinating his way into the medieval court of a mad queen, her wicked advisor and a couple of wacky nuns. The story of disease and betrayal that unfolds over half an hour or so is bloody and silly - or, to put it another way, bloody silly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yinka Shonibare: Justice for All | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/shonibare-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/shonibare-friedman/</guid>
      <description>Lady justice, sword in one hand, scales in the other, gestures at us on Old Burlington Street, behind the glass windows of the gallery. It’s a show designed to be looked at from outside: unreachable, but unmissable.
It’s Stephen Friedman Gallery and Yinka Shonibare’s response to the Black Lives Matter movement that’s roiled the global discourse this summer. The outdoor viewing is induced by the year’s other big global event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Warhol | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been waiting to see this show for ages, given Tate&amp;rsquo;s pandemic-induced shutdown just after its opening. This vast, career-spanning retrospective has been extended now until November. Following all that anticipation, it was a sad experience to visit Tate Modern post-lockdown. I could deal with the need to pre-book, the long queues and the mask wearing - all good by me. But the long queues and implied one-way system made me feel like I needed to keep moving forwards, and not linger on this or that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Bunga - Something Necessary and Useful | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bunga-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bunga-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>For a small sect that has never had a global membership higher than a few thousand souls, the Shakers have had an outsize cultural impact. With their dedication to beautifully modest and minimal design, their aesthetic influence has echoed down the centuries, from Modernist cereal-box architecture, to wood-n-whitewash worshipping magazines like Kinfolk.
Shakerism influences the work of Carlos Bunga, a Portuguese-born, US-based artist. He’s taken inspiration not just in Shaker aesthetics in this one-room show, currently on at Whitechapel Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike Silva: London Portraits, Interiors and Still Lives | The Approach</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/silva-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/silva-approach/</guid>
      <description>Something about Mike Silva’s paintings make me feel - “that’s London”. I promise I would have said the same even if this show had been called anything else. I’ll try to explain why.
Kitchen Window, pictured below, is representative of Silva’s scenes, which are worked up from photos he has taken over the years, many from his old flatsharing days. There’s something about the brownish light, filtering in from the impractical curtain covering, wanly suspended from a plastic tube across the window, giving a little privacy from the neighbours across the way, that makes me think: we&amp;rsquo;re in London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rineka Dijkstra | Marian Goodman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dijkstra-goodman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dijkstra-goodman/</guid>
      <description>This portrait photographer shoots well-off, good-looking young people. Her subjects tend to pose for the camera, natural and relaxed expressions on their unlined faces. Most of the photographs at Rineka Dijkstra’s current London show keep to this formula: there’s a series of sibling portraits, brothers and sisters pictured at home. These homes are generally well-appointed, even fancy.
But the photo below shakes up the formula a bit, and stands out. It was taken in Sefton Park in Liverpool, part of Dijkstra’s Park Portraits series, which includes works from between 2003 and 2006.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derek Jarman: My garden’s boundaries are the horizon | Garden Museum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/jarman-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/jarman-garden/</guid>
      <description>London’s Garden Museum is a lovely, peaceful enclave on the Southwark riverfront, adjoining Lambeth Palace. A nice contrast to the subject of its latest exhibition, who’s one of the very angriest artists of the last few decades: Derek Jarman.
Alongside his work as a filmmaker and painter, specialising in naked guys speaking Latin and cludgy black canvases studded with broken glass respectively, Jarman cultivated a famous garden. For the last five years of his life, he lived at Prospect Cottage, close to the nuclear power station in Dungeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rinus Van de Velde - Ashtrays | König</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/velde-koenig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/velde-koenig/</guid>
      <description>Here in the UK, smoking’s been banned in many public places for well over a decade. Which means that smoking-related objects, like the humble ashtray, are passing into obscurity. The kids are vaping these days.
As a result, I wouldn’t have necessarily recognised Rinus Van de Velde’s cute yet disturbing sculptures as being ashtrays, had it not been for the title of this show. But there they are: round, shallow dishes, with notches around the rim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hell Gette - (##) | Annka Kultys Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gette-kultys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gette-kultys/</guid>
      <description>The first emojis were created in 1999 by Japanese designer Shigetaka Kurita for a local telecoms company. Over the two decades since, they’ve mounted a stealth takeover of the world’s written conversation, and along the way, found their way into the permanent collection at MoMA. Some more emoji art can currently be found up a staircase off the Hackney Road, with a small exhibition of paintings from Kazakhstan-born German artist, Hell Gette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Stoner - Al-Andalus | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>At last, at last, many of London’s commercial galleries have reopened. As the country emerges from its lockdown, for better or worse, things aren’t quite back to normal. A spontaneous tour through open galleries isn’t going to be possible for a while: all of my visits have been by appointment. This extra element of necessary planning isn’t a bad thing though - it makes you more considered about what you want to see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Lubaina Himid at Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</guid>
      <description>“Nobody paints our love stories, our ordinary everyday,” the British artist Lubaina Himid told an interviewer once. “How our ordinary everyday is touched by enormous trauma and tragedy but we as a whole set of women globally and historically have the capacity to keep going.”
Let’s look at Ankledeep, a Himid painting from 1991 that’s part of the Tate collection, and was on show in an artist’s room at Tate Britain right up until the virus hit, and the doors closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Thomas Jones at the National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/jones-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/jones-national/</guid>
      <description>This fascinating and tiny painting, 16cm across and 10cm high, was usually one of my stops when I dropped in to the National Gallery. I must have visited the gallery hundreds of times over the years, and therefore must have seen this painting dozens of times, back when I had the option of doing so.
The title is admirably descriptive: Jones paints, in oils on paper, a worn out wall, lit by strong sunshine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Léon Spilliaert | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>What a shame this show, like all the others in London, is now closed. If there ever was an artist who exemplified social distancing, it’s Léon Spilliaert. And, having not spoken in person to anybody for coming up to two weeks now, I can’t tell anyone about how much I loved his paintings. I already regret just taking a quick spin around the three rooms in the upper galleries of the Royal Academy when I visited the exhibition, blithely assuming that I’d be back soon enough for a proper look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massimo Bartolini - Credits | Frith Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bartolini-frith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bartolini-frith/</guid>
      <description>It seems like a long time ago, now: a world where taking a trip to Italy was an indulgence, rather than an impossibility. I used some of my two days in Turin, back in late 2017, to visit the Fondazione Merz, a converted Lancia factory in a pretty suburb. Sitting on its concrete floor as the September sun slanted through its high windows, the space rebounded with metallic clanks, whizzes and hisses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louise Bonnet - New Works | Max Hetzler</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bonnet-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bonnet-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition, the debut UK show from Louise Bonnet, packs quite a punch. Large canvases show swollen female figures, wildly disproportionate. With their pointy boobs, big fat bums, tiny heads and odd-sized feet, they’re all uncomfortable, striking contorted poses, often constrained by ropes, shrouds and veils.
The oil paints are smoothly applied to these women, giving a vaguely inflatable, inorganic sheen to their skin. Not for Bonnet the textures and discolourations of Lucian Freud or Eric Fischl, those modern masters of the epidermis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dorothea Tanning - Worlds in Collision | Alison Jacques</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</guid>
      <description>This American artist, who lived past 100, has a hefty reputation as a Surrealist icon of the 20th century. Over her long career, Dorothea Tanning was famous for her crafty paintings and stuffed-toy-like sculptures. Accompanied by her husband Max Ernst, she lived in an Arizona desert town and then in Paris. That’s certainly the life on show in her Tate Modern retrospective, which I enjoyed and returned to repeatedly during its run early last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sigmar Polke - Objects Real and Imagined | Michael Werner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/polke-werner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/polke-werner/</guid>
      <description>Sigmar Polke said, once: “Why doesn’t the public turn its attention to the potato, where ultimate fulfilment awaits?” This colossus of post war art practiced what he preached, making a variety of potato-based artworks against the bleak backdrop of post-war Germany. One of which, the 1960s Kartoffelhaus (or “potato house”) is currently, incongrugously, on show in one of London’s loveliest exhibition spaces, the winter garden at Michael Werner Gallery.
Polke’s turn to the potato came after he noticed a prize tuber in the cellar of his house one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Conner - BREAKAWAY | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/conner-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/conner-dane/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty rare opportunity to view work by the American polymath Bruce Conner in London. Conner, who died in 2008, was a painter, sculptor and video artist who worked over a massive range of media.
This time, the focus is on his mid-60s video art: on show at Thomas Dane is Breakaway, from 1966, which he shot with popstar and choreographer Toni Basil, whose similarly long career improbably peaked a decade and a half later with the stone cold novelty classic Hey Mickey!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve McQueen - Year 3 | Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mcqueen-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mcqueen-tate/</guid>
      <description>Steve McQueen was made a knight in the 2020 honours list, and this is just the kind of public-spirited artwork suitable for such a high national honour. (Though I can’t help thinking LS Lowry’s approach of turning down such Royal-approved baubles, all the way up to refusing the Companion of Honour twice, is a much cooler artistic statement.)
For this exhibition, specially-trained Tate teams have photographed a total of 76,000 of London’s Year 3 schoolchildren and teachers in the traditional class photo format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candida Höfer - Showing and Seeing | Ben Brown Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hofer-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hofer-brown/</guid>
      <description>Like her Düsseldorf school colleague Andreas Gursky, who I’ve written about on here before, Candida Höfer specialises in large-format photographs of big, man-made spaces. But Höfer’s subject matter has a tighter focus: very fancy, richly-coloured, and almost entirely depopulated, interiors.
The nine photographs on show right now at Ben Brown Fine Arts stick rigidly to her precisely-defined parameters (Höfer has been photographing interiors since 1979). Her empty spaces are built to host crowds of strangers: libraries, in Austria, France and Mexico; and theatres, in Russia and Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ged Quinn | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</guid>
      <description>The British pastoral painter Ged Quinn’s style has been described by one critic as “malevolent&amp;hellip; sinister ”. It’s easy to see why, considering his subject matter. Quinn favours dark Romantic forests, silent pine-strewn paths and peaty skies. But in this new exhibition, Quinn showcases a sweeter edge.
Consider the fluffy linden tree that dominates Bloodstream Sub Tilia (on the right of the picture below). Folk mythology suggests that inhaling its pollen leads to nothing so sinister as… pleasant dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nan Goldin - Sirens | Marian Goodman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/goldin-goodman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/goldin-goodman/</guid>
      <description>This is Nan Goldin’s first London solo show in almost 20 years, and it’s really drawing the crowds. The exhibition begins with one of the US photographer’s trademark digital slideshows, The Other Side, a compilation of 25 years of candid snaps of her friends on society’s margins. The next room features some of the stills from which she sourced the slideshow.
Her subjects, showgirls, drag queens and groupies, have plaquey teeth, smoke a lot of cigarettes and are photogenically skinny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immaterial - Fontana Ceramics | Robilant &#43; Voena</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fontana-robilant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fontana-robilant/</guid>
      <description>I had a cringeworthy encounter with an in-house camera crew when I visited the HangerBicocca in Milan a few years ago. On stepping into the enormous space, I was confronted with one of mid-century maestro Lucio Fontana’s neon Ambienti, hanging, glowing blue, from the ceiling. What do you think of Fontana, the crew asked me, on the lookout for some promo content. I nervously mumbled something about not seeing him often in London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L’Empreinte | Olivier Malingue</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/empreinte-malingue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/empreinte-malingue/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to theme an exhibition around a concept. If the concept’s too broad, the effect is absurd; too specific, and it could just be hair-splittingly academic and boring. But this very smartly-conceived and executed show finds the sweet spot, featuring works which all feature some form of imprint. A concept sufficiently rich in suggestion, and encompassing a sufficiently broad variety of artistic expression, to make this exhibition really special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfredo Jaar: 25 Years Later | Goodman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/jaar-goodman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/jaar-goodman/</guid>
      <description>An example, for this viewer at least, of unintended consequences between an artwork’s intention and its effect. Alfredo Jaar’s exhibition is a sober document of one of the most horrific events of the last century: the sectarian violence that swept Rwanda in 1994, leaving over a million dead. Thes events unfolded, he argues, without the blanket coverage from an outraged global media they warranted.
To illustrate his point, he’s lined up a row of front covers for Newsweek, which 25 years ago was one of the most-read news weeklies in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Spaces | 180 Strand</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>The last exhibition I went to in this place, a Brutalist former office building next to King’s College, featured an ankle-aching 20+ video artists in a programme curated by the New Museum.
This time, the edit is a lot tighter, helped as ever by 180 Strand’s creative partners The Vinyl Factory, with assistance from Paris’ Fondation Cartier. Just three immersive works are on show.
My favourite was Vanishing Point, pictured above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAWS: BLACKOUT | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’d rocked up to Skarstedt to be confronted by an unfamiliar scene: a queue! In the crowd and confusion, I somehow made it inside despite not having an Eventbrite ticket. A ticketed show in a commercial gallery? It must be KAWS - the hugely hyped multimedia phenomenon, whose work’s everywhere from the MTV awards ‘Moonman’ statue to a line of clothes from Uniqlo.
Elbowing my way through the crowds - who mostly seemed really into the paintings and sculptures on display - I could see the extreme, almost computer-generated flatness of KAWS’s acrylic colours: no drippy paint drops on the sides of his frameless canvases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francesco Arena - Cubic Metre of Seawater as a Diagonal | Sprovieri</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</guid>
      <description>Two shows from Italian artists caught my eye this week. First, this exhibition from Franceso Arena at one of the west end’s least accessible galleries, up a flight of stairs behind Regent Street. Arena makes vaguely arte povera-aligned works, using natural and found materials.
The centrepiece of this show is rather grandiose: exactly as the title suggests, seawater is contained in a metal trough, 13 metres long, oriented diagonally across the largest gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cynthia Talmadge - Four Courtroom Outfits of Anna Delvey | Soft Opening</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/talmadge-soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/talmadge-soft/</guid>
      <description>I read the original New York Magazine exposé of Anna Delvey, the mysteriously-accented genius grifter, in bed one Saturday morning, phone a couple of inches from my riveted eyes, too fascinated to even reach over to my bedside table for my glasses.
While that was fun for a morning read, plus a few days of Twitter hilarity, I have to say I’m surprised that Delvey’s impact on the culture means she’s now the subject of a London exhibition viewed by thousands of people a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elena Tejada-Herrera - Queen Kong, The Girls Learn to Fight | Frieze London</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tejada-frieze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tejada-frieze/</guid>
      <description>I might as well hand in my London art reviewer badge by saying so, but this year was my first Frieze. That giant white tent in Regent’s Park was even more huge and overwhelming than I thought it’d be; I staggered out after just under four hours, feet and shoulders aching, tote overloaded with magazines, press releases and lists of works.
The easiest thing to do in a review with such a variety of potential subjects is to pick out a show that I particularly liked from a non-obvious source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Exhibition - Simon Hantaï, Pierre Soulages and Antoni Tàpies | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</guid>
      <description>International gallery Timothy Taylor has a new home on the other side of Berkeley Square as its old one, and has put on an interesting exhibition to mark the occasion. The show brings together three artists who found fame at a similar time - the years following the last world war - but via quite different methods.
Pierre Soulages applied thick black paint - layers and layers of it - to his large canvases, while Antoni Tàpies went even heavier, with his bulky sculptures in bronze and fired clay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony Gormley | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gormley-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gormley-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>This is a very comprehensive show, featuring lots of Gormley’s notebooks and sketchbooks, and ranging from the early Land Art-inspired work, to new experiments. Such the final room, which I visited at night, feeling the dark chill of the entire gallery space submerged in clay-ey water.
Elsewhere, there are endless variations on Gormley’s trademark rusty metal and steel. Such as the exhibition’s centrepiece: Matrix III, constructed especially for the show. A couple lay dreamily on the hard wooden floor, gazing up at the grid patterns, densely arranged around a central void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takis | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/takis-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/takis-tate/</guid>
      <description>Despite the multi-decade career - he died just after this Tate Modern show opened - the “kinetic” artist Takis is bound into the 1960s, specifically the decade’s go-ahead technological positivity. His art, kindled by the possibilities of electromagnetism and machinery, shows an excitement and wonder similar to that of the IBM pavilion at the 1965 World’s Fair, or Vasarely’s strobing patterns.
That’s not to suggest this exhibition is any fun though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clare Woods - Doublethink | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>This artist’s practice has similar roots to other artists I’ve featured on this site before. Like Robert Muntean, Clare Woods takes found images from newspapers and magazines and makes something new with them.
Like her compatriot Gary Hume, she paints on aluminium, giving the final works an ultra-clean, shiny, textured look. Like Rachel Howard , she paints from above, letting the drips fall down the edges of the works.
But Woods’ overall effects are unique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bartolomé Bermejo - Master of the Spanish Renaissance | National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>Walking around this impressive one-room exhibition , I was reminded of another artist on show in the National Gallery’s permanent collection, down the corridor. Because Bartolomé Bermejo, like the better-known Antonello da Messina, was a painter of the south that was as influenced by the Northern Renaissance as what was going on in Italy at the time.
There’s an echo of van Eyck and van der Weyden in these artists: their jewel-like clarity; the comparative disinterest in anatomical correctness and the new rules of perspective; the love lavished on different surfaces and materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cindy Sherman | National Portrait Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sherman-npg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sherman-npg/</guid>
      <description>This is a retrospective in the truest sense, ranging from the American master photographer’s first ever book, produced at the age of nine, to some of the most recent uber-glossy, expensively-produced photos of the artist as a range of grandes dames. (She showed a few of them at a highly enjoyable show at Sprüth Magers last year.)
It’s not possible not to read meanings into the childhood Cindy Book, which features family snaps, each with the artist herself carefully circled, and a single phrase: “that’s me”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nunzio - The Shock of Objectivity | Mazzoleni</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nunzio-mazzoleni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nunzio-mazzoleni/</guid>
      <description>I found this show spectacular but a bit inscrutable. It’s summed up - though maybe not in the way the curator, Kenneth Baker, intended - by the artist’s own quote from the show notes: “When you are confronted with the work of art, either you feel that it is it, or it leaves you soulless.”
On entering the Mazzoleni gallery, behind one of Mayfair’s less functional doorbells and beyond one of its less populated front desks, I was confronted by the spectacular in search of a soul: Avvoltoio, meaning ‘vulture’, a new work, free-standing and grand, made out of burnt wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Order - Art, Product, Image 1976-1995 | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wearing-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wearing-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>The place is quite familiar, rendered strange over the decades. We’re in a shopping centre in Peckham in 1994. Everyone’s dressed in baggy 90s style. If anyone’s carrying a shopping bag, it’s plastic. This being several decades before that multi-story car park down the road got its pink coat of paint and craft beer outlets, the crowd is solidly ungentrified. And nobody has a mobile phone, so nobody’s filming the very unusual scene - except one camera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Head is a Haunted House | Sadie Coles HQ</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/haunted-sadie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/haunted-sadie/</guid>
      <description>It’s not quite Hallowe’en, but there are plenty of anticipation-building creepy thrills to be had at this show , curated by writer, curator and horror movie obsessive Charlie Fox.
Everywhere you look, there’s work blurring the lines between scary, funny and… a bit deviant. From Sam McKinnis’ reverent paintings of Buffy the Vampire Slayer, to a pink laser show from Matt Copson, to some truly disgusting - even by his standards - Larry Clark photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Iranian Artists in London - THE SPARK IS YOU | Parasol Unit</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/iranian-parasol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/iranian-parasol/</guid>
      <description>In the dog days of summer, there’s not so much to see in London’s art scene. But for those of us who prefer chilly air conditioned white cubes to lying in the sun, there are some real treats to be had. Among them is in an upstairs gallery in one of the chilliest cubes of all, the formidably air conditioned Parasol Unit in Islington.
This show is featuring a group of Iranian artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xie Nanxing - A Gift Like Kung Pao Chicken | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nanxing-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nanxing-dane/</guid>
      <description>This show wasn’t exactly appealing to me as I can’t stand the volcanically spicy Sichuan dish it’s named after, but Xie Nanxing soon put my prejudices (and stomach) to rest. The reason for the name is the bright colours of kung pao chicken, and accordingly the walls of Thomas Dane are painted in greens and pinks.
The similarities to the chicken dish end there. Xie’s painting technique is known as ‘canvas print’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Drawing - José Antonio Suárez Londoño | Ordovas</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/londono-ordovas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/londono-ordovas/</guid>
      <description>This Colombian artist must be a gallerist’s dream: his tiny, ornate pen and ink drawings, arranged in this exhibition in attractive rows, are deeply pretty, crafty and uplifting. Each features a tiny stamp proving ownership, just for that little extra bit of covetability; the artist, cultivating the brand, likes to be known just as “JASL”.
There are 100 drawings in all, along with 50 etchings, covering most of the smallish gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamian Juliano-Villani - Let’s Kill Nicole | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</guid>
      <description>Slapdash, funny and deeply, deeply Instagrammable, New York-based Jamian Juliano-Villani has produced a sweet summer treat. Like a soft scoop ice cream special with hundreds and thousands, a flavoured cone AND a Flake, this show is an all out assault. And the generally lurid work is nicely offset by its host: one of London’s poshest and soberest private gallery spaces.
My favourite - introduced via Russell Tovey’s Instagram of all places - features a cuddly tiger getting savagely orally pumped by a mechanised dildo in a plastic bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barthélémy Toguo - Human Nature | HdM Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/toguo-hdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/toguo-hdm/</guid>
      <description>Barthélémy Toguo trained in Paris but works in Cameroon - and has a foundation there. He works and shows a lot in China too, hence why this gallery, which specialises in Chinese art, has put on this exhibition.
It’s quite a sight, with works on paper on the walls, and large porcelain pots strewing the floor. These imposing works - as a series they’re called Fragile Bodies - were made in China and decorated by local artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pécs Workshop | Mayor Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pecs-mayor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pecs-mayor/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition is truly lovely. To a restive, anxious London in summer comes a sweet breeze from the east, redolent of other long-distant distant summers. 50 years ago, behind the Iron Curtain, across an ideological divide, and out in the countryside, the Pécs Workshop met.
They were an avant-garde group of five artists in communist Hungary, who met each summer between 1969 and 1971 in Pécs, close to the Croatian… well, Yugoslavian, border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony Caro - Seven Decades | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>Despite the epic title, this one is a small, lovingly-curated show over two floors in a quiet upstairs gallery off Oxford Street. I particularly loved the bigger machine-like works on the upper floor.
They’re collectively a study in contrasts: the forms balanced between the rectilinear and the curvy; the material combining both reused parts and the purpose-built; the surfaces vary between the smooth and the pitted.
What about Sky Passage (T0179), a very recent, three metre high work from 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chihuly - Reflections on nature | Kew Gardens</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/chihuly-kew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/chihuly-kew/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing wrong with being a people pleaser. And Dale Chihuly’s one of them. Final proof, if proof were needed, of this view is provided by In the Light of Jerusalem, a film playing in the confines of the Shirley Sherwood gallery: the small indoor section of a big outdoor show devoted to Chihuly that spreads over a good portion of Kew’s 300 acres.
The film shows the artist, famous for his fantastical glassworks, in the throes of building one of his most famous outdoor sculptures: a wall of big ice blocks, stacked in front of the Citadel Tower, and under the hot Jerusalem sun, marking the turn of the millennium in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cy Twombly - Natural History | Bastian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/twombly-bastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/twombly-bastian/</guid>
      <description>I just can’t with him. I’ve tried. Cy Twombly on a large scale hasn’t worked. I’ve trudged through a (huge) retrospective at the Pompidou, trying to find something, anything, in his mannered scribbles, his big messy flowers, his enormous, aggressive, pompous drips. I’ve wheeled around the Lepanto series in its purpose-built room at the top of the Brandhorst Museum in Munich: appreciating the lovely colours and ultra-luxe surroundings, but just, somehow, failing to connect with what was on the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mario Sironi - Signs and Colours | Brun Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sironi-brun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sironi-brun/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition begins with a surprising painting, considering its painter: a smiling self-portrait. Surprising, as Mario Sironi’s reputation is based his unremittingly grim work, spanning the early 1920s to the 50s. This general bleakness, coupled with his enthusiastic embrace of the Mussolini regime pre-war, and his post-war withdrawal from the public sphere, has made him a pretty obscure name - especially in the UK, where this is the first Sironi show in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don McCullin | Tate &amp; Hamiltons</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</guid>
      <description>It’s those little flecks of light, reflected in the shiny metal of minecart tracks, criss-crossing the ground in front of a mine in County Durham, and depicted in sumptuous black and white, that drew me in. Standing astride these tracks is a well-dressed couple, looking back at their photographer with a mixture of wariness and pride.
Their (very famous) photographer, Don McCullin, is best known for his images of war - from Vietnam to Biafra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diane Arbus - In the beginning | Hayward Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arbus-hayward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arbus-hayward/</guid>
      <description>After the weirdly-curated Lee Bul show here last year, I was wondering what funny treatment the renovated Hayward Gallery would give this iconic photographer. But it’s very well put together, with the small black and white work arranged, seemingly randomly, against white posts in strict grid formation; based, apparently, on the New York streets on which Diane Arbus found some of her most memorable scenes.
The exhibition concentrates on the early career, being mainly made up of photos shot on 35mm between 1956 and 1962.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Salle - Musicality and Humour | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/salle-skarstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/salle-skarstedt/</guid>
      <description>What a lovely palete cleanser this exhibition is! David Salle’s cartoony collage paintings shift and swirl, mixing black-and-white and colour. In this new show, he focuses on repetitive depictions of mops, coffee cups, pork chops and other ephemeral, day-to-day objects. He peppers his canvases with slogans and word marks.
They’re generally repainted elements from 1940s cartoons and ad imagery. Salle himself has said he’s aiming for a kind of “free jazz” effect: a pleasant cacophony, with enough underlying structure to hold the attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom Hammick - Night Animals | Flowers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hammick-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hammick-flowers/</guid>
      <description>Spooky as a Sargent Nocturne, Tom Hammick’s oil paintings are here awash with blue, depicting campsites, cabins and ships. He’s deeply influenced by the Romantic movement, with the figure of the solitary striver explains why none of his figures seem to look at or talk to each other.
That’s not to say they’re entirely rejecting material culture: in Walden Pond, partygoers cluster around a shiny camper van. And there’s something lovely and regular about the sailboat that appears in many of the paintings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Anderson - Body Disruptions | Waddington Custot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/anderson-waddington/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/anderson-waddington/</guid>
      <description>Alice Anderson is known as a performance artist as well as a visual artist, but this show is definitely big on the visual wow factor. Dominating the larger gallery at Waddington Custot are a series of copper-wire-covered monoliths. Anderson calls them Body Disruptions, and they’re built by wrapping the wire around a rectilinear wooden structure so that it forms repetitive motifs and patterns.
As an artist, Anderson’s very interested in digital connectivity, and of course copper wire’s a transfer medium for online information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Günther Förg | Max Hetzler and Luxembourg &amp; Dayan</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/forg-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/forg-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>Günther Förg was a German painter with quite a forbidding aesthetic - grainy architectural photographs, often of buildings built for a Fascist government - and monochrome acrylic paintings on a lead backing. He’s also selling well, if the three commercial gallery shows of his work in London alone over the past few months are any guide.
Two of them are running at the moment, one at Max Hetzler and one at Luxembourg &amp;amp; Dayan, and offer a good guide to both types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calder/Miro - Clair de lune | Nahmad Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/calder-nahmad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/calder-nahmad/</guid>
      <description>Alexander Calder and Joan Miró were good friends, with a lot in common. The same goes for the work, too, and this dreamy little exhibition proves it. Working in Paris, both took the most crowd-pleasing bits of the Surrealist movement they were surrounded with, and expressed it in antic, zany, colourful form. Calder made mobiles, Miró paintings.
They’re both still really popular: the last couple of years having brought major retrospectives for Calder at the Whitney, and Miró at the Grand Palais.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living with Buildings - Health &amp; Architecture | Wellcome Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/buildings-wellcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/buildings-wellcome/</guid>
      <description>What an interesting series of free exhibitions at this totally unique institution on the Euston Road. This latest one is probably my favourite so far - even beating the show last year about teeth. It’s a rag-bag of architectural plans, paintings, maquettes, pages from books - all organised around the theme of buildings that promote health.
To give a couple of examples that stood out to me: a beautiful 70s plan of Milton Keynes (that was the future, once), a Pissarro landscape of Bedford Park in Chiswick - the first garden suburb of all, where the artist lived for a time - and Andreas Gursky’s Montparnasse tower block photo, that I first encountered at the Hayward last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bosco Sodi - Heavens and the Earth | Blain Southern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sodi-blain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sodi-blain/</guid>
      <description>There are two parts of this exhibition. First the heavens: big black and white paintings, made of ultra-thick paint, cracked in interesting ways, depicting mysterious swirls and bubbles. It’s as if you’re staring at a mountain range from the sky.
Then the earth, brick towers in Jenga-style patterns. They look about as stable as Jenga towers, too: the bricks wonky and uneven.
The bricks and the paint were both formed by chance as well as craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Muntean - Just Like Honey | Rosenfeld Porcini</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</guid>
      <description>Austria-born, Berlin-based painter Robert Muntean says he’s inspired by Richard Gerstl, and there’s definitely something of the Secession-era artist’s taste for the obliterative in his new paintings, which often depicts figures only in outline, slashed by colours, large stretches of canvas left raw. They’re on show at Rosenfeld Porcini in Fitzrovia at the moment.
I’m thinking of Gerstl’s portrait of the family of Arnold Schoenberg, painted while having an affair with the mother of the house, just before discovery, and the painter’s descent into madness and suicide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jörg Immendorff - Questions from a Painter Who Reads | Michael Werner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</guid>
      <description>This is an artist who was a really big deal in his native land. I first heard of Jörg Immendorff when I visited his enormous retrospective at the Haus der Kunst in Munich last year, spanning his early political paintings of to his complex, gloomy, finely-wrought late works, painted as the artist was dying of ALS. A hideous way to go - and he went in 2007.
Now, Michael Werner is showing a cycle of huge paintings from the final year in its lovely winter garden, with some other examples of another Immendorff period - his fervent and optimistic 70s paintings of heroic workers and artists, working together to trash capitalism in some impressive wing collars and flares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Leonard. Aerials | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Zoe Leonard is an American conceptual artist who took aerial photos of New York City over several years in the late 80s. Gelatin silver prints of these are on show as Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth right now, and when I went to see them, I basically wanted to buy them all, in an alternative fantasy universe where I actually have the funds to do that.
The artist’s eye gets caught on urban infrastructure; the densely gridded street pattern of the city; worn summer baseball fields, packed back to back and encroached on by houses from all sides; and, most lovingly shot of all, a gleaming rail interchange, the iron and wood of the parallel tracks caught by low light, rendered mysterious by the silver print’s blur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edward Burne-Jones | Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</guid>
      <description>I went into this large exhibition ready to write off Edward Burne-Jones as total kitsch. But he resists being dismissed. The show is full of annoying reminders of the artist&amp;rsquo;s great popularity - from the start - and the fact that he was an epic do-gooder. Rising to world fame from humble origins, unlike some of his fellow pre-Raphaelites, Burne-Jones went into business with Socialist paragon of virtue William Morris to produce mass-market wall-hangings, to go along with his paintings for rich patrons and collectors; he saw no distinction between fine and decorative art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2018</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a pretty big first year of art watching for this little side project.
In all, I saw 256 shows and collections in 2018 - not counting repeated visits to some old favourite permanent collections in London. Over that time, I featured a fifth of that total on the site, posting each week.
While I give my eyes a rest over the festive period, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up post, listing my top five of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmgreen &amp; Dragset - This Is How We Bite Our Tongue | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>Whitechapel Gallery has been transformed into a derelict swimming pool with an imaginary backstory. Built by a Victorian philanthropist (the story goes), the Whitechapel Pool played host to Tesco founder Jack Cohen and David Hockney over its decades as a public utility. Then it got shut down in the privatisation-happy Thatcher era, before being renovated as part of a “design hotel” opening in 2019. Unfortunately for future Cohens and Hockneys, it’ll be accessible only through membership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilse d’Hollander | Victoria Miro</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dhollander-victoriamiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dhollander-victoriamiro/</guid>
      <description>Ilse d’Hollander worked in Flanders, and had just one gallery show, in a local café, before her death in 1997. She painted alone, in a studio in the countryside. And now, she has a UK solo show, on at Victoria Miro right now.
You could call all of the paintings on show “landscapes” of one kind or another. Houses, trees, grass and sky are mainly legible, though sometimes unusually cropped and zoomed in - and therefore abstracted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Masters  | Hamilton&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</guid>
      <description>So often when looking at large-scale work, it&amp;rsquo;s a single detail that catches your eye. With Modern Masters, a group photographic show currently on at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s a young woman commuter in a light raincoat, glaring out from a train. She&amp;rsquo;s the emotional centre of Shinjuku Station, Tokyo, Japan, taken by photographer Hiro in 1962.
Across the breadth of this seven metre wide work, made up of seven gelatin silver prints, faces and hands of Tokyo commuters are pressed against the steamy glass of the subway car&amp;rsquo;s window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerry James Marshall - History of Painting  | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>Kerry James Marshall is uber-influential these days, with his works selling for seven figure sums - to P Diddy, no less. He&amp;rsquo;s also an incredible and sensitive portraitist. Sometimes beloved, successful work is great work, as his new exhibition at David Zwirner proves. But the show also has interesting things to say about the nature of that success.
This is an exhibition about the ways in which paintings can be made, and the contexts in which they are received.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan Henderikse - MINT | Cortesi</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/henderikse-cortesi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/henderikse-cortesi/</guid>
      <description>One man&amp;rsquo;s trash is another&amp;rsquo;s treasure. That&amp;rsquo;s a message taken on board by so many artists over the past century, with everyone from Duchamp to Jannis Kounellis to Michael Landy using everyday detritus in new ways. Jan Henderikse, currently showing at Cortesi, takes things to new, daffy heights.
Most of the works are framed, wall mounted, and neatly unified by theme. There are collections of coins, number plates, toilet soap, corks and plastic caps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavin Turk - White Van Man | Paul Stolper</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/turk-stolper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/turk-stolper/</guid>
      <description>I saw this exhibition, subtitled &amp;lsquo;A Brexit portfolio and other Transit Disasters&amp;rsquo; at a time when the thoroughly depressing Brexit negotiations were reaching something of a climax.
The central motif of the various silkscreen prints is a burnt out Ford Transit. Any British observer would recognise the cultural signifier of a white van - home to &amp;ldquo;White Van Man&amp;rdquo;, a highly Brexity demographic.
The prints themselves owe an obvious debt to Warhol&amp;rsquo;s gloomy 60s prints of car crashes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Débora Delmar - Corporate Facades | Soft Opening</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/delmar-soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/delmar-soft/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Londoner who writes regularly about exhibitions at commercial galleries. This means I spend a lot of my time, in lunch hours and at weekends, walking around the tangle of streets behind the Royal Academy, where designer clothes and jewellery shops and white cubes jostle for space.
Mexican artist Débora Delmar is also familiar with these Mayfair streets, as they&amp;rsquo;re the subject of this mini show in the mini gallery at Picadilly Circus underground station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun House | Josh Lilley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gaignard-lilley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gaignard-lilley/</guid>
      <description>This is definitely the first gallery exhibition I&amp;rsquo;ve been to that&amp;rsquo;s named after a 90s kid&amp;rsquo;s TV show. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t remember the essential after-school viewing for now-thirtysomethings &amp;lsquo;Fun House&amp;rsquo; with Pat Sharp, this video should help you out.) But there&amp;rsquo;s not much to tie that &amp;ldquo;messy technicolour treat for kids&amp;rdquo;, as the show notes have it, to this rather sober collection. It&amp;rsquo;s a group show, and the artist in it that most stood out for me is American photographer Genevieve Gaignard, who I&amp;rsquo;d spotted at a previous exhibition at Stephen Friedman, and read about in this (excellent) New Yorker profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paloma Varga Weisz - Wild Bunch | Sadie Coles HQ</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/weisz-sadie-coles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/weisz-sadie-coles/</guid>
      <description>Being a woodcarver in Bavaria seems an unlikely apprenticeship for a fine artist, but looking around this show, currently on at Sadie Coles, it all sort of makes sense. Paloma Varga Weisz started woodcarving in a tiny town in the mountains after being rejected from art school the first time round. After getting in at the second try, she began a more formal education in Düsseldorf, home of a crop of sober, straightforwardly honest artists and photographers of the late 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lee Bul - Crashing | Hayward Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bul-hayward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bul-hayward/</guid>
      <description>What a weird show this is! Following their stellar Gursky retrospective earlier in the year, and some bad juju prior to opening when one of the works caught fire, what remains is a majorly varied grab-bag of paintings, installations, costume, architectural maquettes, a light show and a big-ass zeppelin. It&amp;rsquo;s less of a sensory assault than a really expensive jumble sale.
The show definitely highlights that Lee Bul is epically productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my name is lettie eggsyrub | Gloucester Road</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/eggysrub-gloucester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/eggysrub-gloucester/</guid>
      <description>This endless hot summer hasn&amp;rsquo;t led to many art discoveries. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending too much time cowering under the blessed cool air of my desk fan: that £20 at John Lewis is the best money I&amp;rsquo;ve spent all decade. But one work that&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind a lot, thanks to my daily commute on the District Line, is &amp;lsquo;my name is lettie eggsyrub&amp;rsquo;, a silly yet also somehow haunting installation that runs the length of the unused platform at Gloucester Road tube station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land of Lads, Land of Lashes | Thaddeus Ropac</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/castoro-ropac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/castoro-ropac/</guid>
      <description>This group show in Thaddeus Ropac&amp;rsquo;s very grand London space centres on three women Minimalist artists who worked in the 1970s. The one who stood out to me was Rosemarie Castoro, whose work gave the show its title.
Land of Lads, Land of Lashes refers to two sculptures in the big room on the upper floor. They&amp;rsquo;re made of epoxy, a type of polymer. They&amp;rsquo;re coloured deep black. And they have vaguely organic, even anthropomorphic, form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beth Letain - Signal Hill | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/letain-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/letain-pace/</guid>
      <description>Beth Letain&amp;rsquo;s influences range from Giorgio Morandi to Agnes Martin, though her deliberately ultra-simple forms are more abstract than either, and with a far bolder use of colour. The colours of these big paintings, currently on show at PACE, are deep, bold and matte. Their surfaces, prepared by layers of homemade gesso, have a luxurious sheen.
My favourite was &amp;lsquo;Strong Winds&amp;rsquo;, its bold horizontality and almost hallucinatory depth was the most directly evocative of the exhibition&amp;rsquo;s title: &amp;lsquo;Signal Hill&amp;rsquo; is the hill from which the first morse code was received.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Sander - Men Without Masks | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sander-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sander-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Nazi Germany wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly an ideal environment for any artist, and that&amp;rsquo;s particularly true for an artist with a vision as profoundly kind, non-judgmental and humanistic as August Sander. His life&amp;rsquo;s work was a photographic project called &amp;ldquo;People of the 20th Century&amp;rdquo;, in which he chose as diverse a range of subjects as possible, and took their portraits.
This impressive show at Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth showcases examples from between 1910 and 1931, a year before Hitler&amp;rsquo;s (elected) rise to power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cindy Sherman | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sherman-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sherman-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Get away from me dear, I don&amp;rsquo;t need you anymore!&amp;rdquo; So said silent screen queen Norma Talmadge to a hopeful autograph seeker, just after she made it to the A-list. Well, according to Hollywood apochrypa anyway. The 20s movie grande dame is the latest visual inspiration from iconic shape-shifting photographer Cindy Sherman, whose new work in this show at Sprüth Magers is just as funny, off-kilter and subversive as ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mind&#39;s Eye - The Photographs of Derek Parfit | Narrative Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/parfit-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/parfit-narrative/</guid>
      <description>Derek Parfit travelled to Venice and St Petersburg on holiday each year for decades. He took many obsessively-composed, haunting photographs of the architecture there, always in low winter light. They&amp;rsquo;re the subject of this small but smart show, on right now at Narrative Projects. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pro photographer, though: his day job was&amp;hellip; philosophy.
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to think of a philosopher who left behind a visual archive, and it&amp;rsquo;s equally hard to decipher Parfit&amp;rsquo;s philosophical views from these moody, misty photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norbert Bisky - Anomie | König</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bisky-konig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bisky-konig/</guid>
      <description>Anomie is a social state of disintegration: where the norms imposed by religion and the state fall away, and all we are left with is our own, never-satisfied desires. It&amp;rsquo;s a word born from the turn of the 20th century and the first rumblings of modernism, popularised by French sociologist Émile Durkheim, who detected in his changing world a mismatch between personal ideals and social standards. Which, naturally, led to unfulfilled desires - and depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermann Nitsch - Das Orgien Mysterien Theater | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/itsch-de-carlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/itsch-de-carlo/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t realise how Catholic a country Austria is until I arrived in the centre of Vienna on All Saint’s Day last year and couldn’t find a single supermarket open. Wandering past wedding-cake Baroque churches, with their over-ornate interiors, I finally found a tiny Turkish corner shop – packed, of course. Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s a memory triggered by wandering around a very different type of Austrian Catholic dysfunction, currently on show at Massimo de Carlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witness | Pilar Corrias</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/chen-pilar-corrias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/chen-pilar-corrias/</guid>
      <description>China&amp;rsquo;s home to one in four people, and many of the world&amp;rsquo;s fastest growing cities. Four different Chinese artists&amp;rsquo; responses to the city are currently on show at Pilar Corrias.
Chen Wei, now resident in Beijing, stood out to me. One lovely photo in particular, New Buildings, (2016), a rainy window, dappled with condensation, lit up with multiple colours, suggesting windows and signage in a street behind.
This weirdly wistful image is a bit of a trick, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morten Skrøder Lund - ome | Belmacz</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/skroder-lund-belmacz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/skroder-lund-belmacz/</guid>
      <description>Philip Larkin, in a rare fit of lyricism, wrote a lovely poem called &amp;lsquo;The Trees&amp;rsquo;. The trees are bursting into leaf / Like something almost being said, it begins. His words come to my mind a lot at this time of year: when winter turns to spring, the weather warms and moistens, the future beckons.
It&amp;rsquo;s also mentioned in the accompanying notes to this small show, written by art historian Ben Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Serra – Rifts | Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/serra-gagosian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/serra-gagosian/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a funny bit in the recent New Yorker hatchet job on Thomas Heatherwick, covering the design superstar&amp;rsquo;s mission to build a centrepiece for the renovation of Hudson Yards, New York City. Richard Serra was also asked to contribute too, but said no. “You know what I do — you know that it’s going to be structural steel, you know it’s going to be monumental. What do I need to show you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso 1932 – Love, Fame, Tragedy | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</guid>
      <description>Even though I went in a churlish mood, on a relentlessly rainy Saturday, surrounded by wheelie-suitcase wielding crowds, I can&amp;rsquo;t pretend that this show is anything else than a megawatt, full-bore, ocean-going triumph. Picasso in 1932 was 50, world-famous, trapped in a love triangle and, according to the evidence currently on the walls at Tate Modern, at the apex of his inventive powers.
This blitz of beauty and innovation, from one of the 20th century&amp;rsquo;s foundational geniuses, overwhelmed my critical faculties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source and Stimulus | Lévy Gorvy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/laing-levy-gorvy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/laing-levy-gorvy/</guid>
      <description>This pocket blockbuster of an exhibition is devoted to the &amp;lsquo;Ben-day dot&amp;rsquo;: those little dots on printed paper that make up images, if you look closely enough. Visible printed dots making up images on low-grade paper are, of course, a relic of the 20th century.
The advent of Pop Art in the 1960s was all about artists getting into commercial culture, and its mass-produced physical relics. This meant, for Sigmar Polke, Roy Lichtenstein and Gerald Laing, painstakingly painting reproductions of Ben-day dots to render iconic reproductions of pictures they saw in magazines, ads and pulp fiction books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fred Wilson: Afro Kismet | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wilson-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wilson-pace/</guid>
      <description>There is an awful lot to see in the big main gallery at PACE, all of which is work from Wilson&amp;rsquo;s showing at last year&amp;rsquo;s Istanbul Biennial. As the name, &amp;lsquo;Afro Kismet&amp;rsquo;, suggests, the influences come both from the Middle East and Africa.
The wow factor comes from the centre of the room, dominated by two walls clad in Isnik tiles, and two large Murano glass, black chandeliers. Both gaudy and excessive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Had the Landscape in My Arms | Josh Lilley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pichlkostner-josh-lilley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pichlkostner-josh-lilley/</guid>
      <description>What an impressive last few months at Josh Lilley! Tucked away on a quiet corner in Fitzrovia, just next to the old Middlesex Hospital site - and its bonkers neo-Byzantine chapel, that I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to write a whole separate post about - this little gallery is on a tear.
Late last year came a knockout show from Philadelphia-based Alex Da Corte. And now, it&amp;rsquo;s a group show of sculpture, using mainly found objects, with the descriptive title &amp;lsquo;I Had the Landscape in My Arms&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michelangelo Pistoletto - Scaffali | Simon Lee Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pistoletto-simon-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pistoletto-simon-lee/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s OK to be a one-trick pony, if the trick&amp;rsquo;s good enough. Michelangelo Pistoletto is associated with the arte povera movement of Italy in the 1960s, and is famous for his &amp;lsquo;mirror paintings&amp;rsquo;, large wall-mounted mirrors with painted or printed images on them. The first mirror painting dates from the early 60s. And Pistoletto is still at it, judging by this show, currently at Simon Lee Gallery.
The dimensions of the mirrors haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much over the decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Howard, Repetition is Truth - Via Dolorosa | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/howard-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/howard-newport/</guid>
      <description>When making this series of works, based on the 14 stations of the cross, the artist first allowed gloss paint to separate. Then, she poured the pigment onto large canvases from above. Then, she added the laminate to the canvas. This has led to the works&amp;rsquo; shiny surface of vertical stripes and drips. Their reflectiveness make them hard to photograph, if not to look at. The series is on show currently at the Newport Street Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andreas Gursky | Hayward Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gursky-hayward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gursky-hayward/</guid>
      <description>An early high point in Andreas Gursky&amp;rsquo;s wonderful show, currently on at the Hayward Gallery, is a photo called &amp;lsquo;Schiphol&amp;rsquo;.
This early-ish (1994) work, looking out onto the runways of the titular airport, was taken at a time of transition for the artist. Gursky was increasingly turning to digital photography, and to the &amp;ldquo;aggregate states&amp;rdquo; for which he&amp;rsquo;s most famous today: complex, heavily retouched depictions of late capitalist workplaces, landscapes and cityscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enchanted Room | Estorick Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sironi-estorick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sironi-estorick/</guid>
      <description>Mario Sironi was a poet of the grimy and growing suburbs of Milan. In the inter-war years, he made a series of small, thickly worked &amp;lsquo;Urban Landscapes&amp;rsquo;, close-cropped, bleak city scenes of factories, smokestacks and apartment blocks.
There are two really fine examples in the Estorick&amp;rsquo;s latest show, subtitled &amp;lsquo;Modern Works from the Pinacoteca di Brera&amp;rsquo;. This is the first time many of these paintings and sculptures, donated by collectors Emilio and Maria Jesi, have been shown outside of Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Von Calhau! MANCHA NEGRA VOLTA A ATACAR | Kunstraum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/von-calhau-kunstraum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/von-calhau-kunstraum/</guid>
      <description>Von Calhau! is a collective project of two artists from Porto, who mainly work with sound and video. This show was inspired by a 1980s-era Lisbon graffiti tag: in English, &amp;ldquo;Black Blob Back to Attack&amp;rdquo;. The tag, in turn, was inspired by a Disney character, the Phantom Blot, one of Mickey Mouse&amp;rsquo;s many enemies. Anyway, that character, which originally appeared in a 1930s comic strip, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really resemble the strange black vinyl inflatable, literally a black blob, filling most of a dingy room off Old Street, pulsing slowly, its seams gaffa-taped and its ends stuck to vents in the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piero Dorazio, Chromatic Fantasies (1948-82) | Tornabuoni Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</guid>
      <description>Showing in the depths of an interminable winter, this blast of colour, at Tornabuoni until springtime, comes as a welcome relief &amp;ndash; even a joy.
Dorazio isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a heavy hitter in the pantheon of post war Italian painting. In fact, this is billed as his &amp;ldquo;first London show in a generation&amp;rdquo; (though he was a big part of a group show up the road at Mazzoleni last year). He gave the Futurist tropes of bustle and movement a new spin in the 50s, after a formative meeting with the then-elderly Giacomo Balla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Riley: Recent Paintings 2014 - 2017 | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>New year, new blockbuster at Zwirner. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s Op Art queen Bridget Riley, in a mini-retrospective of (mainly) work from the past four years.
It&amp;rsquo;s based around two themes: her return to the black and white patterns that made her name in the 60s, and her more recent disc paintings. What the two styles have in common is formal rigour, the impression of movement and disorientation. You could say her work, taken as a whole, form an inquiry into the constituent elements of painting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
