<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Max Hetzler on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/max-hetzler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Max Hetzler on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/max-hetzler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Louise Bonnet - New Works | Max Hetzler</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bonnet-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bonnet-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition, the debut UK show from Louise Bonnet, packs quite a punch. Large canvases show swollen female figures, wildly disproportionate. With their pointy boobs, big fat bums, tiny heads and odd-sized feet, they’re all uncomfortable, striking contorted poses, often constrained by ropes, shrouds and veils.
The oil paints are smoothly applied to these women, giving a vaguely inflatable, inorganic sheen to their skin. Not for Bonnet the textures and discolourations of Lucian Freud or Eric Fischl, those modern masters of the epidermis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Günther Förg | Max Hetzler and Luxembourg &amp; Dayan</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/forg-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/forg-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>Günther Förg was a German painter with quite a forbidding aesthetic - grainy architectural photographs, often of buildings built for a Fascist government - and monochrome acrylic paintings on a lead backing. He’s also selling well, if the three commercial gallery shows of his work in London alone over the past few months are any guide.
Two of them are running at the moment, one at Max Hetzler and one at Luxembourg &amp;amp; Dayan, and offer a good guide to both types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albert Oehlen - Sexe, religion, politique | Max Hetzler &amp; Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>Albert Oehlen is a difficult artist to love, but an easy artist to admire. This is due to his tendency to treat his painting as an intellectual exercise within strict self-imposed boundaries, rather than a vehicle of sensual pleasure. This tendency is on show in a pair of identically- titled exhibitions in two of Paris’ most prestigious private galleries: Max Hetzler and Gagosian.
Each exhibition features works with a near-identical yellow hue: clearly another deliberately-imposed restriction from Oehlen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
