<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laure Genillard on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/laure-genillard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laure Genillard on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/laure-genillard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Children Riding Gravestones: George Shaw &amp; Thomas Bewick | Laure Genillard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bewick-shaw-genillard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bewick-shaw-genillard/</guid>
      <description>I love a show that brings together two apparently totally different artists, and finds unexpected and inspiring connections! In fact, that kind of thing is what this blog is all about, as I tried to explain in my first post way back when. And I’ve showcased a couple such exhibitions since.
So, on one hand, George Shaw, famous for painting scenes from the not-so-nice Coventry suburb he grew up in, using the kind of enamel paints more commonly used for model aeroplanes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Michel Verjux at Laure Genillard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/verjux-genillard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/verjux-genillard/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to do. I had some leave from work to use, and used it this week, while galleries (and so many other places) remain locked down here in London. So the days have seemed blank, featureless.
I think of a plain circle of electric light, cast by a ceiling-mounted electric lamp. It’s a work by Michel Verjux, downstairs at Laure Genillard, which I viewed at an exhibition of his early last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Muntean - Just Like Honey | Rosenfeld Porcini</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</guid>
      <description>Austria-born, Berlin-based painter Robert Muntean says he’s inspired by Richard Gerstl, and there’s definitely something of the Secession-era artist’s taste for the obliterative in his new paintings, which often depicts figures only in outline, slashed by colours, large stretches of canvas left raw. They’re on show at Rosenfeld Porcini in Fitzrovia at the moment.
I’m thinking of Gerstl’s portrait of the family of Arnold Schoenberg, painted while having an affair with the mother of the house, just before discovery, and the painter’s descent into madness and suicide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
