<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Francis Bacon on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/francis-bacon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Francis Bacon on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/francis-bacon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lucian Freud: New Perspectives | National Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/freud-national/</guid>
      <description>Kindness isn’t a word that’s really associated with Lucian Freud, whose centenary retrospective is just coming to an end at the National Gallery. As befits such a big artistic beast - Freud has only become more mega-famous since his death in 2011 - the show is epic in scale. It’s loaded with the rather cruel portraits of his lovers and children he’s famous for: the early subjects bug-eyed and on the verge of tears, the later ones nude, uncomfortably contorted and rendered in thick oil paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keith Cunningham: The Cloud of Witness | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</guid>
      <description>This is a deeply gloomy exhibition of densely-worked oil paintings with a repeating roster of macabre subjects. Dogs, fighting each other; animal carcasses and slabs of meat and fish; portraits surrounded by foul, foggy miasmas, in semi-silhouette. The grandeur of the paintings’ surroundings - every time I come to this Damien Hirst-owned gallery, I’m struck by its lofty luxuriousness - sets them off wonderfully.
The story behind the exhibition is unusual: the works were created over half a century ago, but have been barely seen since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Bacon: Man and Beast | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>I caught COVID a few days ago. Worse than the sharp, uncanny fever has been the confinement - the daily stare at the fading T line on my LFT test, the lack of human contact, exercise… and gallery trips. This means I have nothing new to write about this week.
It’s possible I caught it at the last show I saw, this major Francis Bacon retrospective at the Royal Academy. I breezed around the large exhibition in around half an hour, not paying very close attention but taking in the atmosphere and getting my bearings: it’s on for a few months, so plenty of other chances to go back, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leon Kossoff | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</guid>
      <description>Along with bigger names like Lucian Freud and Francis Bacon, Leon Kossoff was part of the School of London, painters who passed a pitiless eye on the down-at-heel postwar capital city, pre Olympics, pre Millennium Dome, pre Big Bang boom. A fine retrospective selection of Kossoff’s work - the artist died in 2019 - is on show right now at Annely Juda Fine Art.
Kossoff&amp;rsquo;s subject matter is firmly rooted in the city he rarely left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hans Hartung - La fabrique du geste | MAM Paris</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hartung-mam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hartung-mam/</guid>
      <description>This artist hasn’t had a major retrospective in years, but had a career that spanned early 20th-century experiments in Symbolism, via Surrealism. He ended up, wheelchair-bound, firing acrylic paint through a spraygun in an insane burst of productivity, with 360 works in the final year of his life, 1989, alone.
Hartung found fame in the 50s and 60s, though, with his black-ink-on-paper works. These spikes and swoops found their way onto many book covers and student bedroom walls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
