<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sigmar Polke on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/sigmar-polke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sigmar Polke on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/sigmar-polke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Magdalena Skupinska: Blending Elements | Maximillian William</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/skupinska-maximillian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/skupinska-maximillian/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition, similar to the Alex Margo Arden show I covered last week, smells great. This time though, the odour wafting through the gallery isn’t synthetic, but all natural, emanating from the dried pine needles that carpets one of the works. There’s a little glass pot of pine next to the visitor’s book, too. Raw nature is an important governing concept for the Warsaw-born, London-based artist, who mixes her own paints from natural products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2020</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is my third year of the Artangled project, and my third end-of-year roundup. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the 2018 and 2019 format, listing the five art exhibitions I enjoyed most this year. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;ve also called out a couple of shows I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy. But for 2020, there’s only one candidate for my festive lump of coal: the global pandemic itself, one of whose side effects was to shutter London&amp;rsquo;s art galleries for months on end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sigmar Polke - Objects Real and Imagined | Michael Werner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/polke-werner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/polke-werner/</guid>
      <description>Sigmar Polke said, once: “Why doesn’t the public turn its attention to the potato, where ultimate fulfilment awaits?” This colossus of post war art practiced what he preached, making a variety of potato-based artworks against the bleak backdrop of post-war Germany. One of which, the 1960s Kartoffelhaus (or “potato house”) is currently, incongrugously, on show in one of London’s loveliest exhibition spaces, the winter garden at Michael Werner Gallery.
Polke’s turn to the potato came after he noticed a prize tuber in the cellar of his house one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source and Stimulus | Lévy Gorvy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/laing-levy-gorvy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/laing-levy-gorvy/</guid>
      <description>This pocket blockbuster of an exhibition is devoted to the &amp;lsquo;Ben-day dot&amp;rsquo;: those little dots on printed paper that make up images, if you look closely enough. Visible printed dots making up images on low-grade paper are, of course, a relic of the 20th century.
The advent of Pop Art in the 1960s was all about artists getting into commercial culture, and its mass-produced physical relics. This meant, for Sigmar Polke, Roy Lichtenstein and Gerald Laing, painstakingly painting reproductions of Ben-day dots to render iconic reproductions of pictures they saw in magazines, ads and pulp fiction books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
