<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Apóstol on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/alexander-ap%C3%B3stol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alexander Apóstol on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/alexander-ap%C3%B3stol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2019</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</guid>
      <description>Across 2019, I saw 221 art exhibitions and collections, not counting repeats, and posted reviews of 48 of them on this website. That’s slightly down on the 256 I saw in 2018. But, on the plus side, I did a lot of travelling within the UK this year and managed to make the site a bit less London-centric,	posting reviews across 10 cities, up from nine last year.
As will hopefully become an annual tradition here at Artangled, I’m going to round up my five favourite shows of the year, and name and shame a couple of public gallery exhibitions I didn’t like so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander Apóstol - Venezuelan Pastoral | Mor Charpentier</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/apostol-mor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/apostol-mor/</guid>
      <description>What horrible news, with more coming every day, from Venezuela! Alexander Apóstol, Venezuelan-born and Madrid-based, has a take on his country’s descent into madness in Dramatis Personae, a photo work, showing in Paris right now.
The visitor is confronted with a grid of black and white portraits, each showing a Venezuelan archetype: some timeless, some, very unfortunately, stuck in the here and now. There’s Simon Bolívar, a beauty queen, a rioting student, and a journalist with a shiny black eye.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
