<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cindy Sherman on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/cindy-sherman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cindy Sherman on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/cindy-sherman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cindy Sherman | National Portrait Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sherman-npg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sherman-npg/</guid>
      <description>This is a retrospective in the truest sense, ranging from the American master photographer’s first ever book, produced at the age of nine, to some of the most recent uber-glossy, expensively-produced photos of the artist as a range of grandes dames. (She showed a few of them at a highly enjoyable show at Sprüth Magers last year.)
It’s not possible not to read meanings into the childhood Cindy Book, which features family snaps, each with the artist herself carefully circled, and a single phrase: “that’s me”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Salle - Musicality and Humour | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/salle-skarstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/salle-skarstedt/</guid>
      <description>What a lovely palete cleanser this exhibition is! David Salle’s cartoony collage paintings shift and swirl, mixing black-and-white and colour. In this new show, he focuses on repetitive depictions of mops, coffee cups, pork chops and other ephemeral, day-to-day objects. He peppers his canvases with slogans and word marks.
They’re generally repainted elements from 1940s cartoons and ad imagery. Salle himself has said he’s aiming for a kind of “free jazz” effect: a pleasant cacophony, with enough underlying structure to hold the attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun House | Josh Lilley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gaignard-lilley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gaignard-lilley/</guid>
      <description>This is definitely the first gallery exhibition I&amp;rsquo;ve been to that&amp;rsquo;s named after a 90s kid&amp;rsquo;s TV show. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t remember the essential after-school viewing for now-thirtysomethings &amp;lsquo;Fun House&amp;rsquo; with Pat Sharp, this video should help you out.) But there&amp;rsquo;s not much to tie that &amp;ldquo;messy technicolour treat for kids&amp;rdquo;, as the show notes have it, to this rather sober collection. It&amp;rsquo;s a group show, and the artist in it that most stood out for me is American photographer Genevieve Gaignard, who I&amp;rsquo;d spotted at a previous exhibition at Stephen Friedman, and read about in this (excellent) New Yorker profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cindy Sherman | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sherman-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sherman-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Get away from me dear, I don&amp;rsquo;t need you anymore!&amp;rdquo; So said silent screen queen Norma Talmadge to a hopeful autograph seeker, just after she made it to the A-list. Well, according to Hollywood apochrypa anyway. The 20s movie grande dame is the latest visual inspiration from iconic shape-shifting photographer Cindy Sherman, whose new work in this show at Sprüth Magers is just as funny, off-kilter and subversive as ever.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
