<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hamilton&#39;s on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/hamiltons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hamilton&#39;s on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/hamiltons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don McCullin | Tate &amp; Hamiltons</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</guid>
      <description>It’s those little flecks of light, reflected in the shiny metal of minecart tracks, criss-crossing the ground in front of a mine in County Durham, and depicted in sumptuous black and white, that drew me in. Standing astride these tracks is a well-dressed couple, looking back at their photographer with a mixture of wariness and pride.
Their (very famous) photographer, Don McCullin, is best known for his images of war - from Vietnam to Biafra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jörg Immendorff - Questions from a Painter Who Reads | Michael Werner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</guid>
      <description>This is an artist who was a really big deal in his native land. I first heard of Jörg Immendorff when I visited his enormous retrospective at the Haus der Kunst in Munich last year, spanning his early political paintings of to his complex, gloomy, finely-wrought late works, painted as the artist was dying of ALS. A hideous way to go - and he went in 2007.
Now, Michael Werner is showing a cycle of huge paintings from the final year in its lovely winter garden, with some other examples of another Immendorff period - his fervent and optimistic 70s paintings of heroic workers and artists, working together to trash capitalism in some impressive wing collars and flares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Masters  | Hamilton&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</guid>
      <description>So often when looking at large-scale work, it&amp;rsquo;s a single detail that catches your eye. With Modern Masters, a group photographic show currently on at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s a young woman commuter in a light raincoat, glaring out from a train. She&amp;rsquo;s the emotional centre of Shinjuku Station, Tokyo, Japan, taken by photographer Hiro in 1962.
Across the breadth of this seven metre wide work, made up of seven gelatin silver prints, faces and hands of Tokyo commuters are pressed against the steamy glass of the subway car&amp;rsquo;s window.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
