<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Royal Academy on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/royal-academy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Royal Academy on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/royal-academy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Francis Bacon: Man and Beast | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>I caught COVID a few days ago. Worse than the sharp, uncanny fever has been the confinement - the daily stare at the fading T line on my LFT test, the lack of human contact, exercise… and gallery trips. This means I have nothing new to write about this week.
It’s possible I caught it at the last show I saw, this major Francis Bacon retrospective at the Royal Academy. I breezed around the large exhibition in around half an hour, not paying very close attention but taking in the atmosphere and getting my bearings: it’s on for a few months, so plenty of other chances to go back, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Constable | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/constable-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/constable-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>A few years back, I bought a print of one of my favourite works in the National Gallery, which as a native Londoner I’ve passed countless times over the years. Cenotaph to the Memory of Sir Joshua Reynolds was completed by John Constable in 1836, a year before the painter’s death. The romantic, autumnal scene, the deep browns of the mostly-bare trees melding into the vanilla-yellow, darkening sky, a ghostly stag gazing straight back at the viewer, is still on my wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hockney: The Arrival of Spring, Normandy, 2020 | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hockney-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hockney-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>While the world went into lockdown last Spring, David Hockney, ensconced in his comfortable country house in northern France, took out his iPad and captured the passing of the seasons.
Through circumstance, this Royal Academy show, containing 116 of these iPad pictures, comes at a time when lockdowns are over, and the Burlington House courtyard and the city beyond is ever more crowded. We’re having a springtime, then, even with the days getting shorter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracey Emin / Edvard Munch: The Loneliness of the Soul | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>There’s a bench in Berkeley Square in Mayfair with a funny plaque: On this bench in 2007, it states, the notorious artist Tracey Emin surrendered all her art rebel credibility when she decided to become a member of the Royal Academy of Arts. Times have changed: she’s not just a member these days. Instead, this self-described “notorious rebel” has aged into full blown grande dame status, and is getting a new RA exhibition, a few streets away from the square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Exhibition 2020 | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/summer-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/summer-academy/</guid>
      <description>The Royal Academy has been pretty conservative with its COVID response, tightening capacity by 80% and making pre-booking compulsory for everyone, members included. It seems tighter than Tate (whose Bruce Nauman show, which I also visited this week, was pretty full). Or maybe it’s the nature of its Summer Exhibition, delayed by lockdown, with over 1,000 works crowding the walls of the main galleries, that makes the relative paucity of the crowds stand out still more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Léon Spilliaert | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/spilliaert-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>What a shame this show, like all the others in London, is now closed. If there ever was an artist who exemplified social distancing, it’s Léon Spilliaert. And, having not spoken in person to anybody for coming up to two weeks now, I can’t tell anyone about how much I loved his paintings. I already regret just taking a quick spin around the three rooms in the upper galleries of the Royal Academy when I visited the exhibition, blithely assuming that I’d be back soon enough for a proper look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony Gormley | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gormley-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gormley-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>This is a very comprehensive show, featuring lots of Gormley’s notebooks and sketchbooks, and ranging from the early Land Art-inspired work, to new experiments. Such the final room, which I visited at night, feeling the dark chill of the entire gallery space submerged in clay-ey water.
Elsewhere, there are endless variations on Gormley’s trademark rusty metal and steel. Such as the exhibition’s centrepiece: Matrix III, constructed especially for the show. A couple lay dreamily on the hard wooden floor, gazing up at the grid patterns, densely arranged around a central void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
