<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lubaina Himid on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/lubaina-himid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lubaina Himid on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/lubaina-himid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ingrid Pollard: Carbon Slowly Turning | MK Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pollard-mk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pollard-mk/</guid>
      <description>“It was quite busy today, we had a queue!” said the gallerist to her colleague, as I was leaving this retrospective show of Guyana-born, London-based photographer Ingrid Pollard. I guess she meant either that this exhibition in particular isn’t drawing in massive crowds, or that this large, beautiful gallery doesn’t tend to attract crowds in general. I suspect the latter, given the uncanny, uber quiet atmosphere of Milton Keynes in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubaina Himid | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’ve talked about Lubaina Himid here before. During lockdown, my mind wandered towards Ankledeep, a pair portrait that’s part of a series the British-born painter completed in the 1990s. Each work in the series depicts pairs of “watchful and calm” black women, discussing important matters.
That painting, from the Tate’s permanent collection, forms part of an illuminating retrospective of Himid’s work, currently on show at Tate Modern. Himid’s an artist who returns again and again to repeating, overlapping themes, mainly in paint, but also in ceramics, set designs and sound works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Lubaina Himid at Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</guid>
      <description>“Nobody paints our love stories, our ordinary everyday,” the British artist Lubaina Himid told an interviewer once. “How our ordinary everyday is touched by enormous trauma and tragedy but we as a whole set of women globally and historically have the capacity to keep going.”
Let’s look at Ankledeep, a Himid painting from 1991 that’s part of the Tate collection, and was on show in an artist’s room at Tate Britain right up until the virus hit, and the doors closed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
