<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heather Phillipson on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/heather-phillipson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Heather Phillipson on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/heather-phillipson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chantal Joffe: A Sunday Afternoon in Whitechapel | Whitechapel Station</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/joffe-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/joffe-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>I’m a major train geek, but even I wasn’t ready for the opening of the Elizabeth Line, London’s biggest public transport event in decades, to be so joyous. The huge, cool, beautiful stations were filled with joyriders the first day it opened on Tuesday. By later in the week, the stations were still packed, but by now almost everybody seemed to be using the line for what it’s intended to be: a much quicker way of getting across town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Museum of the Moon | Durham Cathedral</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/moon-durham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/moon-durham/</guid>
      <description>This work’s simple and impressive: it’s a big blow-up model of the moon. Stencilled with detailed topographical photographs from NASA, this incredible inflatable has been touring for a couple of years, everywhere from downtown Kolkata to the Natural History Museum in London.
I saw it in one of the most awesome rooms in the world, Durham Cathedral. With its pointed arch vault gesturing towards the Gothic, and its fat columns and piers grounded in the Romanesque, this thousand-year-old space is huge and dim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2018</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a pretty big first year of art watching for this little side project.
In all, I saw 256 shows and collections in 2018 - not counting repeated visits to some old favourite permanent collections in London. Over that time, I featured a fifth of that total on the site, posting each week.
While I give my eyes a rest over the festive period, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up post, listing my top five of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my name is lettie eggsyrub | Gloucester Road</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/eggysrub-gloucester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/eggysrub-gloucester/</guid>
      <description>This endless hot summer hasn&amp;rsquo;t led to many art discoveries. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending too much time cowering under the blessed cool air of my desk fan: that £20 at John Lewis is the best money I&amp;rsquo;ve spent all decade. But one work that&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind a lot, thanks to my daily commute on the District Line, is &amp;lsquo;my name is lettie eggsyrub&amp;rsquo;, a silly yet also somehow haunting installation that runs the length of the unused platform at Gloucester Road tube station.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
