<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dorothea Tanning on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/dorothea-tanning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dorothea Tanning on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/dorothea-tanning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rosie Gibbens: Soft Girls | Zabludowicz Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gibbens-zabludowicz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gibbens-zabludowicz/</guid>
      <description>Rosie Gibbens’ sculptures are soft, cute and semi-interactive. The artist, clad in a constraining sheath dress and high heels, has activated this room of ‘soft girls’ in performances. Visitors to her show at the Zabludowicz Collection can also unroll a giant plushy tongue, attached to the wall by a mangel-like device, and use a foot pump to inflate one of the girls’ hands (a plastic glove).
The artist’s made inventive used of a combination of sex toys, clothing, office chairs and exercise equipment, plus a bunch of other found objects, to pull together her cute collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dorothea Tanning - Worlds in Collision | Alison Jacques</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tanning-jacques/</guid>
      <description>This American artist, who lived past 100, has a hefty reputation as a Surrealist icon of the 20th century. Over her long career, Dorothea Tanning was famous for her crafty paintings and stuffed-toy-like sculptures. Accompanied by her husband Max Ernst, she lived in an Arizona desert town and then in Paris. That’s certainly the life on show in her Tate Modern retrospective, which I enjoyed and returned to repeatedly during its run early last year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
