<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edward Hopper on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/edward-hopper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edward Hopper on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/edward-hopper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Danielle Roberts: Evening All Day | Fredericks &amp; Freiser</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</guid>
      <description>The portraitist Danielle Roberts, who has a show right now at the Fredericks &amp;amp; Freiser gallery, has a lot in common with Jenna Gribbon and Shannon Cartier Lucy, who I’ve featured on here before. All three painters are young women who paint young women: dramatically lit, listless, filled with ennui.
Roberts’ scenes are generally suburban, and take place at night. One woman is perched with one leg up on the back of a car in a convenience store car park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brothers in Art: Walter &amp; Harold Steggles and the East London Group | Beecroft Art Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been really interested in The East London Group’s paintings for a while - ever since I moved to Bow, slap bang in the middle of the neighbourhood depicted by these painters. This large exhibition puts over 100 paintings on show: that&amp;rsquo;s a hefty proportion of the total known surviving works from the Group. With the big majority of these in private collections, this exhibition represents a rare opportunity for an interested viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Fischl: The Krefeld Project | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</guid>
      <description>Sorry Lucian Freud, but when I think of a painter who captures the vulnerability and variety of the skin we live in, it’s Eric Fischl. The American artist, still active and showing at Skarstedt this autumn, works with loose, sparse but unerringly suggestive brushstrokes. He’s an unsentimental, relentless chronicler of skin, our skin, as it stretches, puffs and sags.
This show zooms in on a particular series Fischl undertook in 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Edward Hopper at the Addison Gallery of American Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hopper-andover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hopper-andover/</guid>
      <description>Manhattan Bridge Loop (1928) is a depiction of urban alienation and loneliness by the 20th century’s master of the form. Edward Hopper is a poet of the manmade: the cornices and fire escapes, the iron scaffolds, the brick and concrete, all lividly real to the viewer. By contrast, his clumsy, solitary figures, faces turned away from us and each other, are touchingly adrift in these spaces.
In this painting, the awesome scope of the bridge’s approach dominates - a great grey-black slash, cutting the lemony asphalt below off from the thin blue sky above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
