<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edvard Munch on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/edvard-munch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edvard Munch on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/edvard-munch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Opie: To What We Think We Remember | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</guid>
      <description>Catherine Opie is a globally-famous photographer who’s broadened her artistic topics of interest over recent years. She hit the big time in the 90s through her confrontational self-portraits, carving words and pictures into her flesh. They’re still her best-known photos. But a set of her work from the last decade, currently on show at Thomas Dane Gallery, reveals an artist in a lyrical mood.
These are photos of calm lakes, sunlit windows and dappled light, revealed in lush pigment prints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracey Emin / Edvard Munch: The Loneliness of the Soul | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/emin-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>There’s a bench in Berkeley Square in Mayfair with a funny plaque: On this bench in 2007, it states, the notorious artist Tracey Emin surrendered all her art rebel credibility when she decided to become a member of the Royal Academy of Arts. Times have changed: she’s not just a member these days. Instead, this self-described “notorious rebel” has aged into full blown grande dame status, and is getting a new RA exhibition, a few streets away from the square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ged Quinn | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</guid>
      <description>The British pastoral painter Ged Quinn’s style has been described by one critic as “malevolent&amp;hellip; sinister ”. It’s easy to see why, considering his subject matter. Quinn favours dark Romantic forests, silent pine-strewn paths and peaty skies. But in this new exhibition, Quinn showcases a sweeter edge.
Consider the fluffy linden tree that dominates Bloodstream Sub Tilia (on the right of the picture below). Folk mythology suggests that inhaling its pollen leads to nothing so sinister as… pleasant dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
