<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prunella Clough on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/prunella-clough/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prunella Clough on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/prunella-clough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Victoria Crowe: Resonance of Time | Flowers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/crowe-flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/crowe-flowers/</guid>
      <description>A pair of unseasonal exhibitions this week, in galleries on opposite sides of Cork Street. Unseasonal in that both of the featured artists use bare, skeletal tree branches as consistent visual motifs; look around you though, and trees are bursting into leaf everywhere, as summer begins to stir.
Victoria Crowe, on show at Flowers, studied under Prunella Clough, who’s shown up more than once on this site before; unlike her teacher though, Crowe’s work escapes from the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keith Cunningham: The Cloud of Witness | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cunningham-newport/</guid>
      <description>This is a deeply gloomy exhibition of densely-worked oil paintings with a repeating roster of macabre subjects. Dogs, fighting each other; animal carcasses and slabs of meat and fish; portraits surrounded by foul, foggy miasmas, in semi-silhouette. The grandeur of the paintings’ surroundings - every time I come to this Damien Hirst-owned gallery, I’m struck by its lofty luxuriousness - sets them off wonderfully.
The story behind the exhibition is unusual: the works were created over half a century ago, but have been barely seen since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leon Kossoff | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kossoff-annely-juda/</guid>
      <description>Along with bigger names like Lucian Freud and Francis Bacon, Leon Kossoff was part of the School of London, painters who passed a pitiless eye on the down-at-heel postwar capital city, pre Olympics, pre Millennium Dome, pre Big Bang boom. A fine retrospective selection of Kossoff’s work - the artist died in 2019 - is on show right now at Annely Juda Fine Art.
Kossoff&amp;rsquo;s subject matter is firmly rooted in the city he rarely left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phyllida Barlow | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/barlow-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Why am I looking at and writing about concrete so much this summer? First there was Prunella Clough’s desolate little paintings of midcentury urban corners, that caught my eye at Annely Juda Fine Art. Then there was Yu Ji’s dripping, detritus-filled installation at Chisenhale Gallery.
Now, rather grander than both, is Phyllida Barlow’s ring of a hundred or so three-metre-high cement sentinels, that squeeze to the edges of Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth’s main gallery at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prunella Clough and Alan Reynolds | Annely Juda Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/clough-annely/</guid>
      <description>Prunella Clough liked to explore the train yards at Willesden Junction: quite a messy and down-at-heel place these days, but surely an absolute decrepit dump in the post-war years in which she started working. From a wealthy background, she spent much of her career teaching at the Chelsea School of Art. But her own artistic output focused on semi-abstract paintings and prints of grimy, industrial and forgotten corners of London.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
