<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Fischl on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/eric-fischl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Fischl on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/eric-fischl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Light Holding: Jenna Gribbon | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</guid>
      <description>I was so impressed with Jenna Gribbon’s vigorous handling of oil paint in this tight, tense exhibition. Her virile brush strokes mercilessly expose her main subject - her partner, and according to Twitter, soon-to-be wife - in full-face portraits.
Heightening the tension, in many of these works, like M in Blinding Light, below, the subject has a bright clamp light directly shone in her face. That&amp;rsquo;s the light that&amp;rsquo;s being held.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hwang Seontae: The Power of Light | Pontone Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hwang-pontone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hwang-pontone/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition shows scenes of well-appointed, but empty modernist interiors from Korean artist Hwang Seontae. They’re light boxes, with sandblasted glass fronts and cold LED lights, the cable powering each scene discreetly boxed in.
In these imaginary rooms, the light comes from the windows: all of the works on show have the same title, The Space with Sunshine. It’s sunny outside, meaning that strong shadows are cast on the wooden floorboards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Fischl: The Krefeld Project | Skarstedt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fischl-skarstedt/</guid>
      <description>Sorry Lucian Freud, but when I think of a painter who captures the vulnerability and variety of the skin we live in, it’s Eric Fischl. The American artist, still active and showing at Skarstedt this autumn, works with loose, sparse but unerringly suggestive brushstrokes. He’s an unsentimental, relentless chronicler of skin, our skin, as it stretches, puffs and sags.
This show zooms in on a particular series Fischl undertook in 2002.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
