<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen Friedman Gallery on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/stephen-friedman-gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stephen Friedman Gallery on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/stephen-friedman-gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>David Shrigley: MAYFAIR TENNIS BALL EXCHANGE | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/shrigley-stephen-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/shrigley-stephen-friedman/</guid>
      <description>“I will make 100 works on paper with the intention that no more than half are any good,” the extremely popular and successful artist David Shrigley told the Guardian recently. “And there are probably four where you’re like: ‘This is basically fantastic! This is me demonstrating my area of expertise and all the other 96 are just attempts to do this.’ And do they sell? Do they fuck. You look through the inventory going: ‘Nobody bought that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yinka Shonibare: Justice for All | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/shonibare-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/shonibare-friedman/</guid>
      <description>Lady justice, sword in one hand, scales in the other, gestures at us on Old Burlington Street, behind the glass windows of the gallery. It’s a show designed to be looked at from outside: unreachable, but unmissable.
It’s Stephen Friedman Gallery and Yinka Shonibare’s response to the Black Lives Matter movement that’s roiled the global discourse this summer. The outdoor viewing is induced by the year’s other big global event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ged Quinn | Stephen Friedman Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/quinn-friedman/</guid>
      <description>The British pastoral painter Ged Quinn’s style has been described by one critic as “malevolent&amp;hellip; sinister ”. It’s easy to see why, considering his subject matter. Quinn favours dark Romantic forests, silent pine-strewn paths and peaty skies. But in this new exhibition, Quinn showcases a sweeter edge.
Consider the fluffy linden tree that dominates Bloodstream Sub Tilia (on the right of the picture below). Folk mythology suggests that inhaling its pollen leads to nothing so sinister as… pleasant dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
