<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rachel Howard on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/rachel-howard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rachel Howard on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/rachel-howard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Orlanda Broom: Shapeshifters | Grove Square Galleries</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/broom-grove/</guid>
      <description>Producing this collection of abstract works, made with colourful resin on canvas, must have taken a toll on the artist. Orlanda Broom can only work on works using resin for a couple of months each year - otherwise the ambient temperature isn’t right. The perfectionist artist also doesn’t allow any resin works with trapped hairs and dust out of the studio.
“I’m interested in the interpretation of abstract works,” she says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohammed Sami | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</guid>
      <description>The Execution Room, painted by Mohammed Sami, is one of the most impressively ugly artworks I’ve seen in a while. It’s currently on show at Modern Art, along with a collection of other new, thematically-linked work from this Iraq-born, Sweden-based artist.
It shows a dining table and chair set in a style that might kindly be termed “dictator chic”. I suspect, but can’t confirm by googling, that it was a room in Saddam Hussein’s palace, captured by allied forces during the disastrous war of 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Howard: You Have a New Memory | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</guid>
      <description>I first featured the British painter Rachel Howard on this site in 2018, when I saw a stately and sombre show of hers in Damien Hirst’s cavernous Newport Street Gallery. Back then, she showed works based around the stations of the cross. This new exhibition, Howard’s first at Simon Lee, is a more intimate affair, both spatially, in that the Mayfair gallery’s a bit pokier, and in the subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clare Woods - Doublethink | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>This artist’s practice has similar roots to other artists I’ve featured on this site before. Like Robert Muntean, Clare Woods takes found images from newspapers and magazines and makes something new with them.
Like her compatriot Gary Hume, she paints on aluminium, giving the final works an ultra-clean, shiny, textured look. Like Rachel Howard , she paints from above, letting the drips fall down the edges of the works.
But Woods’ overall effects are unique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Howard, Repetition is Truth - Via Dolorosa | Newport Street Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/howard-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/howard-newport/</guid>
      <description>When making this series of works, based on the 14 stations of the cross, the artist first allowed gloss paint to separate. Then, she poured the pigment onto large canvases from above. Then, she added the laminate to the canvas. This has led to the works&amp;rsquo; shiny surface of vertical stripes and drips. Their reflectiveness make them hard to photograph, if not to look at. The series is on show currently at the Newport Street Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
