<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mario Sironi on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/mario-sironi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mario Sironi on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/mario-sironi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Balthus: Under the Surface | Luxembourg &#43; Co</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, apparently the first Balthus exhibition in the UK since 1968, contain the following Oscar Wilde quote: “All art is at once surface and symbol. Those who go beneath the surface do so at their peril. Those who read the symbol do so at their peril.”
This plea not to look too closely is appropriate for this artist, considering the fact he was a snob, a vile anti-semite despite his Jewish heritage, and is most famous these days for his unabashedly erotic pictures of little girls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brothers in Art: Walter &amp; Harold Steggles and the East London Group | Beecroft Art Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/steggles-beecroft/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been really interested in The East London Group’s paintings for a while - ever since I moved to Bow, slap bang in the middle of the neighbourhood depicted by these painters. This large exhibition puts over 100 paintings on show: that&amp;rsquo;s a hefty proportion of the total known surviving works from the Group. With the big majority of these in private collections, this exhibition represents a rare opportunity for an interested viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2019</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2019/</guid>
      <description>Across 2019, I saw 221 art exhibitions and collections, not counting repeats, and posted reviews of 48 of them on this website. That’s slightly down on the 256 I saw in 2018. But, on the plus side, I did a lot of travelling within the UK this year and managed to make the site a bit less London-centric,	posting reviews across 10 cities, up from nine last year.
As will hopefully become an annual tradition here at Artangled, I’m going to round up my five favourite shows of the year, and name and shame a couple of public gallery exhibitions I didn’t like so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mario Sironi - Signs and Colours | Brun Fine Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sironi-brun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sironi-brun/</guid>
      <description>This exhibition begins with a surprising painting, considering its painter: a smiling self-portrait. Surprising, as Mario Sironi’s reputation is based his unremittingly grim work, spanning the early 1920s to the 50s. This general bleakness, coupled with his enthusiastic embrace of the Mussolini regime pre-war, and his post-war withdrawal from the public sphere, has made him a pretty obscure name - especially in the UK, where this is the first Sironi show in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enchanted Room | Estorick Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sironi-estorick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sironi-estorick/</guid>
      <description>Mario Sironi was a poet of the grimy and growing suburbs of Milan. In the inter-war years, he made a series of small, thickly worked &amp;lsquo;Urban Landscapes&amp;rsquo;, close-cropped, bleak city scenes of factories, smokestacks and apartment blocks.
There are two really fine examples in the Estorick&amp;rsquo;s latest show, subtitled &amp;lsquo;Modern Works from the Pinacoteca di Brera&amp;rsquo;. This is the first time many of these paintings and sculptures, donated by collectors Emilio and Maria Jesi, have been shown outside of Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
