<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emil Nolde on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/emil-nolde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emil Nolde on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/emil-nolde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Balthus: Under the Surface | Luxembourg &#43; Co</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, apparently the first Balthus exhibition in the UK since 1968, contain the following Oscar Wilde quote: “All art is at once surface and symbol. Those who go beneath the surface do so at their peril. Those who read the symbol do so at their peril.”
This plea not to look too closely is appropriate for this artist, considering the fact he was a snob, a vile anti-semite despite his Jewish heritage, and is most famous these days for his unabashedly erotic pictures of little girls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emil Nolde: Anatomy of Light and Water | Bastian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nolde-bastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nolde-bastian/</guid>
      <description>Emil Nolde was a supremely talented painter who made gorgeous use of colours suggesting light. He also had well-documented Nazi sympathies. That’s surely a big reason why he isn’t much seen: this small show of watercolours was the first Nolde exhibition I can recall in London in my years of gallery-going.
As an older man, Nolde spent his summers in Seebüll in Northern Germany, a beach-side town. Thomas Mann country - Caspar David Friedrich country - at least in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phantastisch! Alfred Kubin und der Blaue Reiter | Lenbachhaus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kubin-lenbachhaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kubin-lenbachhaus/</guid>
      <description>Alfred Kubin had a pretty standard upbringing, when you consider his predilection for the grotesque. Bouncing between mental health problems, a sexual encounter with a pregnant woman when he was 11, and a (failed) suicide-by-shotgun attempt on his mother’s grave, he found lasting fame just after graduating with sickly macabre little pen-and-ink drawings, depicting torture, devils, and death. There’s a great selection on show at Phantastisch! Alfred Kubin und Der Blaue Reiter, an exhibition currently running at the Lenbachhaus in Munich.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
