<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamian Juliano-Villani on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/jamian-juliano-villani/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamian Juliano-Villani on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/jamian-juliano-villani/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coco Capitán: Naïvy | Maximillian William</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/capitan-william/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/capitan-william/</guid>
      <description>This young artist, who also pays the bills as a fashion photographer, is very obviously going places. Still a couple of years shy of 30, she has a rock-solid aesthetic across photos, paintings, (hand) writing and found objects, which are all on show at Maximillian William right now.
The exhibition is based around a garment that could be militaristic, cute or camp: a sailor suit. The actual suit is draped over a schoolroom-style wooden chair, its hood carefully appliquéd with white-stitched daisies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junque | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/junque-massimo/</guid>
      <description>The first time I saw US-based Jamian Juliano-Villani’s work was at Massimo de Carlo last year. I wrote about this show’s prime attraction: a cuddly tiger getting rigorously orally penetrated with a plastic-clad dildo. The fun continues in the same gallery this summer, in a group show organised around “junk”.
That’s junk in both the literal and slang senses of the word: either worthless clutter, or, like… a penis. It doesn’t really matter which way you take it (hmmm), Juliano Villani’s slapdash, don’t-care aesthetic isn’t proscriptive in the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamian Juliano-Villani - Let’s Kill Nicole | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/juliano-de-carlo/</guid>
      <description>Slapdash, funny and deeply, deeply Instagrammable, New York-based Jamian Juliano-Villani has produced a sweet summer treat. Like a soft scoop ice cream special with hundreds and thousands, a flavoured cone AND a Flake, this show is an all out assault. And the generally lurid work is nicely offset by its host: one of London’s poshest and soberest private gallery spaces.
My favourite - introduced via Russell Tovey’s Instagram of all places - features a cuddly tiger getting savagely orally pumped by a mechanised dildo in a plastic bag.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
