<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Zwirner on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/david-zwirner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David Zwirner on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/david-zwirner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dan Flavin: colored fluorescent light | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>The handsome townhouse&amp;rsquo;s windows were glowing with warm pink light. A warm and welcome sight as I approached the David Zwirner gallery up Hay Hill on a gloomy afternoon in early February, the dark already setting in.
Warmth isn’t a feeling commonly associated with Dan Flavin, who wore his various intellectual inspirations heavily even by the standards of his fellow macho midcentury Minimals. But you can’t knock the fact that his central artistic innovation - using light as his material - was both radical and influential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Leonard. Aerials | Hauser &amp; Wirth</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/leonard-hauser-wirth/</guid>
      <description>Zoe Leonard is an American conceptual artist who took aerial photos of New York City over several years in the late 80s. Gelatin silver prints of these are on show as Hauser &amp;amp; Wirth right now, and when I went to see them, I basically wanted to buy them all, in an alternative fantasy universe where I actually have the funds to do that.
The artist’s eye gets caught on urban infrastructure; the densely gridded street pattern of the city; worn summer baseball fields, packed back to back and encroached on by houses from all sides; and, most lovingly shot of all, a gleaming rail interchange, the iron and wood of the parallel tracks caught by low light, rendered mysterious by the silver print’s blur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmgreen &amp; Dragset - This Is How We Bite Our Tongue | Whitechapel Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/elmgreen-dragset-whitechapel/</guid>
      <description>Whitechapel Gallery has been transformed into a derelict swimming pool with an imaginary backstory. Built by a Victorian philanthropist (the story goes), the Whitechapel Pool played host to Tesco founder Jack Cohen and David Hockney over its decades as a public utility. Then it got shut down in the privatisation-happy Thatcher era, before being renovated as part of a “design hotel” opening in 2019. Unfortunately for future Cohens and Hockneys, it’ll be accessible only through membership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerry James Marshall - History of Painting  | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>Kerry James Marshall is uber-influential these days, with his works selling for seven figure sums - to P Diddy, no less. He&amp;rsquo;s also an incredible and sensitive portraitist. Sometimes beloved, successful work is great work, as his new exhibition at David Zwirner proves. But the show also has interesting things to say about the nature of that success.
This is an exhibition about the ways in which paintings can be made, and the contexts in which they are received.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Riley: Recent Paintings 2014 - 2017 | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/riley-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>New year, new blockbuster at Zwirner. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s Op Art queen Bridget Riley, in a mini-retrospective of (mainly) work from the past four years.
It&amp;rsquo;s based around two themes: her return to the black and white patterns that made her name in the 60s, and her more recent disc paintings. What the two styles have in common is formal rigour, the impression of movement and disorientation. You could say her work, taken as a whole, form an inquiry into the constituent elements of painting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
