<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sanya Kantarovsky on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/sanya-kantarovsky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sanya Kantarovsky on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/sanya-kantarovsky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanya Kantarovsky &amp; Camille Blatrix: Will-o’-the-wisp | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-blatrix-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-blatrix-modern/</guid>
      <description>I’ve loved Sanya Kantarovsky’s snarky, morbid and scatological paintings since I first encountered them, in his 2018 solo show at Kunsthalle Basel. So I was really excited to see this London show of his woodblock prints, set in frames from French painter/sculptor Camille Blatrix.
The thing that struck me about Kantarovsky’s work, then and now, is the balance between the serious and the silly. These prints have hideous subject matter - in one, a robed, bloodied figure kneels by the surf; in another, a child and his mother are molested by a bony hand - but are cartoonishly-drawn, in zanily bright colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2018</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a pretty big first year of art watching for this little side project.
In all, I saw 256 shows and collections in 2018 - not counting repeated visits to some old favourite permanent collections in London. Over that time, I featured a fifth of that total on the site, posting each week.
While I give my eyes a rest over the festive period, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up post, listing my top five of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanya Kantarovsky - Disease of the Eyes | Kunsthalle Basel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-kunsthalle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kantarovsky-kunsthalle/</guid>
      <description>This Russia-born, New York based artist likes to do his work prone on the ground, with people around to talk to. Stray brush strokes and other little mistakes are usually left in the final painting, to better build up its texture. He mixes oil paint and water, which don&amp;rsquo;t really mix properly. But, despite these quite zany and antic working methods, the subjects of Sanya Kantarovsky&amp;rsquo;s paintings and prints are relentlessly despairing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
