<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thomas Demand on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/thomas-demand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thomas Demand on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/thomas-demand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Henni Alftan: Contour | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/alftan-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/alftan-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>The painting below is called Tinted. It really stood out to me when I visited the artist’s show at Sprüth Magers, which opened this week. The painter, Henni Alftan, is Finland-born and Paris-based. She takes her inspiration from everyday mundane human scenes, except the human beings are absent. A prevailing theme in exhibitions featured here recently, including one from Thomas Demand (at the same gallery) and another from Hwang Seontae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Demand | Sprüth Magers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/demand-spruth-magers/</guid>
      <description>I loved Canopy, the photograph below, on show in the main gallery room at Sprüth Magers at the moment. It’s a sunny scene of some powdery blue apartment block, with a single, lemon sorbet-coloured canopy over-extended over one of the blocky white balconies. Given the work’s from 2020, the artist must have been thinking of our lockdown when he made it. The silent shadowy interiors signal the confinement of unseen occupants; I remember that for some city-dwellers, in the early days of the crisis, balconies were the only &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; outside space available to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
