<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shannon Cartier Lucy on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/shannon-cartier-lucy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shannon Cartier Lucy on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/shannon-cartier-lucy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Danielle Roberts: Evening All Day | Fredericks &amp; Freiser</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</guid>
      <description>The portraitist Danielle Roberts, who has a show right now at the Fredericks &amp;amp; Freiser gallery, has a lot in common with Jenna Gribbon and Shannon Cartier Lucy, who I’ve featured on here before. All three painters are young women who paint young women: dramatically lit, listless, filled with ennui.
Roberts’ scenes are generally suburban, and take place at night. One woman is perched with one leg up on the back of a car in a convenience store car park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Holding: Jenna Gribbon | Massimo de Carlo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/gribbon-massimo/</guid>
      <description>I was so impressed with Jenna Gribbon’s vigorous handling of oil paint in this tight, tense exhibition. Her virile brush strokes mercilessly expose her main subject - her partner, and according to Twitter, soon-to-be wife - in full-face portraits.
Heightening the tension, in many of these works, like M in Blinding Light, below, the subject has a bright clamp light directly shone in her face. That&amp;rsquo;s the light that&amp;rsquo;s being held.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2021</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2021/</guid>
      <description>I’ve surprised myself with sticking to the Artangled project for another year. Ever since lockdown eased in April, and many London galleries reopened, I’ve posted weekly. Just as I have each week since the beginning of 2018. This site, and its thousands of words, remain a personal project: I doubt I could ‘grow the brand’ even if I tried! But I should admit, it’s remained a personal pleasure to sit down each week and put together a post, and I’ll continue doing it as long as the pleasure remains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Cartier Lucy: Cake on the Floor | Soft Opening</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/lucy-soft/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, from Nashville-based painter Shannon Cartier Lucy, are really excellent, and illuminated what I saw in the gallery. (Given that show notes are so often trite and obfuscatory, it’s worth shouting out.)
“Any singular narrative is made obtuse,” by this artist, Philomena Epps writes, “the certainty of reality melted away through her embrace of fantasy and the uncanny.
“The setting of a party can be inferred by the particular debris and signs of festivities: there is cake and strings of undulating, crimped satin ribbons, but the situation reads as ominous, toxic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
