<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Munich on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/munich/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Munich on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/munich/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Rogier van der Weyden at the Alte Pinakothek</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/weyden-alte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/weyden-alte/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this site is for me to write about an art show I&amp;rsquo;ve seen each week. Obviously, that&amp;rsquo;s a purpose that can’t be fulfilled at the moment, with galleries - and gallery-goers - in lockdown. Time for something different then: from home, I’m going to focus each post on a work in a permanent collection, shuttered somewhere in an empty museum, that I’ve been thinking about for some reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phantastisch! Alfred Kubin und der Blaue Reiter | Lenbachhaus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/kubin-lenbachhaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/kubin-lenbachhaus/</guid>
      <description>Alfred Kubin had a pretty standard upbringing, when you consider his predilection for the grotesque. Bouncing between mental health problems, a sexual encounter with a pregnant woman when he was 11, and a (failed) suicide-by-shotgun attempt on his mother’s grave, he found lasting fame just after graduating with sickly macabre little pen-and-ink drawings, depicting torture, devils, and death. There’s a great selection on show at Phantastisch! Alfred Kubin und Der Blaue Reiter, an exhibition currently running at the Lenbachhaus in Munich.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
