<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antoni Tàpies on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/antoni-t%C3%A0pies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antoni Tàpies on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/antoni-t%C3%A0pies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Romauld Hazoumè: Carnaval | October Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hazoume-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hazoume-october/</guid>
      <description>Like Antoni Tàpies, featured on here last week, Romauld Hazoumè uses found objects in his work. But the two artists could hardly be more different. As this show highlights, Hazoumè is droll, down to earth and humanist where Tàpies is sober, grand and ethereal.
This artist, who lives and works in Benin, uses discarded oilcans, bottles, feathers and other throwaway objects to produce what he calls masques bidons (repurposed masks). The title of the exhibition’s a clue to the kind of atmosphere Hazoumè wants to create: just like at a carnival parade, the masks shouldn’t just look good, they also provide a kind of subversive social commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>antoni tàpies: alchemy | Nahmad Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tapies-nahmad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tapies-nahmad/</guid>
      <description>Nahmad Projects is one of Mayfair’s shiniest white cubes, a deceptively large gallery with a nave, side chapel and benches. This allows the dozen or so large, abstract works that make up most of this exhibition to be presented like relics in a church.
Antoni Tàpies, the artist on show, made a decisive turn towards abstraction early in his career, and built up a distinctive visual lexicon of signs and symbols, using everyday materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L’Empreinte | Olivier Malingue</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/empreinte-malingue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/empreinte-malingue/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to theme an exhibition around a concept. If the concept’s too broad, the effect is absurd; too specific, and it could just be hair-splittingly academic and boring. But this very smartly-conceived and executed show finds the sweet spot, featuring works which all feature some form of imprint. A concept sufficiently rich in suggestion, and encompassing a sufficiently broad variety of artistic expression, to make this exhibition really special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Exhibition - Simon Hantaï, Pierre Soulages and Antoni Tàpies | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hantai-taylor/</guid>
      <description>International gallery Timothy Taylor has a new home on the other side of Berkeley Square as its old one, and has put on an interesting exhibition to mark the occasion. The show brings together three artists who found fame at a similar time - the years following the last world war - but via quite different methods.
Pierre Soulages applied thick black paint - layers and layers of it - to his large canvases, while Antoni Tàpies went even heavier, with his bulky sculptures in bronze and fired clay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
