<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Flavin on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/dan-flavin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dan Flavin on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/dan-flavin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Noland: Stripes/Plaids/Shapes | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Noland put himself under a lot of pressure to achieve such chilled-out art. He’s been called a “minimalist” or “colour field” painter, with his large canvases banded with simple patterns - or just stripes. In fact, Stripes/ Plaids/ Shapes, the title of this show, Noland’s first monograph exhibition in the UK for over 20 years, pretty much sums up what’s on display.
So, where’s the pressure from? In the technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Flavin: colored fluorescent light | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/flavin-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>The handsome townhouse&amp;rsquo;s windows were glowing with warm pink light. A warm and welcome sight as I approached the David Zwirner gallery up Hay Hill on a gloomy afternoon in early February, the dark already setting in.
Warmth isn’t a feeling commonly associated with Dan Flavin, who wore his various intellectual inspirations heavily even by the standards of his fellow macho midcentury Minimals. But you can’t knock the fact that his central artistic innovation - using light as his material - was both radical and influential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albert Oehlen - Sexe, religion, politique | Max Hetzler &amp; Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>Albert Oehlen is a difficult artist to love, but an easy artist to admire. This is due to his tendency to treat his painting as an intellectual exercise within strict self-imposed boundaries, rather than a vehicle of sensual pleasure. This tendency is on show in a pair of identically- titled exhibitions in two of Paris’ most prestigious private galleries: Max Hetzler and Gagosian.
Each exhibition features works with a near-identical yellow hue: clearly another deliberately-imposed restriction from Oehlen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerry James Marshall - History of Painting  | David Zwirner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/marshall-zwirner/</guid>
      <description>Kerry James Marshall is uber-influential these days, with his works selling for seven figure sums - to P Diddy, no less. He&amp;rsquo;s also an incredible and sensitive portraitist. Sometimes beloved, successful work is great work, as his new exhibition at David Zwirner proves. But the show also has interesting things to say about the nature of that success.
This is an exhibition about the ways in which paintings can be made, and the contexts in which they are received.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
