<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rinus Van de Velde on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/rinus-van-de-velde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rinus Van de Velde on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/rinus-van-de-velde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Burley: The Intricate Live Habits and Rituals of the Goblin | GAO Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/burley-gao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/burley-gao/</guid>
      <description>I wonder whether Daniel Burley, the young British multimedia artist, pored over the memorably disgusting Fungus the Bogeyman when he grew up. He’d definitely have seen Shrek. And he’s clearly come of age in the noughties, the decade that fashion forgot, with its gross bootcuts and belly shorts.
All that’s gone in the aesthetic mixer for this show in the small GAO Gallery, just off the Mile End Road. Three “goblins”, green figures made of epoxy and steel, finished off with oil paint, galavant across the floor: tumbling over a log, gathering flowers, and clawing at the sky with sharp talons - painted with nail polish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rinus Van de Velde - Ashtrays | König</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/velde-koenig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/velde-koenig/</guid>
      <description>Here in the UK, smoking’s been banned in many public places for well over a decade. Which means that smoking-related objects, like the humble ashtray, are passing into obscurity. The kids are vaping these days.
As a result, I wouldn’t have necessarily recognised Rinus Van de Velde’s cute yet disturbing sculptures as being ashtrays, had it not been for the title of this show. But there they are: round, shallow dishes, with notches around the rim.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
