<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wade Guyton on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/wade-guyton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wade Guyton on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/wade-guyton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Richard Patterson: Only Fans | Timothy Taylor</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/patterson-taylor/</guid>
      <description>Richard Patterson was a YBA, part of the scandalous 1990s ‘Sensation’ generation. But, like his peers Gillian Wearing and Gavin Turk, he’s matured into a painter of sensitivity and skill. Proof of this view comes in ‘Only Fans’, a show of small-format works using what the press release describes as a “carnal palette”, which closed this week at Timothy Taylor.
All 13 paintings in the exhibition are dreamy swirls of flesh-toned roses and ochres, on luxurious-looking linen canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Dordoy: Answering Machine | GRIMM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dordoy-grimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dordoy-grimm/</guid>
      <description>The ambiance cast by the works in this exhibition somehow matched the weather on the day I went: cold, clear and uncannily still. Alex Dordoy uses shallow collages of acrylic paint on canvas to render apparently comforting and familiar scenes. The interior of a church (Answering Machine); a seascape (A Few Careless Words); a couple camping in a forest (Kindling the March Wind).
Look closer, though, and things get uncomfortable. The church’s statues are cut off at the ankles; a big wave in the middle of the sea is breaking on… apparently nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingrid Pollard: Carbon Slowly Turning | MK Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pollard-mk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pollard-mk/</guid>
      <description>“It was quite busy today, we had a queue!” said the gallerist to her colleague, as I was leaving this retrospective show of Guyana-born, London-based photographer Ingrid Pollard. I guess she meant either that this exhibition in particular isn’t drawing in massive crowds, or that this large, beautiful gallery doesn’t tend to attract crowds in general. I suspect the latter, given the uncanny, uber quiet atmosphere of Milton Keynes in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ed Fornieles: Associations | Carlos/Ishikawa</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/fornieles-carlos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/fornieles-carlos/</guid>
      <description>Ed Fornieles brings together a couple of prevailing themes I’ve been covering on Artangled these last few months. First, the technique of using found photographs in a clever way: see here for similar on Wade Guyton and Jan Hendrickse. Second, responding artistically to the weird phase of lockdown the world’s been in this past year or so: as have Gillian Wearing, Alban Laurent, Thomas Demand and likely many more to be featured in future weeks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Wade Guyton at MoMA</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/guyton-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/guyton-moma/</guid>
      <description>How unsatisfying to look at art on a computer screen, rather than in a gallery. Unsurprisingly, considering I go to 200+ shows per year, I’ve fallen in love with the whole ritual of gallery going: ringing the bell, taking the printed-out press release, writing in the artist’s book on leaving. And now, how quaint that seems in virus-induced lockdown: bell, paper and pen have all become potential vectors of disease, in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
