<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New York City on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/new-york-city/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New York City on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/new-york-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spencer Finch: Lux and Lumen | Hill Art Foundation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/finch-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/finch-hill/</guid>
      <description>“Ye cannot serve God and mammon,” claims the gospel of Matthew. But the Hill Art Foundation gives it a good go. This small gallery is owned by hedge fund billionaire J. Tomlinson Hill, and is currently hosting a beautiful bringing-together of a Renaissance stained glass window and various stained glass installations from contemporary artist Spencer Finch.
The Creation and the Expulsion from Paradise was completed by Valentin Bousch in 1533, and has most recently been a prize possession of rich American collectors: it used to be installed above William Randolph Hearst’s fireplace, according to the show notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danielle Roberts: Evening All Day | Fredericks &amp; Freiser</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/roberts-fredericks-freiser/</guid>
      <description>The portraitist Danielle Roberts, who has a show right now at the Fredericks &amp;amp; Freiser gallery, has a lot in common with Jenna Gribbon and Shannon Cartier Lucy, who I’ve featured on here before. All three painters are young women who paint young women: dramatically lit, listless, filled with ennui.
Roberts’ scenes are generally suburban, and take place at night. One woman is perched with one leg up on the back of a car in a convenience store car park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Wade Guyton at MoMA</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/guyton-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/guyton-moma/</guid>
      <description>How unsatisfying to look at art on a computer screen, rather than in a gallery. Unsurprisingly, considering I go to 200+ shows per year, I’ve fallen in love with the whole ritual of gallery going: ringing the bell, taking the printed-out press release, writing in the artist’s book on leaving. And now, how quaint that seems in virus-induced lockdown: bell, paper and pen have all become potential vectors of disease, in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
