<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tornabuoni Art on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/tornabuoni-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tornabuoni Art on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/tornabuoni-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jörg Immendorff - Questions from a Painter Who Reads | Michael Werner</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/immendorff-werner/</guid>
      <description>This is an artist who was a really big deal in his native land. I first heard of Jörg Immendorff when I visited his enormous retrospective at the Haus der Kunst in Munich last year, spanning his early political paintings of to his complex, gloomy, finely-wrought late works, painted as the artist was dying of ALS. A hideous way to go - and he went in 2007.
Now, Michael Werner is showing a cycle of huge paintings from the final year in its lovely winter garden, with some other examples of another Immendorff period - his fervent and optimistic 70s paintings of heroic workers and artists, working together to trash capitalism in some impressive wing collars and flares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piero Dorazio, Chromatic Fantasies (1948-82) | Tornabuoni Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dorazio-tornabuoni/</guid>
      <description>Showing in the depths of an interminable winter, this blast of colour, at Tornabuoni until springtime, comes as a welcome relief &amp;ndash; even a joy.
Dorazio isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a heavy hitter in the pantheon of post war Italian painting. In fact, this is billed as his &amp;ldquo;first London show in a generation&amp;rdquo; (though he was a big part of a group show up the road at Mazzoleni last year). He gave the Futurist tropes of bustle and movement a new spin in the 50s, after a formative meeting with the then-elderly Giacomo Balla.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
