<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Candida Höfer on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/candida-h%C3%B6fer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Candida Höfer on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/candida-h%C3%B6fer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marwan Bassiouni: New British Views | Workplace</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bassiouni-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bassiouni-workplace/</guid>
      <description>There’s something about the low light of my homeland, depicted in a painting or a photograph, that pushes me to write about it: see previous examples from George Shaw, Mike Silva and Jock McFadyen. This time, it’s an exhibition from Marwan Bassiouni, whose impressively cosmopolitan background (Italian-Swiss-Egyptian-American) hasn’t stopped him depicting the most humdrum, low-lit British landscapes with notable sensitivity and skill.
Bassiouni’s conceit is simple: he shoots landscapes, seen through the windows of mosques and Islamic prayer rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yves Marchand &amp; Romain Meffre: Movie Theaters | Tristan Hoare Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/marchand-meffre-hoare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/marchand-meffre-hoare/</guid>
      <description>‘Ruin porn’ is a loaded term. Viewers living in intact and tidy homes, getting a vicarious thrill from images of spectacularly derelict places. Places we don’t have to deal with in our day to day lives.
Anyway, if ruin porn is a thing, Yves Marchand and Romain Meffre are some of the top pornographers in the game. They’re behind The Ruins of Detroit, a coffee table book of sumptuously shot photos of the motor city, once so prosperous and now run so completely to seed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candida Höfer - Showing and Seeing | Ben Brown Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hofer-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hofer-brown/</guid>
      <description>Like her Düsseldorf school colleague Andreas Gursky, who I’ve written about on here before, Candida Höfer specialises in large-format photographs of big, man-made spaces. But Höfer’s subject matter has a tighter focus: very fancy, richly-coloured, and almost entirely depopulated, interiors.
The nine photographs on show right now at Ben Brown Fine Arts stick rigidly to her precisely-defined parameters (Höfer has been photographing interiors since 1979). Her empty spaces are built to host crowds of strangers: libraries, in Austria, France and Mexico; and theatres, in Russia and Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albert Oehlen - Sexe, religion, politique | Max Hetzler &amp; Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/oehlen-hetzler/</guid>
      <description>Albert Oehlen is a difficult artist to love, but an easy artist to admire. This is due to his tendency to treat his painting as an intellectual exercise within strict self-imposed boundaries, rather than a vehicle of sensual pleasure. This tendency is on show in a pair of identically- titled exhibitions in two of Paris’ most prestigious private galleries: Max Hetzler and Gagosian.
Each exhibition features works with a near-identical yellow hue: clearly another deliberately-imposed restriction from Oehlen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
