<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thomas Dane Gallery on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/thomas-dane-gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thomas Dane Gallery on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/thomas-dane-gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Opie: To What We Think We Remember | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/opie-dane/</guid>
      <description>Catherine Opie is a globally-famous photographer who’s broadened her artistic topics of interest over recent years. She hit the big time in the 90s through her confrontational self-portraits, carving words and pictures into her flesh. They’re still her best-known photos. But a set of her work from the last decade, currently on show at Thomas Dane Gallery, reveals an artist in a lyrical mood.
These are photos of calm lakes, sunlit windows and dappled light, revealed in lush pigment prints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Conner - BREAKAWAY | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/conner-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/conner-dane/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty rare opportunity to view work by the American polymath Bruce Conner in London. Conner, who died in 2008, was a painter, sculptor and video artist who worked over a massive range of media.
This time, the focus is on his mid-60s video art: on show at Thomas Dane is Breakaway, from 1966, which he shot with popstar and choreographer Toni Basil, whose similarly long career improbably peaked a decade and a half later with the stone cold novelty classic Hey Mickey!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francesco Arena - Cubic Metre of Seawater as a Diagonal | Sprovieri</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/arena-sprovieri/</guid>
      <description>Two shows from Italian artists caught my eye this week. First, this exhibition from Franceso Arena at one of the west end’s least accessible galleries, up a flight of stairs behind Regent Street. Arena makes vaguely arte povera-aligned works, using natural and found materials.
The centrepiece of this show is rather grandiose: exactly as the title suggests, seawater is contained in a metal trough, 13 metres long, oriented diagonally across the largest gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xie Nanxing - A Gift Like Kung Pao Chicken | Thomas Dane Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/nanxing-dane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/nanxing-dane/</guid>
      <description>This show wasn’t exactly appealing to me as I can’t stand the volcanically spicy Sichuan dish it’s named after, but Xie Nanxing soon put my prejudices (and stomach) to rest. The reason for the name is the bright colours of kung pao chicken, and accordingly the walls of Thomas Dane are painted in greens and pinks.
The similarities to the chicken dish end there. Xie’s painting technique is known as ‘canvas print’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
