<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rachel Whiteread on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/rachel-whiteread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rachel Whiteread on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/rachel-whiteread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Haunted Realism | Gagosian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/haunted-gagosian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/haunted-gagosian/</guid>
      <description>This is a typically epically show-offy group exhibition, in which various contemporary and 20th century A-listers face each other down in large galleries police by black-clad security men. A confluence of art celebrity, crammed together: here, a wall full of Richard Prince photos loomed over a Rachel Whiteread bed; there, a Jenny Saville bum rubbed against what looked to be a string shopping bag with a chunk of polystyrene inside (in fact it was a bronze and marble sculpture from Tatiana Trouvé).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living with Buildings - Health &amp; Architecture | Wellcome Collection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/buildings-wellcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/buildings-wellcome/</guid>
      <description>What an interesting series of free exhibitions at this totally unique institution on the Euston Road. This latest one is probably my favourite so far - even beating the show last year about teeth. It’s a rag-bag of architectural plans, paintings, maquettes, pages from books - all organised around the theme of buildings that promote health.
To give a couple of examples that stood out to me: a beautiful 70s plan of Milton Keynes (that was the future, once), a Pissarro landscape of Bedford Park in Chiswick - the first garden suburb of all, where the artist lived for a time - and Andreas Gursky’s Montparnasse tower block photo, that I first encountered at the Hayward last year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
