<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>White Cube on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/white-cube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in White Cube on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/white-cube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harland Miller: Imminent End, Rescheduled Eternally | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/miller-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/miller-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>Harland Miller is a novelist as well as a painter, and his best-known works bring the two media together. I’ve seen (and loved) his large painted versions of imaginary Penguin book covers: the artist faithfully matched the typeface and colours of the classic series in his paintings, but added mordant titles of his own, with his own name always in the author&amp;rsquo;s slot.
He’s now taken over the large, coldly-lit White Cube space in Bermondsey, with 45 paintings and works on paper, all produced this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Wall | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wall-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wall-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Wall’s best known for large, lush, elaborately staged photographs set in light boxes. This absorbing exhibition puts on show several of his unstaged and landscape works - all of which are blown up to a grand scale. The show’s at the large White Cube gallery in Mayfair was eerily deserted when I visited, with most other commercial galleries closed due to the Jubilee weekend.
Quite appropriately, the standout exhibit depicts a party - though not one you’d want to be at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AR Penck: Paintings 1974-1990 | White Cube</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/penck-white-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/penck-white-cube/</guid>
      <description>AR Penck has been on show pretty frequently in London over recent years: I enjoyed an intimate collection of his paintings and sculpture at Michael Werner last November, and now some large canvases are at the large White Cube gallery in Mayfair. His popularity isn’t surprising. Penck, who died in 2017, was a loveable artist, with his large canvases of hieroglyph-like figures and symbols.
The large scale of the White Cube gallery gives his works some room to breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
