<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tate Britain on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/tate-britain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tate Britain on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/tate-britain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Lubaina Himid at Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/himid-tate/</guid>
      <description>“Nobody paints our love stories, our ordinary everyday,” the British artist Lubaina Himid told an interviewer once. “How our ordinary everyday is touched by enormous trauma and tragedy but we as a whole set of women globally and historically have the capacity to keep going.”
Let’s look at Ankledeep, a Himid painting from 1991 that’s part of the Tate collection, and was on show in an artist’s room at Tate Britain right up until the virus hit, and the doors closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve McQueen - Year 3 | Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mcqueen-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mcqueen-tate/</guid>
      <description>Steve McQueen was made a knight in the 2020 honours list, and this is just the kind of public-spirited artwork suitable for such a high national honour. (Though I can’t help thinking LS Lowry’s approach of turning down such Royal-approved baubles, all the way up to refusing the Companion of Honour twice, is a much cooler artistic statement.)
For this exhibition, specially-trained Tate teams have photographed a total of 76,000 of London’s Year 3 schoolchildren and teachers in the traditional class photo format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don McCullin | Tate &amp; Hamiltons</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/mccullin-tate/</guid>
      <description>It’s those little flecks of light, reflected in the shiny metal of minecart tracks, criss-crossing the ground in front of a mine in County Durham, and depicted in sumptuous black and white, that drew me in. Standing astride these tracks is a well-dressed couple, looking back at their photographer with a mixture of wariness and pride.
Their (very famous) photographer, Don McCullin, is best known for his images of war - from Vietnam to Biafra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edward Burne-Jones | Tate Britain</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/burne-jones-tate/</guid>
      <description>I went into this large exhibition ready to write off Edward Burne-Jones as total kitsch. But he resists being dismissed. The show is full of annoying reminders of the artist&amp;rsquo;s great popularity - from the start - and the fact that he was an epic do-gooder. Rising to world fame from humble origins, unlike some of his fellow pre-Raphaelites, Burne-Jones went into business with Socialist paragon of virtue William Morris to produce mass-market wall-hangings, to go along with his paintings for rich patrons and collectors; he saw no distinction between fine and decorative art.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
