<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indrė Šerpytytė on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/indr%C4%97-%C5%A1erpytyt%C4%97/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indrė Šerpytytė on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/indr%C4%97-%C5%A1erpytyt%C4%97/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Martin Aagaard Hansen: Autumn skullcap | Union Pacific</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/aagaard-pacific/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/aagaard-pacific/</guid>
      <description>The weather in London this week has been grey, cold and still. Though the first daffodils are out in the parks, and there’s that extra few minutes of light in the afternoon to let us know that better times are on their way. This wintry feeling meant that Martin Aagaard Hansen’s paintings, scratchy and cold, struck a chord with me this week.
Copenhagen-based Hansen clearly enjoys escaping to the countryside: the paintings on show at Union Pacific are closely thematically linked, all some variation on a forest scene with solitary wanderers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forest | Parafin</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/forest-parafin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/forest-parafin/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always liked a good thematic group show, and this one at Parafin didn’t disappoint. The theme is &amp;rsquo;the forest&amp;rsquo;, which are part of our shared consciousness, even for those of us who live in the middle of large cities. Across different cultures and times, the forest represents a quiet place to retreat to and hide. But it&amp;rsquo;s also a lonely place, where monsters may lurk.
The exhibition begins with an engraving from the mystical French artist Gustave Doré to set the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
