<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PACE on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/pace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PACE on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/pace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Noland: Stripes/Plaids/Shapes | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/noland-pace/</guid>
      <description>Kenneth Noland put himself under a lot of pressure to achieve such chilled-out art. He’s been called a “minimalist” or “colour field” painter, with his large canvases banded with simple patterns - or just stripes. In fact, Stripes/ Plaids/ Shapes, the title of this show, Noland’s first monograph exhibition in the UK for over 20 years, pretty much sums up what’s on display.
So, where’s the pressure from? In the technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Muntean - Just Like Honey | Rosenfeld Porcini</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/muntean-rosenfeld/</guid>
      <description>Austria-born, Berlin-based painter Robert Muntean says he’s inspired by Richard Gerstl, and there’s definitely something of the Secession-era artist’s taste for the obliterative in his new paintings, which often depicts figures only in outline, slashed by colours, large stretches of canvas left raw. They’re on show at Rosenfeld Porcini in Fitzrovia at the moment.
I’m thinking of Gerstl’s portrait of the family of Arnold Schoenberg, painted while having an affair with the mother of the house, just before discovery, and the painter’s descent into madness and suicide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Murdoch - Collecting Colour | Marlborough Fine Arts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/murdoch-marlborough/</guid>
      <description>Nina Murdoch paints with egg tempera on gesso. Her works main show abstracted scenes of buildings and pathways. Some of the paintings in this show, with their endless layerings and scrapings, take years to produce.
To me, they had the irresistably evocative atmosphere of a rainy London evening - evocative maybe because that was exactly the atmosphere outside of the gallery, when I wandered in ten minutes before closing. Path, pictured below, which took three years, drew me in, with its lights banding as if they were seen from a slow-moving car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beth Letain - Signal Hill | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/letain-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/letain-pace/</guid>
      <description>Beth Letain&amp;rsquo;s influences range from Giorgio Morandi to Agnes Martin, though her deliberately ultra-simple forms are more abstract than either, and with a far bolder use of colour. The colours of these big paintings, currently on show at PACE, are deep, bold and matte. Their surfaces, prepared by layers of homemade gesso, have a luxurious sheen.
My favourite was &amp;lsquo;Strong Winds&amp;rsquo;, its bold horizontality and almost hallucinatory depth was the most directly evocative of the exhibition&amp;rsquo;s title: &amp;lsquo;Signal Hill&amp;rsquo; is the hill from which the first morse code was received.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fred Wilson: Afro Kismet | PACE</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/wilson-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/wilson-pace/</guid>
      <description>There is an awful lot to see in the big main gallery at PACE, all of which is work from Wilson&amp;rsquo;s showing at last year&amp;rsquo;s Istanbul Biennial. As the name, &amp;lsquo;Afro Kismet&amp;rsquo;, suggests, the influences come both from the Middle East and Africa.
The wow factor comes from the centre of the room, dominated by two walls clad in Isnik tiles, and two large Murano glass, black chandeliers. Both gaudy and excessive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
