<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Lee on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/simon-lee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simon Lee on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/simon-lee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Howard: You Have a New Memory | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/howard-lee/</guid>
      <description>I first featured the British painter Rachel Howard on this site in 2018, when I saw a stately and sombre show of hers in Damien Hirst’s cavernous Newport Street Gallery. Back then, she showed works based around the stations of the cross. This new exhibition, Howard’s first at Simon Lee, is a more intimate affair, both spatially, in that the Mayfair gallery’s a bit pokier, and in the subject matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elena Tejada-Herrera - Queen Kong, The Girls Learn to Fight | Frieze London</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tejada-frieze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tejada-frieze/</guid>
      <description>I might as well hand in my London art reviewer badge by saying so, but this year was my first Frieze. That giant white tent in Regent’s Park was even more huge and overwhelming than I thought it’d be; I staggered out after just under four hours, feet and shoulders aching, tote overloaded with magazines, press releases and lists of works.
The easiest thing to do in a review with such a variety of potential subjects is to pick out a show that I particularly liked from a non-obvious source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clare Woods - Doublethink | Simon Lee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoner-modern/</guid>
      <description>This artist’s practice has similar roots to other artists I’ve featured on this site before. Like Robert Muntean, Clare Woods takes found images from newspapers and magazines and makes something new with them.
Like her compatriot Gary Hume, she paints on aluminium, giving the final works an ultra-clean, shiny, textured look. Like Rachel Howard , she paints from above, letting the drips fall down the edges of the works.
But Woods’ overall effects are unique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Masters  | Hamilton&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/hiro-hamiltons/</guid>
      <description>So often when looking at large-scale work, it&amp;rsquo;s a single detail that catches your eye. With Modern Masters, a group photographic show currently on at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s, it&amp;rsquo;s a young woman commuter in a light raincoat, glaring out from a train. She&amp;rsquo;s the emotional centre of Shinjuku Station, Tokyo, Japan, taken by photographer Hiro in 1962.
Across the breadth of this seven metre wide work, made up of seven gelatin silver prints, faces and hands of Tokyo commuters are pressed against the steamy glass of the subway car&amp;rsquo;s window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michelangelo Pistoletto - Scaffali | Simon Lee Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pistoletto-simon-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pistoletto-simon-lee/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s OK to be a one-trick pony, if the trick&amp;rsquo;s good enough. Michelangelo Pistoletto is associated with the arte povera movement of Italy in the 1960s, and is famous for his &amp;lsquo;mirror paintings&amp;rsquo;, large wall-mounted mirrors with painted or printed images on them. The first mirror painting dates from the early 60s. And Pistoletto is still at it, judging by this show, currently at Simon Lee Gallery.
The dimensions of the mirrors haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much over the decades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
