<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pablo Picasso on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/pablo-picasso/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pablo Picasso on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/pablo-picasso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Balthus: Under the Surface | Luxembourg &#43; Co</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/balthus-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The notes for this show, apparently the first Balthus exhibition in the UK since 1968, contain the following Oscar Wilde quote: “All art is at once surface and symbol. Those who go beneath the surface do so at their peril. Those who read the symbol do so at their peril.”
This plea not to look too closely is appropriate for this artist, considering the fact he was a snob, a vile anti-semite despite his Jewish heritage, and is most famous these days for his unabashedly erotic pictures of little girls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohammed Sami | Modern Art</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/sami-modern/</guid>
      <description>The Execution Room, painted by Mohammed Sami, is one of the most impressively ugly artworks I’ve seen in a while. It’s currently on show at Modern Art, along with a collection of other new, thematically-linked work from this Iraq-born, Sweden-based artist.
It shows a dining table and chair set in a style that might kindly be termed “dictator chic”. I suspect, but can’t confirm by googling, that it was a room in Saddam Hussein’s palace, captured by allied forces during the disastrous war of 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francis Bacon: Man and Beast | Royal Academy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bacon-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>I caught COVID a few days ago. Worse than the sharp, uncanny fever has been the confinement - the daily stare at the fading T line on my LFT test, the lack of human contact, exercise… and gallery trips. This means I have nothing new to write about this week.
It’s possible I caught it at the last show I saw, this major Francis Bacon retrospective at the Royal Academy. I breezed around the large exhibition in around half an hour, not paying very close attention but taking in the atmosphere and getting my bearings: it’s on for a few months, so plenty of other chances to go back, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atelier Picasso | Bastian</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/picasso-bastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/picasso-bastian/</guid>
      <description>Pablo Picasso moved to the south of France after the second world war, and pitched up in Cannes in 1955, living in splendour at La Californie, a sumptuous mansion in the hills above town. He remained in the area until his death in 1973. This period is the focus of a new show at Bastian - one of the few open in London at this time of year.
As productive as ever, Picasso painted, sculpted, drew and cast thousands of ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 of 2018</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/top-5-2018/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a pretty big first year of art watching for this little side project.
In all, I saw 256 shows and collections in 2018 - not counting repeated visits to some old favourite permanent collections in London. Over that time, I featured a fifth of that total on the site, posting each week.
While I give my eyes a rest over the festive period, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up post, listing my top five of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picasso 1932 – Love, Fame, Tragedy | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/picasso-tate/</guid>
      <description>Even though I went in a churlish mood, on a relentlessly rainy Saturday, surrounded by wheelie-suitcase wielding crowds, I can&amp;rsquo;t pretend that this show is anything else than a megawatt, full-bore, ocean-going triumph. Picasso in 1932 was 50, world-famous, trapped in a love triangle and, according to the evidence currently on the walls at Tate Modern, at the apex of his inventive powers.
This blitz of beauty and innovation, from one of the 20th century&amp;rsquo;s foundational geniuses, overwhelmed my critical faculties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
