<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathleen Ryan on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/kathleen-ryan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kathleen Ryan on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/kathleen-ryan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Cohen: Two Point Eight Million | FOLD</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cohen-fold/</guid>
      <description>This show is dominated by a mini mountain range of day-glo green “eco chips” - the kind of polystyrene-like packaging that pads out Amazon boxes - in the far corner of the gallery. The artist Benjamin Cohen called it all mouth and no trousers, and studded the green chip mountains with an amp and two transparent speakers emitting droning sounds.
It’s a riff on Félix González-Torres’s Portrait of Ross in LA, which was a pile of sweets stacked up in the corner of the gallery, weighing the same as the artist’s lover - before he was stricken with AIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathleen Ryan: Red Rose | Josh Lilley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/ryan-lilley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/ryan-lilley/</guid>
      <description>I chucked out a rotten half lemon the same morning I saw this show. There was nothing pretty about it, the yellow skin turned wobbly, the innards blue black: fruit spoils so quickly in the summer heat. Kathleen Ryan, on the other hand, sees beauty in this kind of organic ruin; she assembles semi precious gemstones, studded with metal, into sculptures of mouldy fruits, and produces something unique and strange.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
