<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andy Warhol on Artangled</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/andy-warhol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Andy Warhol on Artangled</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/andy-warhol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alice Neel: Hot Off The Griddle | Barbican</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/neel-barbican/</guid>
      <description>Alice Neel blazed her own trail for decades, painting from her home studio in New York City from the 1930s right up to her death in 1984. She lived unfashionably far uptown, ignoring the comings and goings of Precisionism, Abstract Expressionism, Pop and the rest. Even more unfashionably, she dedicated her artistic life to figuration, sticking doggedly to being an “anarchic humanist”, painting people who interested her.
This impressive retrospective, featuring works from every stage of the long career, also proves that Neel’s artistic motifs got locked in early and never varied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mimmo Rotella Beyond Décollage | Cardi Gallery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rotella-cardi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rotella-cardi/</guid>
      <description>While Andy Warhol’s mega-show plays across the river at Tate, a much less-heralded friend from Italy has taken up residence in a quiet street in Mayfair. Just like Warhol, Mimmo Rotella was obsessed by the mechanistic over the manual. But instead of making glitzy silk screen prints of pop icons, Rotella responded to the post-War boom with a grungy alternative: the décollage.
In the 1950s, Rotella launched his artistic career by roaming the streets of Rome and tearing advertising posters from the walls, which he then distressed further at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Warhol | Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/warhol-tate/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been waiting to see this show for ages, given Tate&amp;rsquo;s pandemic-induced shutdown just after its opening. This vast, career-spanning retrospective has been extended now until November. Following all that anticipation, it was a sad experience to visit Tate Modern post-lockdown. I could deal with the need to pre-book, the long queues and the mask wearing - all good by me. But the long queues and implied one-way system made me feel like I needed to keep moving forwards, and not linger on this or that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlude - Gerhard Richter at Kunstmuseum Basel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/richter-kunstmuseum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/richter-kunstmuseum/</guid>
      <description>Gerhard Richter made a series of oil paintings based on photographs in the 1960s. They&amp;rsquo;re among his most famous works, which is quite an achievement, considering his is a career of both extreme achievement and length. One of the finest is Motorboot (Motor Boat), from 1965, in the permanent collection at the Kunstmuseum in Basel.
The artist used source material ranging from popular magazines to his own family photo albums. He painted them at a time of an economic boom, with Germany (the West, at least), aiming to leave behind the dark past and enjoy a brighter life of travel, new leisure pursuits and an ever-increasing range of consumer goods to buy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
